<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-28T21:02:21-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>The official website of the CSArts student newspaper. Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">OCSA Teachers Visit CSArts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/OSCA-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCSA Teachers Visit CSArts" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:30-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:30-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/OSCA-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/OSCA-meeting/"><![CDATA[<p>In February, CSArts welcomed teachers from our sister school, Orange County School of The Arts, in order for both schools to be on the same page with educational philosophies and strategies. The focus of the visit was for OCSA teachers to adopt standards-based mastery grading, a system which CSArts implemented from its start.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>CSArts’ grading scale is out in educational literature and is a common knowledge scale in the realm of progressive grading reform,” said Mrs. Read. A group of teachers, when founding CSArts, collaborated to eventually establish the current scale.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The collaboration between these two bastions of arts education was not a mere administrative formality but a deeply philosophical dialogue on the essence and implementation of standards-based mastery grading. Mrs. Thompson, the 12th grade AP Literature teacher, was one of the staff members who offered insights about the grading system to OCSA teachers. “It was kind of a philosophical meeting on why we grade this way,” Thompson said, underscoring the reflective and forward-thinking nature of the discussion.</p>

<p>One of the core concerns addressed by OCSA teachers was the potential impact of this transition on student engagement, particularly regarding formative assignments. Yet, as CSArts has demonstrated, standards-based mastery grading is not just about assessment; it’s about emphasizing quality education and eliminating the inefficiencies of “busy work.” This approach aligns closely with contemporary educational philosophies prioritizing depth over breadth and learning over grading.</p>

<p>Despite the prevalent trend of online gatherings, the decision to hold this meeting in person was a testament to the importance of human connection in educational collaboration. “They wanted people to talk to,” Thompson explained, highlighting the value of face-to-face interactions in building trust and understanding, especially when contemplating significant pedagogical shifts.</p>

<p>Although OCSA teachers were open to changes, Mrs. Read says that it’s unlikely OCSA would be willing to change its grading scale anytime soon. “With high schools that have been around for 30+ years, it would be difficult to have such a drastic change.” However, OCSA is looking to adopt CSArt’s philosophy of mastery- based learning, and Mrs. Read is optimistic that the meeting opened up discussion that eventually might form change around summative and formative assignments, extra credit, and retakes.</p>

<p>While the faculty at OCSA displayed an eagerness to explore this new philosophy, their journey is fraught with hesitations—a sentiment Mrs. Thompson and other teachers empathize with deeply, given CSArts’ own path to where it is today. The reception of this initiative shows the future of a broader educational landscape, where schools are increasingly considering standards-based mastery grading as a more equitable and accurate reflection of student learning.</p>]]></content><author><name>MJ Cho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In February, CSArts welcomed teachers from our sister school, Orange County School of The Arts, in order for both schools to be on the same page with educational philosophies and strategies. The focus of the visit was for OCSA teachers to adopt standards-based mastery grading, a system which CSArts implemented from its start.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/OSCA-meeting.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/OSCA-meeting.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Curtain of Mean Girls: A “Fetch” Production</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mean-girls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Curtain of Mean Girls: A “Fetch” Production" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:10-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:10-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mean-girls</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mean-girls/"><![CDATA[<p>Popular pupils and sassy songs hit the PAC stage in the IA Conservatory production of Mean Girls. During the February production students’ talent and hard work were on display. As the spotlight illuminated the stage, behind-the-scenes efforts and teamwork brought this musical adaptation to life.</p>

<p>Joey Ancona, Integrated Arts Conservatory director, says a collaborative spirit and robust funding made the show a success.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Producing a musical akin to Mean Girls can demand a budget exceeding $30,000. This includes expenses like securing rights ($7,000), covering production essentials such as lighting rental, scenery supplies, projections design, and costumes ($15,000). Plus, there’s the cost of compensating key personnel like the director, choreographer, and music director ($8,000).”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>CSArts encourages cross conservatory projects, and with Mean Girls, Production and Design Conservatory students lent their skills and talents.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Their practicum students contribute significantly to the show’s design elements, offering a remarkable opportunity for these budding designers to showcase their talent,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Ancona said.</p>

<p>A show of this magnitude cannot hit the stage without  help from student families and the community.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Ticket sales and family involvement are absolutely vital! We rely solely on word of mouth and social media for advertising. Families play a pivotal role in spreading the word within the community, assisting with tech day meals, and generously donating props, costumes, and other necessities.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Whether on stage or behind the scenes, students said their experience was unforgettable.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was such a great experience, super rewarding, and the show is amazing. It’s such a stacked cast; everyone is so amazingly talented and they are all just so fun to hang out with too,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Lauren Zavala, who played “Caddy,” said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My favorite moment of Mean Girls was hyping up my friends during ‘Whose House is This?’. It was only a few of us who were on stage, but in the back, we were hyping up and dancing, it was so much fun,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Samantha Rily, who played “Regina”</p>

<p>The experience of putting a show together this large, not only helps students grow in their respective skill sets, but also in learning how to work together.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think that the show is really good, everything was put together, and it all came together…everyone did their parts accordingly, and it just pulled everything together, and it was just amazing in general,“</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Alina Kaptain, from P&amp;D Conservatory said.</p>

<p>So, what’s next behind the curtain? The CSArtisan tried to get the scoop from Mr. Ancona. His reply? <em>“It’s a Big Secret!”</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Popular pupils and sassy songs hit the PAC stage in the IA Conservatory production of Mean Girls. During the February production students’ talent and hard work were on display. As the spotlight illuminated the stage, behind-the-scenes efforts and teamwork brought this musical adaptation to life.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mean-girls.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mean-girls.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Solution, Not the Pollution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/solution-to-pollution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Solution, Not the Pollution" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:05-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/solution-to-pollution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/solution-to-pollution/"><![CDATA[<p>Have you seen all the packets of carrots and apples all over the ground? On March 14, the lunch and security staff added cardboard boxes near some trash cans. In the cafeteria where most students eat, a cardboard box for recycling has been placed by the door. These receptacles were added by the administration to help with the litter problem of unwanted food from students all over campus.</p>

<p>With the recent rise of the amount of trash around campus, some students have complained about how this is causing more work for the  custodial staff. There have been problems with students leaving their trash out because of the trash cans being full; however, there are always more crash cans if students sought them out. It’s a reminder that littering doesn’t just affect students, it also affects other humans and  animals on campus.</p>

<p>On windy days, trash around campus tends to put animals in danger. The recent add-up of tree branches, trash, and water from the wind, usually ends up in rivers like on the way to CSArts. Some reservoirs around town are filled with leaves and trash, affecting the birds and animals that might be living in those areas. Birds tend to use branches and other materials to make their nests, but sometimes they can harm them.</p>

<p>CSArts’ custodial staff JJ and Alex do more than their fair share of hours, helping out with setting up school-wide events and more!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>One thing we’ve discussed but never tried here on campus that they do at our sister school OCSA did… was a system where the first 10 minutes of Block 3 or 6 classrooms had to do trash duty and it would rotate, so a teacher twice a year would have a class that got trash duty,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Assistant Principal Nicole Read.</p>

<p>With an administrator mentioning this solution, students have a choice: pick up your trash each day, or you may not have a choice but to have you and your class pick up trash like the program at OCSA.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Ares Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you seen all the packets of carrots and apples all over the ground? On March 14, the lunch and security staff added cardboard boxes near some trash cans. In the cafeteria where most students eat, a cardboard box for recycling has been placed by the door. These receptacles were added by the administration to help with the litter problem of unwanted food from students all over campus.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/solution-to-pollution.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/solution-to-pollution.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Review: John Proctor is the Villain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/john-proctor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Review: John Proctor is the Villain" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:03-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:03-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/john-proctor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/john-proctor/"><![CDATA[<p>On March 15th, I watched John Proctor is the Villain, and it’s not an overstatement to say it blew me away. The whole production had a sense of realism unlike any other show I’ve seen this year. It felt less like I was watching the show and more like I was peering through the window of the character’s actual life. Some moments felt so intimate that I shouldn’t have watched them unfold.</p>

<p>The main star of the show for me was the acting. All the people in the play put on a tour-de-force of emotional range. The show itself handles very complex and heavy themes like relationships, sexual assault, and feminism in an impactful way, and the actors played it so naturally that I found myself gripped by the drama happening in front of me.</p>

<p>The set design also played an integral role in grounding the story. The classroom setting was seamless and added to the feeling that this was happening to people I’d known my entire life, so props to P&amp;D.</p>

<p>I think the most impressive part of the whole project was that it was done in the first place. I admire the fact that our school was willing to put on a show that tackled these heavy subject matters and did not shy away from them.</p>

<p>John Proctor is the Villain is one of the best shows I’ve seen this school put on and I’m excited to see what comes next.</p>]]></content><author><name>Braedon Younger</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On March 15th, I watched John Proctor is the Villain, and it’s not an overstatement to say it blew me away. The whole production had a sense of realism unlike any other show I’ve seen this year. It felt less like I was watching the show and more like I was peering through the window of the character’s actual life. Some moments felt so intimate that I shouldn’t have watched them unfold.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/john-proctor.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/john-proctor.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Language Struggles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second-language-struggles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Language Struggles" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:02-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second-language-struggles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second-language-struggles/"><![CDATA[<p><em>I took four years of Mandarin at school, but I can barely speak or understand it.</em></p>

<p>Ironic remarks similar to these are, unfortunately, a common occurrence made by second language learners across learning platforms like <a href="https://www.quora.com/Even-though-I-have-taken-4-years-of-a-language-in-high-school-I-still-dont-consider-myself-fluent-in-the-language-Who-is-at-fault-here-me-or-the-education-system">Quora</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/languagelearning/comments/u3eix6/is_it_normal_to_not_be_fluent_after_learning_a/">Reddit</a>. While we might jump to conclusions that these comments originate from underperforming students who just want to complain or don’t pay attention in class, a surprising statistic comes into play.</p>

<p>According to Nadiia Mykhalevych from <a href="https://preply.com/en/blog/americans-foreign-language-survey/#:~:text=Second%20languages%20aren't%20retained,-The%20lack%20of&amp;text=And%2C%20even%20at%20the%20height,understand%20the%20language%20they%20studied.">Preply</a>, “Less than half (48%) viewed their [language] ability as intermediate. Today, 10% of foreign language learners could no longer understand the language they studied. Nearly 40% couldn’t make it through a day in the country whose language they studied using only that language.”</p>

<p>Learning a second language is important because it broadens communication, enhances cognitive skills like memory and problem-solving, increases job prospects, and  enriches personal experiences.  Being bilingual is becoming an essential skill in today’s interconnected world.</p>

<p>Whether it’s Mandarin, Spanish, or German, there is a need to narrow this divide in order to optimize learning outcomes for students. So, how exactly can this problem be addressed?</p>

<p>In past decades, schools typically followed a traditional approach that focused heavily on grammar rules, vocabulary memorization, and translation exercises. Today, teachers use fluency based instruction, an effective immersion approach to language through contexts of experiences that is similar to how people learn their first language.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am currently doing a unit on how they can introduce themselves and properly interact with other people in social settings, like their friends, peers, or even strangers. Having lessons like this is especially important these days,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>California School of the Arts- SGV Mandarin teacher Nana Yang said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because of the shift from the mere completion of worksheets to real-life application, students have a better grasp of usage, are more confident in their ability, and can effectively cultivate cross-cultural understanding,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yang said.</p>

<p>There still remains a clear gap in second language learners in the United States, as compared to countries that have also embraced these teaching methods.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As you get older, language is harder to absorb and connect with. It’s simply a matter of exposure,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Spanish teacher Anthony Reyes said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Many countries start their students with foreign languages much earlier,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Reyes said. This can make a big difference, especially for those who want to be fluent in a second language.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.24hourtranslation.com/language-learning-gap-us-causes-solutions.html#:~:text=One%20reason%20for%20the%20language,language%20course%20before%203rd%20grade.">24 Hour Translation</a>, European students typically start learning their foreign languages between 6 and 9 years old, but only 20% of American students take a foreign language course before 3rd grade. Language education is compulsory in over 20 European countries, whereas the United States has less than 25% participation.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2015/05/filling-americas-language-education-potholes/392876/">The Atlantic</a>, language enrollments in higher education in the US are at 7%, having declined by more than 111,000 spots between 2009 and 2013.</p>

<p>Language education continues to evolve, and it’s in the best interest of the United States to focus on its students learning a second language. This will ensure that The United States can compete globally, while giving students the resources towards greater success in their academic and professional pursuits.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="essays" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I took four years of Mandarin at school, but I can barely speak or understand it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/second-language-struggles.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/second-language-struggles.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Visiting Exchange Students from Japan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exchange-students/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Visiting Exchange Students from Japan" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:02-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exchange-students</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exchange-students/"><![CDATA[<p>You may have seen some new faces on campus this week! CSArts-SGV has been hosting around two dozen exchange students from Japan. The 8th-12th grade Japanese students have been attending conservatory and academic classes as well as staying with host families during their time in California. The students will also be taking a day trip to Disneyland to conclude their visit.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We did this same program last year, and will probably continue it in the future. It’s a great opportunity for our visiting Japanese students and for our students here.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Says Dr. Cook, the Associate Principal at CSArts-SGV. Japanese students stayed with host families from CSArts. If you’d like to host possible future groups of students keep an eye out for messages on StudentSquare.</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have seen some new faces on campus this week! CSArts-SGV has been hosting around two dozen exchange students from Japan. The 8th-12th grade Japanese students have been attending conservatory and academic classes as well as staying with host families during their time in California. The students will also be taking a day trip to Disneyland to conclude their visit.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Searching for Silence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/searching-for-silence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Searching for Silence" /><published>2024-03-29T05:00:01-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T05:00:01-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/searching-for-silence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/searching-for-silence/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re trying to study over the clamor of conversation, or are looking for some quiet, you might just benefit from a few solitudes on campus, tucked away from the main hangouts.</p>

<p>The first of these places is Northview Field, which is accessible through the 100s breezeway or the gym during lunch. It’s open to the sky and has a nice track for walking or running. It’s also spacious, so sound doesn’t travel like it would elsewhere. If you’re looking for some sunshine in addition to silence, the field is the right place to go.</p>

<p>A few paces past the field is the Wellness Center in Room 111. The Wellness Center has several stations to help students with their mental wellbeing, and is available between classes or during classes with permission from your teacher. Check out our in-depth article about the Wellness Center <a href="https://www.csartisan.org/wellness-center/">here</a>.</p>

<p>The next space, The Creative Writing Library, sits adjacent to the cafeteria (next to the door by the 200s). Although it sounds like it’s only for CW students, it’s actually open to everyone Monday through Wednesday during lunch and office hours. The space offers a cozy atmosphere, faux fireplace, and of course, books. The library is in the process of getting some new decorations, furniture, and even a system for checking out books.</p>

<p>Besides having very little traffic, the studios are another quiet place. Hidden behind the 200s are a handful of quiet corners, several picnic tables, and real grass with good shade.</p>

<p>Last on the list is the alley parallel to “Diagon Alley” in the 400s. It’s attached to the main walkway through a few ramps, and it makes it a good shortcut for getting to classes. It’s mostly unpopulated, and also cleaner than you’d expect.</p>

<p>So, the next time you’re dealing with a headache, sensory overload, frustration, or anything where you would benefit from silence, take some time to look for some solitude. Your mind will thank you.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re trying to study over the clamor of conversation, or are looking for some quiet, you might just benefit from a few solitudes on campus, tucked away from the main hangouts.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/searching-for-silence.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/searching-for-silence.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comic: Water Fountain Pt. 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comic: Water Fountain Pt. 2" /><published>2024-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Read “Spencer’s Show Pt. 2: Water Fountain”</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/comics/comic-water-fountain-2.jpg" alt="Spencer's Show Pt 1: Water Fountain" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Sofia Ruiz</name></author><category term="comics" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read “Spencer’s Show Pt. 2: Water Fountain”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-fountain-2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-fountain-2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Update on the Bathroom Vape Sensors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update on the Bathroom Vape Sensors" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:30-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:30-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors/"><![CDATA[<p>With the recent changes in vape sensors in the bathrooms, the CSArtisan interviewed Mr. Metoyer to clear up rumors circulating around the campus, detecting what’s true and what’s false.</p>

<h3 id="what-factors-led-to-the-decision-to-invest-in-the-detectors">What factors led to the decision to invest in the detectors?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Student, parent, and teacher feedback over the past couple of years. And while we were doing focus groups and research for our most recent WASC accreditation. So this work started before I got here a couple of years ago. And that work led our team to believe one of the best ways to address what I heard was a pervasive amount of smoking.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-process-do-students-go-through-when-these-detectors-are-used-for-investigation">What process do students go through when these detectors are used for investigation?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Our practice and it’s an evolving practice… But our practice right now is: if the vape detectors go off at a certain level, that indicates that there might be some vaping going on. Our staff is immediately informed, and security brings that student to the office for a quick search. We try to do them as quickly as possible. And then students get to go back to class. However, we live in an imperfect world, and I’m an imperfect person who also has scheduled meetings. So if there’s a meeting, if I’m in a meeting, and someone gets brought in, sadly, we will ask that person to wait because it’s not realistic to send that person back if they’re suspected of having done this thing.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="if-a-vape-device-is-found-how-is-the-situation-typically-handled">If a vape device is found, how is the situation typically handled?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>There’s an ED code against students having tobacco products, marijuana products, drug paraphernalia, and those types of things on campus. They’re held accountable, according to the ED Code. Typically, that’s suspension. I can’t think of when it hasn’t been a suspension in my tenure… We believe in restorative practices here. So a student who is suspended does earn demerits, but has an opportunity to make those demerits go away through the use of a Restorative Action Plan, which is 100%, the student’s responsibility to opt in and participate in.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-are-some-examples-of-some-things-that-might-be-in-the-restorative-action-plan">What are some examples of some things that might be in the Restorative Action Plan?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>People have written songs, content therapy, done things around the house for their parents, and volunteered to work extra time at the front desk. One person did beach cleanup. Others have done PowerPoint presentations. One person did an analysis on parking practices. So it would be impactful for them as it relates to why a student received that type of suspension.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-data-has-been-gathered-before-and-after-implementing-the-vape-sensors">What data has been gathered before and after implementing the vape sensors?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Since full implementation in early January, from that week to the next week, the number of detections went down by 50%. By the next week, it went down 50%. And the next week, it probably went down 70%. So either we’ve gotten better at gaming the system, or we’re choosing to make better choices, I’m hoping we’re choosing to make better choices. But I’m realistic, and understand that people have been smoking in bathrooms and high schools since before I was born… It’s my hope that it’s gotten a little better. At the end of the year, I’ll probably do like some many focus groups and try to talk to some students and see what they’ve seen from January to June, and see where we’re at.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-is-the-most-commonly-confiscated-item">What is the most commonly confiscated item?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Lighters and nicotine vapes. A lighter alone is a suspension; it’s one of those things in the ED code listed under like cigarette products.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="how-does-the-vape-system-discern-between-substances">How does the vape system discern between substances?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>We get a report from the base detector system. It has different types of particles where it will say, this might be more likely this. And that differentiates between colognes, Nicotine, and marijuana. But the system is also there to detect noise and keep students safe…So in case there’s a bunch of people screaming, which is typical high school behavior, there’s noise peaks.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="why-have-some-students-have-had-their-phones-taken">Why have some students have had their phones taken?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because it’s an investigation about what happened within the bathroom at that time. We found that sometimes these investigation leads to other people who aren’t in the hallway at that time…When students have their phones, misinformation gets posted on the internet. People get told to go hide your drugs, and it negatively impacts our ability to get some real information. It’s not a confiscation. We hold it. We don’t go into it. We don’t do anything. The minute that we’re done with that investigation, bone comes back.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-are-the-resources-or-support-available-for-students-dealing-with-substance-related-challenges-on-campus">What are the resources or support available for students dealing with substance-related challenges on campus?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>All of our counselors have access to information and direct support for students who are struggling with drug use… there’s also a Wellness Center. We have a thing called Care Solace, which is a free referral service for anyone in our organization, not just students, but teachers and any of our people that need some direct support”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Minji Cho &amp; Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the recent changes in vape sensors in the bathrooms, the CSArtisan interviewed Mr. Metoyer to clear up rumors circulating around the campus, detecting what’s true and what’s false.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bathroom-sensors.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bathroom-sensors.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blame It on the Rain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blame It on the Rain" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:25-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:25-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Picture this:</em> CSArts students in rain jackets crowd the pathways to classes, umbrellas crashing together, it’s rainy season in Southern California. The problem is some parts of Southern California received their annual rainfall in just two days, with parts of the San Gabriel Valley getting 10 inches for the first storm, and another 3 inches last week. Students who love the rain are all happy and delighted, but other students are used to the California sun, and hate the wet weather on our <em>“outdoor campus.”</em></p>

<p>The tarps around campus are meant to provide shade to students and can’t handle rain at this intensity, which leads to students getting splashed and soggy. Throughout the rainy season, the campus has witnessed flooding in many different parts of the school due to the heavier than normal rain. Plus, leaves, wood chips, and other objects clogging up the drains.</p>

<p>One of the major challenges is outdoor nutrition and lunch lines. CSArts administrators have addressed these issues, discussing moving the lines to a covered area. Also, there are shade covers near these lines that are not being used due to the fact that the shade covers cannot handle the amount of rain with these record breaking storms.</p>

<p>The buildings in the 400s have leaks in the roofs. With all the umbrellas, it causes traffic jams in the narrow path when students are heading to classes.</p>

<p>CSArts admin are working on solutions for problems on campus, but the problem extends outside of campus, with Duarte’s infrastructure  being challenged by mudslides from the foothills. With the way the sewage and water works in Duarte, everything comes from the high mountains and hills to the low streets, creating more collection and more standing water. CSArts does their best to address possible problems before it rains.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The leakage in the gym was affected by Duarte Unified putting new air exchangers on the roof and those connections aren’t fully sealed as well as they could be. So there were leaks in the gym,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>assistant principal Mr. Metoyer said. He is also aware of the water puddling up in the 100s, 200s, and the Quad. The problem is that cash, unlike rain, doesn’t fall from the sky.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We have a limited capital budget and that’s the budget that we use every summer to fix things,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It will be hard to spend a decent amount of that budget when it rains, which is only a few days a year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Admin is being focusing on what they can control and fix, with these goals:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Replacing the tarps with one individual durable tarp that slightly bends at both ends so there are no open spaces</li>
  <li>Mats that soak up water efficiently to be put near the front doors of each classroom</li>
  <li>2 buckets for each classroom to put umbrellas</li>
</ul>

<p>You can always reach out to admin with any concerns or ideas on how to better deal with the rainy weather.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Ares Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Picture this: CSArts students in rain jackets crowd the pathways to classes, umbrellas crashing together, it’s rainy season in Southern California. The problem is some parts of Southern California received their annual rainfall in just two days, with parts of the San Gabriel Valley getting 10 inches for the first storm, and another 3 inches last week. Students who love the rain are all happy and delighted, but other students are used to the California sun, and hate the wet weather on our “outdoor campus.”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/blame-it-on-the-rain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/blame-it-on-the-rain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>