<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-25T17:58:14-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">CSArts Expands Phone Restrictions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/csarts-expands-phone-restrictions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts Expands Phone Restrictions" /><published>2025-09-26T05:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T05:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/csarts-expands-phone-restrictions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/csarts-expands-phone-restrictions/"><![CDATA[<p>This school year has brought noticeably stricter policies regarding student use of phones and chromebooks across nearly all classes. Students must now store their phones in designated phone charts, while computer usage has become more restricted. You may know from teachers and conservatory directors that this is based around a new state policy, but what is the bigger picture here?</p>

<p>In 2024, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed the Phone-Free School Act into law, requiring all K-12 schools to restrict phone usage on campus.</p>

<p>“We know that excessive smartphone use increases anxiety, depression, and other mental health issues – but we have the power to intervene. This new law will help students focus on academics, social development, and the world in front of them, not their screens, when they’re in school,” said Governor Gavin Newsom.</p>

<p>The policy, however, left schools to decide how much, and in what ways, it would need to be limited. Students in the Los Angeles Unified School District are facing the extreme, with a complete ban on cellphones and social media throughout the entire school day.</p>

<p>Rather than implementing new restrictions, CSArts decided to strengthen the existing policy. With ninth-grade classes already using similar phone limitations and receiving positive results over the past few years, the practice was expanded campus-wide. CSArts conducted extensive research to ensure that student needs would be met, gathering input from the California Healthy Kids survey, working with students on the Operations Committee, and talking to parents and teachers.</p>

<p>“Teachers have been pretty positive about the changes and saying that they have noticed student conversation picking up,” said academic principal Mrs. Read.</p>

<p>It’s expected that the benefits from these policies will continue, and that the restrictions won’t be going away any time soon.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue &amp; Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This school year has brought noticeably stricter policies regarding student use of phones and chromebooks across nearly all classes. Students must now store their phones in designated phone charts, while computer usage has become more restricted. You may know from teachers and conservatory directors that this is based around a new state policy, but what is the bigger picture here? In 2024, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed the Phone-Free School Act into law, requiring all K-12 schools to restrict phone usage on campus.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/csarts-phone-restrictions.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/csarts-phone-restrictions.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Importance Of AP African American Studies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ap-african-american-studies-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Importance Of AP African American Studies" /><published>2025-09-26T05:29:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T05:29:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ap-african-american-studies-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ap-african-american-studies-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of the school year, class lists were released, marking a fresh start for many students. Yet when it comes time to choose courses, history classes are often the ones students skim past without much thought. One newly created class, African American Studies, is not just a standard history elective, it’s been in development since the 1960s, when universities started advocating for more inclusion in education.</p>

<p>Still in the U.S, only 700 schools in 50 states include AP African American Studies in their curriculum. The first Black studies program was established in San Francisco State University during a major Civil Rights era. The College Board launched the first high school pilot of AP African American Studies in 2022-2023. The formation of African American studies takes a new step of greater recognition for Black history and culture in education.</p>

<p>“It’s needed to expand a student’s knowledge and experience. Keep the study of history alive and engaging. This class especially, because there’s a trend in the historical community that has adopted this social viewpoint of history” AP African American Studies instructor Mr. Turf said.</p>

<p>CSArts is one of the few schools that has African American Studies as an option. As a school with a large racially-diverse population, having African American history available allows kids to see their own identities, cultures and give a fuller exploration of US history, one that constantly erases diverse historical stories.</p>

<p>Colleges also see African American Studies as an impressive course.“The additional narrative of history is impressive to Colleges. It makes you look different because it’s only one of the few classes in America. Ethnic studies is a few years away from being a graduation requirement. They will be behind the future generation who have it,”  Turf said. Students who take this course are seen as people who like to challenge themselves and are held higher than students who just take AP U.S. or AP World History.</p>

<p>African American history shows resilience and focuses on the importance of community and identity, while continuing to fight an ongoing injustice, where people can see their stories reflected in history and contribute to discussions still relevant today.</p>]]></content><author><name>Hannah Anderson</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of the school year, class lists were released, marking a fresh start for many students. Yet when it comes time to choose courses, history classes are often the ones students skim past without much thought. One newly created class, African American Studies, is not just a standard history elective, it’s been in development since the 1960s, when universities started advocating for more inclusion in education.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/ap-african-american-studies-2025.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/ap-african-american-studies-2025.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New Gates for the 400s</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/400s-gates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Gates for the 400s" /><published>2025-09-26T05:28:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T05:28:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/400s-gates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/400s-gates/"><![CDATA[<p>The 400’s alley now has gates bookending it, and security guards keeping vigilance.</p>

<p>CSArts administration recently made the decision with the goal of keeping people from entering or leaving campus through the alley during the school day.</p>

<p>“Our first job here is to keep students safe,” said Assistant Principal of Facilities and Supervision Leon Metoyer. “You can’t do that if people can just walk in and out of the gates whenever they want.” He didn’t respond to a request for comment on if the gates were also meant to secure campus from ICE.</p>

<p>Each of the gates has a keypad that students can open with the last four digits of a student ID. These are available on Aeries and on student IDs, and are different from cafeteria pins.</p>

<p>The gates are much narrower than the chainlink fences from past years, so there are now three bottlenecks between the 200s and 400s. Take a detour by the studios if you’re in a rush!</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="campus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 400’s alley now has gates bookending it, and security guards keeping vigilance.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/400s-gates.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/400s-gates.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Man’s Best Friend: An 80’s Fantasy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mans-best-friend-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Man’s Best Friend: An 80’s Fantasy" /><published>2025-09-26T05:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T05:20:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mans-best-friend-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mans-best-friend-review/"><![CDATA[<p>Shrouded in controversy and criticism before release, Sabrina Carpenter’s new album Man’s Best Friend debuts at No. 1 on the Billboard 200 chart. Man’s Best Friend marks Sabrina Carpenter’s second debut at No. 1, after Short n’ Sweet last year.</p>

<p>Man’s Best Friend takes listeners to an ’80s fantasy world. Carpenter utilized campy horror film visuals, a prominent 80s-inspired synthesizer, and lyrical choices reminiscent of ‘80s pop hits. Over the course of Man’s Best Friend, Sabrina complains on an imaginary phone call, taken over a plastic pastel blue rotary phone, about the various men in her life.</p>

<p>Throughout Man’s Best Friend, Carpenter explores the trials and tribulations of the modern dating scene, focusing on how unreliable the men she dates are. Carpenter’s flirty and casual tone, prevalent throughout her song lyrics is more of a casual conversation between two friends, rather than a deep lyrical tale meant to criticize men, like fans had originally expected when the album cover was revealed.</p>

<p>The album cover, which has become a polarizing point of recent conversation both about Sabrina Carpenter and about feminism, depicts Sabrina’s hair being aggressively pulled by what appears to be a man whilst she kneels in front of him. Critics worried that the sexual nature of the cover romanticized domestic abuse and would continue into the lyrical themes of the album. Critics also feared what the album cover suggested about Carpenter’s politics and her stance on feminism. “She’s an adult woman that’s expressing herself in the lens of the album,” Siena Fantini, a CSARTS-SGV junior and Sabrina Carpenter fan, argued. “I really hated that people were making these blanket statements about feminism before even hearing the album for more context”.</p>

<p>In a recent interview with Interview Magazine, Sabrina responded to the discourse, “If I’m being completely transparent, I don’t do anything anticipating what the reaction will be. I only do things that speak to me, that feel right, and make sense when you hear the music. When I came up with the imaging for it, it was so clear to me what it meant. So the reaction is fascinating to me. You just watch it unravel and go, ‘Wow.’”</p>

<p>Now that the album has been released, many fans have found that Man’s Best Friend’s lyrical content was not what was expected. The storyline does not revolve around a tumultuous relationship or Sabrina Carpenter being taken advantage of. Instead, it tells the story of Carpenter’s struggle to find a relationship with a man she finds compatible. The lead single of Man’s Best Friend, “Manchild,” depicts this issue in detail.</p>

<p>Sabrina Carpenter’s lyrics do not tell the expected story, but they do further transport the listener into the fantasy of an 80’s world. Carpenter’s lyrics, full of cliches, innuendos, and puns, reflect popular hits that define the era, such as Madonna’s 1989 classic,” Like a Prayer.”</p>

<p>Despite an album release shrouded in controversy and contemplation, Sabria Carpenter’s recent album Man’s Best Friend has risen to success. The album currently holds the No. 1 spot on the Billboard 200. It also marks Carpenter’s biggest streaming week of 2025, as well as 2025’s biggest streaming debut for an album by a woman.</p>]]></content><author><name>Natalie Lanza</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shrouded in controversy and criticism before release, Sabrina Carpenter’s new album Man’s Best Friend debuts at No. 1 on the Billboard 200 chart. Man’s Best Friend marks Sabrina Carpenter’s second debut at No. 1, after Short n’ Sweet last year.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mans-best-friend-review.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mans-best-friend-review.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hidden in Plain View</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/northview-field/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hidden in Plain View" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/northview-field</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/northview-field/"><![CDATA[<p>The largest part of the CSArts campus is a secret hidden in plain view. The Northview Field is a large part of our campus, mostly used for certain PE classes such as Taekwondo. There is significant confusion among the students that has led to many people believing that the CSArts field is closed off to all students during all three breaks. But, this is simply not true. The Northview Field is open to students as long as you aren’t in class. In fact there were students on September 3rd who were lounging in the shade by the building.</p>

<p>“We’ve been open with only a few exceptions. If we’re using the field for a parking lot, obviously not those days. And if there is extreme weather we’re not doing it on those days,” said Assistant Principal of Facilities &amp; Supervision Mr. Metoyer.</p>

<p>Metoyer also mentioned one more rule: students need to be supervised by a staff member present on the field at all times. He spoke about a struggle with finding available staff for this task, which is likely a reason for the confusion among the students.</p>

<p>So then CSArts students, as long as you follow the rules, the field is your domain for all field-related activities.</p>]]></content><author><name>Leia VanAckeren</name></author><category term="campus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The largest part of the CSArts campus is a secret hidden in plain view. The Northview Field is a large part of our campus, mostly used for certain PE classes such as Taekwondo. There is significant confusion among the students that has led to many people believing that the CSArts field is closed off to all students during all three breaks. But, this is simply not true. The Northview Field is open to students as long as you aren’t in class. In fact there were students on September 3rd who were lounging in the shade by the building.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/northview-field.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/northview-field.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of Mexican American Music - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of Mexican American Music - Part 1" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-1/"><![CDATA[<p>The Mexican American influence on music today is undoubtedly impressive, as seen in Mexican American artists playing pop or rock that tops charts, or even Spanish language or Latino music styles that have made it into the listening habits of Americans.</p>

<p>Of course, being a Mexican American musician can be very difficult. These musicians faced conflicting ideas around identity, racism, and a host of other challenges. Despite the challenges of their environment, Chicano musicians have historically been pillars and representatives of Mexicans in the U.S.</p>

<p>In this four-part article series, I will discuss four different eras of Mexican American music and the musicians that defined them.</p>

<p>The first Mexican American musicians to really gain popularity started in the late 1920s. During this time of Mexican immigration and significant changes in the United States, artists like Lalo Guerro and Lydian Mendeza were some of the first popular artists of their time. Lalo Guerro was renowned for his comedic Chicano music, which resonated deeply with many Mexican Americans. His lyrics were funny and catchy, and reflected his own experiences growing up. Lalo sang in Spanish or in the Pachuco dialect. His music became iconic to Chicano culture. Luis Valdez famously wove Lalo’s music into his historic play, Zoot Suit, as it set the tone of the era.</p>

<p>Lydian Mendoza is another Mexican American musician who started creating her music around the 1930s. Mendoza was born in Houston, Texas in 1916, during the wave of Mexicans fleeing the revolution back home. Mendoza played primarily Tejano music, a music genre that blends Mexican folk music with American styles of rock and blues. Her music told stories of the Mexican working class of Texas and resonated with many people of Mexican identity. Along with her popularity in the U.S., her music got attention across the border as well. One of her first hit songs, Mal Hombre, was very popular and earned her a record contract with RCA. She had a long career and performed regularly into the 1980s. Mendoza was invited to sing at President Jimmy Carter’s inauguration in 1977, and in 1999, she was awarded the National Medal of Arts. Her style was truly representative of the blend of cultures above and below the border.</p>

<p>Another influential artist who came to the scene later in the late 1950s is Ritchie Valens (Valenzuela). With a vastly more American style, Riche Vallens mainly played rock music despite his Mexican heritage. Born in the San Fernando Valley to two Mexican Parents, Riche Vallens was very much Mexican American, but at the height of his fame, managers and others in the music industry tried to hide that fact. They changed his name from Valenzuela to Vallens to Anglosize his identity. There was no mention of his Mexican American background. The one major exception to that fact was La Bamba. One of Richie’s biggest hits, La Bamba, was sung entirely in Spanish and was a way for Richie to celebrate his heritage. Although Valenz did know how to speak Spanish, he insisted on learning to sing the song as an homage to his identity and his family. On this list, Riche Vallens was the most popular in the U.S. Although he downplayed his Mexican American heritage, he was critical of the representation of Mexicans in mainstream American Media. Sadly, Valen’s short career ended in a famous plane crash along with Buddy Holly and J. P. Richardson.</p>

<p>The artists discussed in this article are just some of the people who laid the groundwork for Mexican American musicians. If you’re curious about how Mexican Americans continued to grow from this point, stay tuned for the following articles in this series. Hopefully, by the end of this series, you will have a better understanding of Mexican American music as a whole and will have some good new artists to put in their playlists.</p>]]></content><author><name>Henry Soderlind</name></author><category term="history" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mexican American influence on music today is undoubtedly impressive, as seen in Mexican American artists playing pop or rock that tops charts, or even Spanish language or Latino music styles that have made it into the listening habits of Americans.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mexican-american-music-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mexican-american-music-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Traffic Jams on The Freeways &amp;amp; The Parking Lot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/traffic-jams-in-parking-lot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traffic Jams on The Freeways &amp;amp; The Parking Lot" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/traffic-jams-in-parking-lot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/traffic-jams-in-parking-lot/"><![CDATA[<p>Following the new school year, the amount of traffic and congestion has increased along with the many new members of CSArts. Following the rise of students joining CSArts, traffic has increased along with it. With many families traveling from many different locations, and commonly between 8:20 and 8:30 a.m.</p>

<p>There are many reasons for the traffic congestion. First, some students take the freeway. Many accidents occur on the freeway, which slows down traffic. Another reason that there could be so much congestion in the parking lot is, “500 families arriving between 8:20 and 8:30,” said Assistant Principal Leon Metoyer.</p>

<p>Some precautions and actions can be taken by parents, guardians, and students. CSArts sophomore, Joanna McGee says, “I get dropped off at the front office, and there isn’t any traffic.” McGee is usually dropped off before or at 8 a.m. and has been to class on time. The entrance to the office is located next to DHS and the Northview field.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kazuri “Kat” Bartholomaus, a junior says she is late frequently and that the front office is always the quicker route. “We usually get here at 8 or 8:20. When we get here on time or as planned, traffic is really bad…we would have to wait 15 minutes and be late.”</p>

<p>If you or anyone you know who struggles with this traffic wants to help, there are many things that you can do to ease the congestion. First, get to school before 8:20. Traffic usually starts at that time, so if you want to beat it, come before then. Next, when being dropped off, be ready to hop out of your car. Have your backpack on already, lunchbox in hand, and everything else safely held by you so that when your parent or guardian drops you off, you immediately open the door and get out. This will ease congestion because if all students get out of the vehicle at the same time, then the lines will be moving faster. Drivers should pull forward as much as they can to make room for other drivers to enter the parking lot. This is a team effort to defeat tardies and traffic, and now, we know what to do to be part of the change.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mariam Ghazaryan</name></author><category term="student-life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the new school year, the amount of traffic and congestion has increased along with the many new members of CSArts. Following the rise of students joining CSArts, traffic has increased along with it. With many families traveling from many different locations, and commonly between 8:20 and 8:30 a.m.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/traffic-jams-in-parking-lot.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/traffic-jams-in-parking-lot.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts Fashionistas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/csarts-fashionistas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts Fashionistas" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/csarts-fashionistas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/csarts-fashionistas/"><![CDATA[<p>Many students at CSArts use their artistic skills every morning when deciding their outfit of the day. Ranging from baggy pants to rainbow jewelry, fashion is used as a creative outlet. As the years go by, different style crazes pass, and students experiment with new clothing and accessories. But how do they keep true to their personal taste while exploring trends? Representing your voice through your physical appearance is a journey that can take a while and looks different for everyone.</p>

<p>Fashion within students at CSArts is very diverse, with some taking inspiration from different decades, different cultures, and even from TV shows. Winston Rabon, a CSArts senior, claims to get inspiration from the 70s and 90s, “I kind of mix it sometimes; some days I wear flared jeans and some days I wear baggy.” Winston agrees that his style resonates with how he perceives himself. Some of his favorite articles include boots, flared jeans, and tank tops. With the significance of music during the 70s and 90s, it is no surprise that this popular music student finds himself taking after them in his daily outfits.</p>

<p>A very colorful japanese style called Decora is “ inspired by childhood, bright colors, children’s shows, and toys,” said Temple Stewart, a junior at CSArts who says she gets her outfit inspirations from the Decora style .  She wears lots of colorful beaded jewelry with toys and rainbow leg warmers among many other unique and vibrant accessories. Temple describes her style as “colorful, fun, and joyous,” expressing positivity with only her clothing.</p>

<p>Besides international and historical influences, some students compare their style to TV show characters. 2000’s media seem to hold inspiration for many students, with Y2K making a comeback in the fashion space. “I feel like I dress like Lorelai Gilmore,” said Lucy Hunt, a senior, in reference to the TV Drama from the 2000s, Gilmore Girls. Lucy says that she likes to spice up her outfits with jewelry, scarves, and even just with her hair!</p>

<p>Overall, fashion ranges from person to person, oftentimes reflecting their personalities. CSArts is a school where students with different styles can thrive in the diverse fashion culture.. When it comes to school attire, there is no such thing as over or underdressed, and creativity is always encouraged!</p>]]></content><author><name>Miranda Cervantes</name></author><category term="student-life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many students at CSArts use their artistic skills every morning when deciding their outfit of the day. Ranging from baggy pants to rainbow jewelry, fashion is used as a creative outlet. As the years go by, different style crazes pass, and students experiment with new clothing and accessories. But how do they keep true to their personal taste while exploring trends? Representing your voice through your physical appearance is a journey that can take a while and looks different for everyone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/csarts-fashionistas.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/csarts-fashionistas.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">California Responds to Texas in Special Election</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/california-redistricting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California Responds to Texas in Special Election" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/california-redistricting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/california-redistricting/"><![CDATA[<p>The possibility of redistricting is coming closer to reality in California with an upcoming special election. This election is set to decide whether or not the state will adopt a map of new Congressional districts. But why is this happening in the first place, and what even is redistricting?</p>

<p>Each state has one or more Congressional districts, and voters can elect one Representative to serve in the US House of Representatives in Washington, DC. The political party with the majority of Representatives controls the House. Districts can be intentionally drawn to favor one party over the other, so that one party ends up with significantly more Representatives. This is called gerrymandering.</p>

<p>States redraw their districts every decade after getting an estimate of the US population from the national census, which recently happened in 2020. So why is California redistricting mid-decade? This is because Texas is redrawing the districts, turning as many as five currently Democratic House seats Republican. The change is bringing in many accusations of gerrymandering. In response, the California Legislature approved a special election for 2025 that would allow voters to put a new map in place, taking back the Democratic seats in the House lost.</p>

<p>Students at CSArts weighed in with their opinions.</p>

<p>“If [California wasn’t redistricting] it would be like bringing a knife to a gunfight. […] We have to fight back before we can fix the problem,” freshman Ripley Ryan said.</p>

<p>“Especially at a time of controversy like this, […] redistricting is absolutely necessary considering the current state of politics going on in Texas,” sophomore Adele Nelson Dahl said.</p>

<p>On November 24th, 2025, the special election will determine whether California will get a new map of redrawn districts. Based on these maps, voters will decide the results of the midterm elections in 2026.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ariella Dawson</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The possibility of redistricting is coming closer to reality in California with an upcoming special election. This election is set to decide whether or not the state will adopt a map of new Congressional districts. But why is this happening in the first place, and what even is redistricting?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/california-redistricting.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/california-redistricting.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AP vs Dual Enrollment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ap-vs-dual-enrollment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AP vs Dual Enrollment" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ap-vs-dual-enrollment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ap-vs-dual-enrollment/"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of each school year, students must ask themselves one question, “Are the classes I’m taking worth it?” The question isn’t a simple one to answer. Mental strain, time spent and money are all a part of the equation.</p>

<p>It is never recommended to overload yourself with rigorous courses. The challenge for students is getting the right balance between building an impressive transcript and maintaining strong grades. For some, this means taking multiple AP classes at once. For many students looking to bulk up their transcript, AP classes are an appealing option. They demonstrate academic rigor and prepare students for college-level work, but it may also come at the cost of late nights, stress, and burnout. And while passing the course itself is an achievement, students must also score well on the AP exam which costs nearly $100 per test in order to earn college credit. “AP is more of a gamble and it’s not always worth it. With CCC classes I know I am going to get a pay off for the work I’ve done,” said Creative Writing senior Natalie Lanza.</p>

<p>Dual Enrollment has become an increasingly popular alternative to AP. These courses allow students to take college-level classes, often for free, and earn credit simply by passing the class. Without the added pressure of a test at the end of the course, dual enrollment can feel more accessible. Still, these courses are not without their challenges. They demand responsibility, maturity, and the ability to adapt to a college classroom environment while still in high school.</p>

<p>Both AP and dual enrollment offer clear advantages, but they also come with challenges. Neither option is universally better. The right choice depends on the student’s goals, learning style, and ability to balance workload with other responsibilities. In the end, the most important consideration is not just how impressive a transcript looks, but whether the courses chosen support both academic success and personal well being.</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of each school year, students must ask themselves one question, “Are the classes I’m taking worth it?” The question isn’t a simple one to answer. Mental strain, time spent and money are all a part of the equation.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>