<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-12T19:40:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>The official website of the CSArts student newspaper. Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Be Prepared!: The Latest Report on Safety</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/be-prepared/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Prepared!: The Latest Report on Safety" /><published>2024-09-13T05:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T05:01:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/be-prepared</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/be-prepared/"><![CDATA[<p>Students’s safety when they are at school is more important than ever. Whether that means understanding our school’s emergency procedures, participating in drills, or knowing about recent legislation that affects student safety, students should be informed and prepared.</p>

<p>As you may know and have heard, a PA system broadcasts important announcements everywhere on CSArt’s campus.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Before we opened CSArts, this used to be a middle school in Duarte unified. Duarte unified had a hardwired system that went everywhere except for the 400s, and we used that for a number of years, but now we’ve been transitioning to a wireless system, so the 400s can be included. So the fire drill last week was our first real good test of the wireless system, because it was installed over the summer,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said assistant principal, Leon Metoyer.</p>

<p>Due to the novelty of this wireless system, however, they are still ironing out some of the system’s issues.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Obviously there are lots of hiccups and concerns, because people heard it outside in the 400s, but didn’t hear it in the classrooms… that’s a concern for all of us. What if there’s a shooter on campus? What if, you know, what if during duck and cover, if there’s an earthquake, we need to be able to communicate inside the classrooms…I’m also fully aware that I sounded like Charlie Brown’s teacher underwater when I was talking,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<p>To fix these issues, Mr. Metoyer, Ms. Read, along with  the facilities team are meeting weekly to ensure that issues concerning student safety are adequately addressed.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’m working with our facilities team as far as like the physical wiring of that, because there’s still like wiring for the internet that needs to happen. And I’m working with our IT team, along with Mrs. Reed, to kind of go through that whole thing, and we’re probably gonna have to go do like a room for room check and go through everything and make sure it works…I also want to thank everybody for their patience, and please let them know that we’re working hard to fix it,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<p>On the rare occasion that an intruder lockdown occurs, Mr. Metoyer said every classroom is equipped with yellow emergency buckets.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What’s typically in there is some food, some water, some shock blankets, you know, like the ones you see after somebody runs a marathon… Reflective kind of stuff, and then just some stuff, basically to keep you alive over a long period of time.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>These yellow kits also include medical supplies such as bandages and blood clotting kits. Metoyer wants to assure students that, “…in the event that something like a shooting does happen our teachers have received blood pathogen training” as well as in person training on how to use Narcan nasal spray in the severe case of a fentanyl overdose.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the future, are we planning to do in person Narcan training for students? Yeah, we’re just trying to figure out the logistics of how to make that happen.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is especially relevant now, as there have already been 45 school shootings this year at time of publication, as recorded by the school shootings database. In response, the Biden administration has recently announced new gun control laws and plans on, “…reducing the number of firearms sold without background checks,” according to whitehouse.gov. Biden has also taken initiative on promoting safe storage of firearms, especially in homes. In most school shootings, young adults take guns from their homes because of poor storage techniques. This bill has the goal to pass stricter laws and stronger penalties.</p>

<p>If you have ideas or feedback on how to make our campus safer, Mr. Metoyer specifically wants students to remember that they can stop by his office with safety concerns or suggestions, “I’m always happy for feedback!”</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon &amp; Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students’s safety when they are at school is more important than ever. Whether that means understanding our school’s emergency procedures, participating in drills, or knowing about recent legislation that affects student safety, students should be informed and prepared.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/be-prepared.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/be-prepared.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Signing up for Free &amp;amp; Reduced Lunch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/frlp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signing up for Free &amp;amp; Reduced Lunch" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/frlp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/frlp/"><![CDATA[<p>The Free and Reduced Lunch Program, or the FRLP for short, is an enrollment that makes certain students eligible for one free lunch and one breakfast meal daily. Among free meals you can also benefit from:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Free lockers</li>
  <li>Free parking permits</li>
  <li>Free student planners</li>
  <li>Reduced price for yearbooks, field trips, and tickets to student dances.</li>
</ul>

<p>Are you eligible for the Free and Reduced Lunch Program?
You can check using these steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Visit the <a href="https://sgv.csarts.net">CSArts website</a>.</li>
  <li>On the sidebar, you will see a link titled “student services.” Clicking it will open up a list of options to select.</li>
  <li>Scroll down and select “Free and Reduced Lunch Program.”</li>
  <li>From there you will see a link to the SchoolCafe website. Once you click on the link please create an account if you don’t already have an existing one.</li>
  <li>Finally, there will be a quick survey for parents/guardians to fill out for Duarte Unified to verify if your family qualifies for a FRLP status. Your family must submit a CSArts-SGV FRLP annually in order to still qualify.</li>
</ol>

<p>If you have any questions, see your counselor for more details.</p>]]></content><author><name>Katie Chiang &amp; Chloe Lee </name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Free and Reduced Lunch Program, or the FRLP for short, is an enrollment that makes certain students eligible for one free lunch and one breakfast meal daily. Among free meals you can also benefit from:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/frlp.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/frlp.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Headwaves &amp;amp; You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/heatwaves/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Headwaves &amp;amp; You" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/heatwaves</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/heatwaves/"><![CDATA[<p>Those first days of school can be the hardest, but then Mother Nature throws a curveball: a heatwave. August is the hottest month of the year, so maybe September will be better? While juggling school and extracurricular activities, it isn’t just our brains that are overheating, which can cause major problems. Don’t worry! There are a few easy steps you can take to start beating the heat!</p>

<h3 id="stay-inside">Stay inside</h3>
<p>CSArts Administrators have added new furniture and tables in our indoor cafeteria area! These changes are sure to be welcomed by students whether it’s scorching hot or pouring rain! Certain teachers also open their classrooms during extreme heat, so make sure to ask your favorite teacher about their lunch policy!</p>

<h3 id="keep-antiperspirant-on-you">Keep Antiperspirant On You</h3>
<p>Not all deodorants contain antiperspirants, and they are a must in this heat. According to Mayo Clinic, the main cause of dehydration in heatwaves is due to the amount of water you’re losing due to sweating! Deodorants with antiperspirants can actually prevent you from losing any sweat! Reapplying every once in a while will help cut down the sweating so you’ll lose less water… and yes, it helps with odor too!</p>

<h3 id="drink-lots-of-wateravoid-caffeine">Drink lots of water/Avoid Caffeine</h3>
<p>Studies show that teenagers need 8-11 cups of water a day, and that number only increases with excessive heat. Doctors say that water can help cool you down from the inside, especially if you use ice. Other studies reveal that caffeine can play a large part in dehydrating your body, so avoiding energy drinks is a must in this weather.</p>]]></content><author><name>Arwen McKay</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those first days of school can be the hardest, but then Mother Nature throws a curveball: a heatwave. August is the hottest month of the year, so maybe September will be better? While juggling school and extracurricular activities, it isn’t just our brains that are overheating, which can cause major problems. Don’t worry! There are a few easy steps you can take to start beating the heat!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/heatwaves.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/heatwaves.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Renovations, Additions, and Reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/renovations-additions-and-reflections/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Renovations, Additions, and Reflections" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/renovations-additions-and-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/renovations-additions-and-reflections/"><![CDATA[<p>CSArts is known for its areas of green grass areas around the campus where people can sit, eat, or take a nap. But with the smoky weather and the heatwave, it’s been difficult for students sitting outside. Now, the campus has new places to hang out indoors! As Assistant Principal Leon Metoyer promised last year, there’s new furniture, ranging from chairs, sofas, and tables indoors! It’s given the campus a new look and more space for students!</p>

<p>Plus, you may have heard about the major technological upgrades in Room 203. “…that included an upgrade to the electrical infrastructure, new gaming computers, monitors, and paint to create an Esports facility on campus. In addition, the gym restrooms have been upgraded and we are also working on an upgrade to internet servers,” said Metoyer.</p>

<p>Along with these upgrades, you can check yourself out in the mirrors near the studio bathrooms. Squeezing behind a bathroom door wasn’t the easiest way to check if your hair was messed up, and CSArts students are grateful that Admin listened to their requests.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As someone who does makeup and wants to look their best, it’s kind of important that we have mirrors.”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>As a guy, I think they’re useful, but not really for me,”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I glance in the mirror sometimes, but otherwise I don’t use them.”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s a little random, it just looks like bathroom mirrors outside,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This year’s changes show that CSArts listens to students, their requests, and concerns. So, if you have ideas to make our campus better, talk to an administrator.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ari Dawson &amp; Aryhanna Pham</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSArts is known for its areas of green grass areas around the campus where people can sit, eat, or take a nap. But with the smoky weather and the heatwave, it’s been difficult for students sitting outside. Now, the campus has new places to hang out indoors! As Assistant Principal Leon Metoyer promised last year, there’s new furniture, ranging from chairs, sofas, and tables indoors! It’s given the campus a new look and more space for students!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/renovations-additions-and-reflections.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/renovations-additions-and-reflections.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Club Rush 2024: Rushing Back</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/club-rush-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Club Rush 2024: Rushing Back" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/club-rush-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/club-rush-2024/"><![CDATA[<p>This year’s club rush was an amazing event and an opportunity to connect with other students. Throughout the later part of the week, clubs were set up in the 100’s, 200’s, and the Quad.</p>

<p>There are over 90 clubs to choose from this semester! Remember, most clubs will let you just try them for 1 or 2 days, so you don’t need to commit to them until you are ready, so there is no problem with just looking.</p>

<p>To those of you who are running your own clubs: remember to be as welcoming as possible to everyone who wants to join and to stay committed to the groups you form. It’s important for you to hold the clubs together because, for a lot of people, the clubs are a huge part of the community.</p>

<p>Each day of club rush had a different theme. Wednesday was “affinity and academics,” Thursday was” community,” and today a large portion of the clubs were centered around being social. If you weren’t able to check out all of the clubs, we’ve put together a list for you!</p>

<ul>
  <li>Animal Crossing</li>
  <li>Art Club</li>
  <li>ASMR Club</li>
  <li>Board Game Club</li>
  <li>Canned Peaches Productions</li>
  <li>Golf Club</li>
  <li>Comic Discussion</li>
  <li>Cookies and Movies</li>
  <li>Crochet Club</li>
  <li>Disney Parks Club</li>
  <li>Don’t Tripp Magazine</li>
  <li>Fashion Club</li>
  <li>Filmmaking Club</li>
  <li>Studio Ghibli Club</li>
  <li>Improv Club</li>
  <li>Just Dance Club</li>
  <li>Karaoke Club</li>
  <li>Kloud Dance Club</li>
  <li>LPS Club</li>
  <li>Photography and Video Club</li>
  <li>Producers Club</li>
  <li>Q Club</li>
  <li>RPG</li>
  <li>Sergeant Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club</li>
  <li>Ski Club</li>
  <li>Soccer Club</li>
  <li>Swiftie Squad</li>
  <li>Tea Party Club</li>
  <li>The Comic Building Club</li>
  <li>The Order of the White Lotus</li>
  <li>The Society for Appreciating Fantastically Convoluted and Intricately Terrible TV Show Dialogue Appreciation Society</li>
  <li>The Sweet Spot</li>
  <li>Video Game Music Club</li>
  <li>Volleyball Club</li>
</ul>

<p>If you missed joining some clubs that you were interested in, you can contact Leadership in Room 200 for more information or contact the clubs you would like to join.</p>]]></content><author><name>Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="events" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s club rush was an amazing event and an opportunity to connect with other students. Throughout the later part of the week, clubs were set up in the 100’s, 200’s, and the Quad.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/club-rush-2024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/club-rush-2024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Conservatory at DHS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/conservatory-at-dhs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conservatory at DHS" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/conservatory-at-dhs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/conservatory-at-dhs/"><![CDATA[<p>This semester, many Acting and Creative Writing students have made the trek from CSArts to our neighboring campus, Duarte High School during conservatory hours. The main reasons why some conservatory classes are being held at Duarte High is because the teacher-to-student ratio for conservatory classes is not as high as academic classes and the fact that there is not enough room on the CSArts campus for every class to have an individual classroom. When asked why the Acting and Creative Writing conservatories were chosen for this change, Dr. Cook, the Principle of Arts, said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The classes for this fall semester for these two conservatories have limited needs in terms of specific types of classrooms, like dance studios or music rehearsal spaces. They also do not need specific types of equipment for their classes, other than computers, like Production &amp; Design.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Cook also said that this will continue for future semesters.</p>]]></content><author><name>Delight Kim &amp; Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This semester, many Acting and Creative Writing students have made the trek from CSArts to our neighboring campus, Duarte High School during conservatory hours. The main reasons why some conservatory classes are being held at Duarte High is because the teacher-to-student ratio for conservatory classes is not as high as academic classes and the fact that there is not enough room on the CSArts campus for every class to have an individual classroom. When asked why the Acting and Creative Writing conservatories were chosen for this change, Dr. Cook, the Principle of Arts, said:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/conservatory-at-dhs.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/conservatory-at-dhs.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Emotional Landscape</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/emotional-landscape/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Emotional Landscape" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/emotional-landscape</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/emotional-landscape/"><![CDATA[<p>Navigating a new school year is an emotional journey. The first week, a full week, plus conservatory meant going from 0-100 after Summer Break! Finding classes, meeting new students, teachers, and staff combine for an adrenaline rush on a Monday only to crash by Friday!</p>

<p>Even though CSArts days are long, students, particularly new students, are happy to be here.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>At my old school, the environment was toxic. I knew some students who transferred due to bullying. At this school, there’s a positive environment and everyone cares about one another. I no longer dread going to school,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said a new freshman.</p>

<p>Even with the praise of our school, students are trying to get used to a new bell schedule. This means shorter nutrition and shorter lunchtime. Plus, conservatory classes now have an earlier end time. Principal of Arts, Dr. Stephen Cook said, “This year we modified our bell schedule to shorten the entire school day by 15 minutes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tara Terzic &amp; Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navigating a new school year is an emotional journey. The first week, a full week, plus conservatory meant going from 0-100 after Summer Break! Finding classes, meeting new students, teachers, and staff combine for an adrenaline rush on a Monday only to crash by Friday!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/emotional-landscape.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/emotional-landscape.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Freshman Survival Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/freshman-survival-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freshman Survival Guide" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/freshman-survival-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/freshman-survival-guide/"><![CDATA[<p>Starting your first year of high school can be nerve-racking, especially with all the media portrayals of students being shoved into lockers and having to eat lunch alone.</p>

<p>“It’s my first time going to an arts high school, so I am definitely nervous.” That’s a sentence heard on campus from many new students! Yes, CSArts is different than other schools, but different is better. Yes, there will be challenges in classes and your social life. We talked to Juniors and Seniors and they are sharing 5 tips to help you adjust and make your experience at CSArts even better!</p>

<h3 id="stay-organized">Stay Organized</h3>
<p>Whether you’re new or not, you are with new teachers and different classes. This comes with more homework, projects, and activities. Also, it takes a month or two to figure out teachers’ expectations and grading policies. It can be easy to lose track of deadlines, so develop a plan to stay organized, whether it means getting a planner or creating a schedule.</p>

<h3 id="join-clubs-explore-your-interests-and-build-community">Join Clubs— Explore Your Interests and Build Community!</h3>
<p>Wanting to gather with other students who share hobbies or advocate for different communities? Clubs are the place for you! Don’t be afraid to get involved. What you put in is what you’ll get in return at CSArts!</p>

<h3 id="speak-to-teachers-and-counselors-for-extra-support">Speak to Teachers and Counselors for Extra Support</h3>
<p>Whenever you’re stuck, whether with tons of work or you’re needing support, don’t be afraid to reach out to teachers or counselors. They are here to help. Write an email or visit their room during office hours for assistance. Also, remember our Wellness Center in Room 111.</p>

<h3 id="keeping-goals--building-healthy-study-habits">Keeping Goals &amp; Building Healthy Study Habits</h3>
<p>Setting yearly or even daily goals can better your overall high school life. Similarly, to have those great goals, you can construct beneficial study plans (instead of pulling all-nighters and guzzling down energy drinks).</p>

<h3 id="stay-true-to-yourself">Stay True to Yourself!</h3>
<p>It can be hard to remember who you are in jumbles of identities and “cliques”, or what’s hot and trendy. So, take a moment to center yourself and remember there is no one else like you! You’re important, so stay true to yourself and celebrate your authenticity!</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue &amp; Natalie Merino</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting your first year of high school can be nerve-racking, especially with all the media portrayals of students being shoved into lockers and having to eat lunch alone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/freshman-survival-guide.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/freshman-survival-guide.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Persistant Pipe Problems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Persistant Pipe Problems" /><published>2024-05-31T05:10:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:10:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems/"><![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday, April 23, pipes burst in the 200s and flooded the area. Students puddle-jumped their way to classes, as CSArts-SGV administrators made the all-too-familiar calls to maintenance to fix an area of pipes that have a history of bursting.</p>

<p>Upper-class students joke that the pipes in the 200s buildings have a calendar to burst every year, creating a mess in the same spot and raising questions about the school’s infrastructure. No students or faculty were hurt, no classes disrupted, and the water was shut off quickly by campus administrators and authorities. Students still had their concerns. “I think that it is important to learn in a clean environment,“ Maiya Bhat, a 9th grader said.</p>

<p>Assistant Principal, Mr. Metoyer says he does not expect any other problems with the main pipe and that during the break, there are multiple projects to strengthen the campus’ infrastructure.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Each Summer CSArts-SGV utilizes a pre-determined budget to maintain the infrastructure, make upgrades, and prepare for the future school year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer is actively planning with the school’s plumbing and facility teams on the areas that require the most focus and funding. One of the areas of focus?  The bathrooms. He says that this summer, money wil go “to enhance the restroom experience for all CSArts-SGV staff and students next year.”</p>

<p>The dry season is the perfect time for work on infrastructure, with students and the rain gone. During the winter, however, due to our school’s location near the foothills, we are at Mother Nature’s mercy, as climate change fuels stronger storms, heavy rainfall, and gusty winds.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park &amp; Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday, April 23, pipes burst in the 200s and flooded the area. Students puddle-jumped their way to classes, as CSArts-SGV administrators made the all-too-familiar calls to maintenance to fix an area of pipes that have a history of bursting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/persistant-pipe-problems.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/persistant-pipe-problems.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing, Testing: How State Tests Impact CSArts and Students</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/testing-testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing, Testing: How State Tests Impact CSArts and Students" /><published>2024-05-31T05:09:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:09:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/testing-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/testing-testing/"><![CDATA[<p>Every Spring, 9-11th grade students endure a week of state testing. The week is long and the rules are strict: no computers, no phones in the classroom, even after students finish the computerized tests. So, what are these tests?  Why are they so important? The CSArtisan has done the research for you!</p>

<p>The focus of state testing is on the Junior Class. 11th graders take the California mandated CAASPP test, which collects important data including academic performance and determines how the school ranks compared to other state schools in California. 9-10th graders take “interim testing” which the California Department of Education defines as a formative assessment. That data can help teachers pinpoint exactly where students need more help.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s a great way for students to practice, but the scores don’t count towards anything.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Says Ms. Read, the Assistant Principal at CSArts.</p>

<p>While the Interim testing can be thought of as formative, the CAASPP test is summative and has real effects on schools and students. The state requires a student participation rate of at least 95% and if that percentage is not met, it puts the school in legal jeopardy and in danger of receiving corrective action from the state.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>One incentive the school uses to keep our participation rate over 95% is valedictorian status.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Ms. Read.</p>

<p>While state and Interim testing can be a bore, it’s important for students to understand the effects that they can have on CSArts and their school experience.</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Spring, 9-11th grade students endure a week of state testing. The week is long and the rules are strict: no computers, no phones in the classroom, even after students finish the computerized tests. So, what are these tests? Why are they so important? The CSArtisan has done the research for you!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/testing-testing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/testing-testing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>