<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-14T23:16:50-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Future of the 400’s</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-of-the-400s/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of the 400’s" /><published>2023-12-15T06:00:20-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T06:00:20-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-of-the-400s</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-of-the-400s/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re a student at CSArt’s, chances are you’ve had a class in Diagon Alley, better known as the 400’s. Rumors of termites, deterioration, and admin losing the 400’s have spread around the school. But what’s true and what’s false?</p>

<p>Dr. Endelman, Principal at CSArts, says he had no knowledge of termites or deterioration in the 400’s when asked about the problems.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There’s certain things that get sent to me, and then there’s a lot that just never get sent to me,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>he said. He said teachers’ complaints sometimes bypass him and are sent to a team responsible for repairs, so not all information goes straight to him.</p>

<p>Regarding the future of the 400s and whether or not we would be losing them to Duarte, Dr. Endelman says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s partially true,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>referring to Duarte wanting the 400s back.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They [the portables] have served as a temporary hub, and that was organized by Duarte. We entered a lease agreement with Duarte but we pay the leasing company, not Duarte.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He was able to give the cost to lease the portables which was over $1 million annually.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That lease is getting ready to expire,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So the big question for all of us is what are we going to do about it?”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After the completion of Duarte’s new sports complex, they are interested in getting the space back for a parking lot. But admin also has big plans for the land that the 400s sit on.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The long term solution is to get rid of the 400s and close off that backside of the school, letting the school end at the studio portables/PAC and let Duarte High have their parking lot back,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Endelman explained.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My dream is to have permanent buildings.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman says the most probable location would be Northview park or replacing some of the portable dance studios with permanent buildings.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We’re already having high-level conversations with the school district and the city about what those plans could look like… It’ll take time and money to get these things accomplished, but I am very excited for the future growth of the school.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman said there currently is no definitive timeline for the plans.</p>]]></content><author><name>Quinn Mc-Nary &amp; Karina Hil</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re a student at CSArt’s, chances are you’ve had a class in Diagon Alley, better known as the 400’s. Rumors of termites, deterioration, and admin losing the 400’s have spread around the school. But what’s true and what’s false?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/future-of-the-400s.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/future-of-the-400s.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Admin Goals 2024</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/admin-goals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Admin Goals 2024" /><published>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/admin-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/admin-goals/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>I am hopeful that we continue to offer our students an amazing educational and arts experience, and that they continue to feel that our school is a place to showcase talent, highlight their creativity and share their gifts with others. Although our current program is outstanding, I want to continue to find other conservatories that might be of interest to potential students and to strengthen and grow our newer programs in Popular Music, Digital Media and Theatre Technology. We have an unbelievable student body, and I couldn’t be more proud to serve as Associate Principal.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>-Dr. Cook, CSArts Associate Principal</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My goals, hopes, and dreams for CSArts  for 2024 would be to continue to embrace our cultural pillars and Shine Brightly mentality. I want students and staff to feel joy for the new year, excitement for pursuing their own goals in the classroom, and community with each other as we all grow into better human beings. I’m also going to embrace a sentiment of “let go, move on ‘’ as a way of setting down heavy emotional luggage and moving forward towards acceptance of self and love for my friends and family. I hope that can be helpful to others as well. Happy New Year!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>-Ms. Read, Assistant Principal</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My wish for all of us, students and staff, is to maximize our full potential and be the best humans and citizens we can possibly be.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>-Mr. Metoyer, Assistant Principal</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am hopeful that we continue to offer our students an amazing educational and arts experience, and that they continue to feel that our school is a place to showcase talent, highlight their creativity and share their gifts with others. Although our current program is outstanding, I want to continue to find other conservatories that might be of interest to potential students and to strengthen and grow our newer programs in Popular Music, Digital Media and Theatre Technology. We have an unbelievable student body, and I couldn’t be more proud to serve as Associate Principal.”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">December Holidays and Beyond</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/holidays-and-beyond/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December Holidays and Beyond" /><published>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/holidays-and-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/holidays-and-beyond/"><![CDATA[<p>Did you know there are 14 religious holidays each December? Christmas, Hanukkah, Kwanzaa, and who could forget the Winter Solstice! At CSArts, students celebrate different holidays from around the world.</p>

<p>At CSArts, we have clubs that celebrate different holidays and cultures. For Hannakuah, a Jewish holiday, Jews Clues embraces the Jewish holidays and shares that with the campus of CSArts. Hannakuah begins on Kislev 25, usually in December, according to the Gregorian calendar, and is celebrated for eight days. The Hanukkiah, or Menorah, has nine candles. It is to celebrate the miracle that one day’s worth of oil lasted for eight days. Another tradition of Hannakuah is the Dreidel. A dreidel is a spinning top with four sides: Nun, Gimel, Hey or Chai, and Shin.</p>

<p>CSArts also supports African American students with Black Student Union (BSU). Kwanzaa is celebrated on December 26 through January 1. Kwanzaa was first created by Dr. Maulana Karenga, a professor of Africana Studies. It was first celebrated in 1966. In Swahili, Kwanzaa means “first fruits,” or “first fruits of the harvest,” inspired by various African harvests or first fruits festivals. The holiday incorporates elements from celebrations across the African continent. Kwanzaa celebrations also incorporate candles in a tradition of lighting what is called a Kinara. Kinara is a Swahili word meaning “candle holder,” for each of the seven days that Kwanzaa is celebrated. One of the seven candles is lit, representing various principles of the holiday.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Samson Khachatryan</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did you know there are 14 religious holidays each December? Christmas, Hanukkah, Kwanzaa, and who could forget the Winter Solstice! At CSArts, students celebrate different holidays from around the world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/holidays-and-beyond.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/holidays-and-beyond.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Neurodivergency During the Holidays</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/neurodivergency-during-the-holidays/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neurodivergency During the Holidays" /><published>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/neurodivergency-during-the-holidays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/neurodivergency-during-the-holidays/"><![CDATA[<p>The holidays can be a stressful time for anyone, but things get more complicated when things like sensory sensitivities and social difficulties are added to the mix. Below is a list of tips to make your holiday go smoother, as well as a sensory-related gift list!</p>

<h3 id="tips-for-neurodivergents-at-holiday-gatherings">Tips for neurodivergents at holiday gatherings</h3>

<p><strong>Prior to the event:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Practice small talk with a friend and rehearse answers to common questions</li>
  <li>Ask for alternative/safe food options</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>At the event/Day of the event:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Eat before the gathering/bring snacks if you aren’t 100% sure that there will be food you can eat there</li>
  <li>Bring or wear headphones or earplugs</li>
  <li>Wear comfortable clothes and bring something familiar/comforting</li>
  <li>Have someone you can trust who you can communicate your needs to if necessary (like a parent or a friend)</li>
  <li>Bring a small fidget toy you can keep in your pocket or in your hand</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="tips-to-accommodate-neurodivergents-at-holiday-gatherings">Tips to accommodate neurodivergents at holiday gatherings:</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Set aside a quiet room for guests who may not be able to handle the crowds for the full time</li>
  <li>Try to keep your volume to a minimum; loud arguments and games of tag can go outside of the main gathering area</li>
  <li>Ask before touching someone—and respect their answer</li>
  <li>Take note of their body language—are their shoulders hunched? Are they looking at the floor or at their phone?</li>
  <li>Don’t push new foods on your guest or fill up their plate for them; let them pick what they want, and if that’s nothing, that’s okay too</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="gift-ideas">Gift Ideas</h3>

<p>Neurodivergent people like all sorts of gifts, just like everyone. However, you may have to be more careful with some gifts- many neurodivergent people have issues with clothing textures, so it may be best to ask ahead of time before buying clothes (and probably go with tagless shirts or sweaters). Here are some sensory-related gift ideas:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Noise-cancelling headphones/Loop earplugs</li>
  <li>Weighted blanket</li>
  <li>Compression clothing</li>
  <li>Sunglasses</li>
  <li>Weighted stuffed animal</li>
  <li>Chewelry (or just food-grade silicone beads to make your own!)</li>
  <li>Kinetic sand</li>
  <li>Pop-Its</li>
  <li>Fidget spinner or spinner ring</li>
  <li>Stress ball</li>
  <li>Gel timer</li>
  <li>Tangle</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Quinn McNary and Ren Carr</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The holidays can be a stressful time for anyone, but things get more complicated when things like sensory sensitivities and social difficulties are added to the mix. Below is a list of tips to make your holiday go smoother, as well as a sensory-related gift list!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/neurodivergency-during-the-holidays.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/neurodivergency-during-the-holidays.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Holiday Gifts Made By CSArts Students</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/holiday-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Holiday Gifts Made By CSArts Students" /><published>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T06:00:15-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/holiday-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/holiday-gifts/"><![CDATA[<p>Don’t have any ideas for what to get your friends and families for the holidays?  Don’t worry, because we have special gifts handmade by our fellow CSArts students! These creative students have fun items that will lift the stress of finding good gifts for your loved ones.</p>

<p>Matilda Currie, a 9th grader in Visual Arts has a business called “Skydesign,” selling keychains, earrings, rings, and necklaces. She says she loves incorporating bright and bold colors, resulting in beautiful colorful accessories, perfect for anyone. You can find her selling these on Instagram [@skydesign__<strong>](https://www.instagram.com/skydesign</strong>__).</p>

<p>Two friends, Juniors, Linhlyl Harwell and Sophia Teyolia, started a crochet business together. They both always enjoyed crocheting, and so they decided to start their own business. Some things they sell are crochet tops, tote bags, keychains, and overall more crochet accessories. Commissions are open during the holiday season, so make sure to visit their Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/doubletreble.co/">@doubletreble.co</a>.</p>

<p>Juliet Martinez in 11th grade has always loved to crochet. She sells crochet earrings, room decor (crochet garlands), and tote bags. She is planning on posting more for her business, especially with the holidays coming up. You can find her business on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/crochet.crafts.by.juliet/">@crochet.crafts.by.juliet</a>.</p>

<p>If you have a student-run business, contact the CSArtisan, so we can pass on the information!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t have any ideas for what to get your friends and families for the holidays? Don’t worry, because we have special gifts handmade by our fellow CSArts students! These creative students have fun items that will lift the stress of finding good gifts for your loved ones.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ballad of Songbirds &amp;amp; Snakes Review</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/songbirds-snakes-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ballad of Songbirds &amp;amp; Snakes Review" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/songbirds-snakes-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/songbirds-snakes-review/"><![CDATA[<p>As someone who went through a Hunger Games phase in middle school and already ran through the Hunger Games movies, when I heard about The Ballad of Songbird and Snakes I was worried because the original movies were perfect. I hoped it held up to that standard and it DEF DID. That movie was so amazing I felt like my soul was ascending, I know middle school me was sobbing. The cinematography was gorgeous and the acting was great; except Lucy Gray’s accent that was a scare each time. It went beyond my expectations. Snow and Lucy Gray’s relationship was beautifully executed and you can see the war going on in Snow’s mind. The only thing that upset me was that they didn’t go more in depth in Tigres’ backstory and what she was up to. She’s such an underrated character and the evolution of her and Snow’s relationship also kind of broke my heart. All in All TEN OUT OF TEN.</p>]]></content><author><name>Anonymous</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone who went through a Hunger Games phase in middle school and already ran through the Hunger Games movies, when I heard about The Ballad of Songbird and Snakes I was worried because the original movies were perfect. I hoped it held up to that standard and it DEF DID. That movie was so amazing I felt like my soul was ascending, I know middle school me was sobbing. The cinematography was gorgeous and the acting was great; except Lucy Gray’s accent that was a scare each time. It went beyond my expectations. Snow and Lucy Gray’s relationship was beautifully executed and you can see the war going on in Snow’s mind. The only thing that upset me was that they didn’t go more in depth in Tigres’ backstory and what she was up to. She’s such an underrated character and the evolution of her and Snow’s relationship also kind of broke my heart. All in All TEN OUT OF TEN.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/songbirds-and-snakes-review.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/songbirds-and-snakes-review.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking the Train After Dark: Metro Safety</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/taking-the-train-after-dark/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking the Train After Dark: Metro Safety" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/taking-the-train-after-dark</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/taking-the-train-after-dark/"><![CDATA[<p>With the end of Daylight Saving Time, nightfall already descends by the end of each school day. Many CSArts students who rely on the Metro system for transportation are left navigating the dark streets and stations. Students have developed growing concerns for safety, fearing the vulnerability that comes with darkness on public transport. With this in mind, Metro has been working hard to help ensure the safety of all students, enhancing their own safety programs and policies among their Los Angeles stations.</p>

<p>In order to stay safe, The CSArtisan spoke with Metro officials and they suggest always traveling in pairs or groups.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There is always safety in numbers,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Jackie Gonzalez from Metro said. It’s recommended that students stick together while walking to and from the Duarte station each day. In addition, Gonzalez urges students to always be aware of their surroundings.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This means remove headphones so you can hear what is going on around you, put your phone away to eliminate distractions, and be observant of emergency intercoms at the station and on the train in case of any issues arising.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Gonzalez said, If you do see any suspicious or concerning activity on the system, don’t be afraid to report it on the LA Metro Transit Watch app, where you can report via text, phone call, or message through the app.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Safety is number 1 to Metro,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>adds Gonzalez. She said it is a team effort to protect students with sheriffs, the LAPD, Metro Security Staff, and Metro Ambassadors.</p>

<p>You can find Metro Ambassadors wearing bright green shirts at stations and on the trains. Gonzalez said the Metro Ambassadors have been effective in cutting incidents on the system as a whole.</p>

<p>We can’t control when the sun sets, but we can make the choice to utilize the safety recommendations given, and be assured that many people from Metro are striving to provide a safe commute for CSArts students.</p>]]></content><author><name>Juliet Martinez &amp; Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the end of Daylight Saving Time, nightfall already descends by the end of each school day. Many CSArts students who rely on the Metro system for transportation are left navigating the dark streets and stations. Students have developed growing concerns for safety, fearing the vulnerability that comes with darkness on public transport. With this in mind, Metro has been working hard to help ensure the safety of all students, enhancing their own safety programs and policies among their Los Angeles stations.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/taking-the-train-after-dark.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/taking-the-train-after-dark.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Would YOU Get Kidnapped by Krampus?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/would-you-get-krampused/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Would YOU Get Kidnapped by Krampus?" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/would-you-get-krampused</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/would-you-get-krampused/"><![CDATA[<p>Who is Krampus you might ask? In some European folklore, Krampus is the opposite of the pure-hearted Santa Claus. With devil horns and goat hooves, Krampus is famous for kidnapping bad children and beating them for being naughty little brats. But what would it take for, I dunno, YOU to be taken by Krampus?</p>

<p>Let’s look at what makes a kid “naughty” in Krampus’s eyes.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Disobedience: The biggest factor for a kidnapping. If you’ve found yourself saying no to your parents when they ask for your help or talking over your teacher in class, you can pretty much tell your life goodbye.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lying: If you’ve stopped telling the truth and started spreading rumors, sorry, but you’re dead. I don’t make the rules.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Stealing: From grand theft auto to picking up a dollar bill that fell out of someone’s pocket, Krampus will know. If you’re caught stealing, then you’re getting stolen.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Bullying: You don’t even have to be bullying something physically! If you tease your friends a little too hard or even send them a mean-spirited TikTok, Krampus will ban you from this plain of existence.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lack of Respect: Krampus has a history of stealing children who are mean to their elders, so be nice to your senior friends this holiday season unless you want a one-way ticket into Krampus’ sack.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>If you hit even one of these criteria, you can expect a certain hoof-having, sack-carrying, horn-on-his-head demon coming down your chimney this Christmas Eve. But its not too late for you. If you behave well for the remainder of Winter, there might be a slim chance you’ll make it to the New Year. But until then, keep one eye open.</p>]]></content><author><name>Braedon Younger</name></author><category term="misc" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who is Krampus you might ask? In some European folklore, Krampus is the opposite of the pure-hearted Santa Claus. With devil horns and goat hooves, Krampus is famous for kidnapping bad children and beating them for being naughty little brats. But what would it take for, I dunno, YOU to be taken by Krampus?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/would-you-get-krampused.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/would-you-get-krampused.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Time to Rewind: A Recap of the 2023 Year</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/time-to-rewind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time to Rewind: A Recap of the 2023 Year" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/time-to-rewind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/time-to-rewind/"><![CDATA[<p>As the first semester of the 2023-2024 school year is coming to an end, let’s take a little time to look at some of the highlights of these past months.</p>

<p>From the first days on-campus after Summer break to these recent winter weeks of the finals-flood, The CSArtisan has brought you the latest on some of the biggest events of the school year. This included the school-wide Club Rush, activities surrounding several cultural heritage months and school Halloween festivities. Other major events included the many concerts, performances and showcases put on by different conservatories like the Musical Theater Conservatory’s Ride the Cyclone, the cross-conservatory productions like A Midsummer Night’s Dream or Enchanted: Forest of Light at Descanso Gardens, and many more.</p>

<p>The CSArtisan also talked with admin to give you the latest info on the school’s new security measures. Under the guidance of Mr. Metoyer, safety measures such as live-streaming security cameras, bathroom sensors, digital hall passes, and emergency Narcan stations were implemented.</p>

<p>Those weren’t the only changes our school went through this year, though. CSArts welcomed a handful of new members of the school staff, including Mr. Leon Metoyer, the new Assistant Principal, and Mr. Timothy Gomez, the new director of the Creative Writing Conservatory. A new conservatory, Popular Music, was also added, along with new course choices in some other conservatories. On top of that, the school-wide bell also got a new tune.</p>

<p>Additionally, the CSArtisan brought you coverage on student life and campus inconveniences (anyone remember the bees?), holiday history, environmental info, polls, reviews, and even short fiction. Our school stories were also given a platform to be heard through different media with the addition of the new CSArtisan website, as well as the newspaper’s new podcast, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0HJcSdDT6CnREdafnh1Ilo?si=216956326c2941d9">CSArtisan Talks</a>.</p>

<p>Reflecting back on this semester, Mr. Blair, head of the CSArtisan, said:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Our student journalists and managing editors have created one of the best high school newspapers in the country. We’ve added a brand new website and weekly games, which are amazing, but what I’m most proud of is our student journalists’ constant search for truth and responsible reporting in order to be a trusted news source for the school.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And the news won’t stop there! Be sure to look out for the newest CSArts scoops in the next coming semester– because no matter what 2024 brings, know that the CSArtisan has got you covered, with stories that will be entertaining, informative… and always the truth.</p>]]></content><author><name>Danica Chen</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the first semester of the 2023-2024 school year is coming to an end, let’s take a little time to look at some of the highlights of these past months.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/time-to-rewind.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/time-to-rewind.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Healthy Holidays: Tips to Avoid Getting Sick this Winter</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/healthy-holidays/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Healthy Holidays: Tips to Avoid Getting Sick this Winter" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/healthy-holidays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/healthy-holidays/"><![CDATA[<p>Getting sick is the worst. Sneezing, coughing, fevers and chills – and on top of everything, the huge amount of missed schoolwork! People are especially prone to sickness during the cold winter. Protect yourself with these healthy habits:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Doctors say to get a full night’s rest. Teens need around 8-10 hours of sleep per day. A lack of sleep weakens the immune system and leaves you susceptible to sickness. Following a healthy sleep schedule also improves your mood and lowers the risk for serious health problems (like heart disease).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Nutritionists say to eat healthy. Consistently eat fruits, vegetables, whole grains, dairy, and protein in a balanced and colorful diet. “For those having long days for rehearsals and conservatory classes, please carry extra healthy snacks to keep your bodies and brains fueled throughout the day,” advises Susan Macknin, registered nurse for the school. Vitamins C and D boost your immune system and help fight colds.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Stay hydrated. Be sure to drink plenty of water every day! “Remember to bring your water bottle and refill it during the day on campus,” says the school nurse.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Clean your hands. Sometimes the simplest tips are the most effective – wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds to remove germs. Also, avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth with unwashed hands.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exercise regularly. High schoolers should get at least one hour of moderate exercise each day. This includes walking, running, participating in sports, or even just attending your P.E. class (or conservatory, if you’re a dancer).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Keep warm. The immune system isn’t as effective when cold air enters the nose and upper airways. Though California winters are far from extreme, wear layers during the chilly months.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mental health is vital! According to the National Institutes of Health, too much stress can cause a weakened (or compromised) immune response. Long-term stress can impede physical and mental health and lead to anxiety, depression, and other health issues. “Practice stress-reducing techniques such as slow, deep breathing, meditation, or exercise,” says the school nurse. She advises students to avoid cramming, procrastinating, and overwhelming themselves with work. Visit the Wellness Center in room 111 for support of your mental well-being.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Follow these tips to help protect yourself from colds and common illnesses. And remember: if you do get sick, stay at home!</p>

<p>“If symptoms are lingering, please wear a mask when you return to school,” says Susan Macknin. It’s easy “to get sick from being in close proximity to others spreading germs.” Stay healthy, CSArts!</p>]]></content><author><name>Linnea Venti</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting sick is the worst. Sneezing, coughing, fevers and chills – and on top of everything, the huge amount of missed schoolwork! People are especially prone to sickness during the cold winter. Protect yourself with these healthy habits:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/healthy-holidays.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/healthy-holidays.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>