<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-04-25T20:45:36-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>The official website of the CSArts student newspaper. Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Have a Care for Earth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/care-for-earth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have a Care for Earth" /><published>2024-04-26T05:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T05:01:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/care-for-earth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/care-for-earth/"><![CDATA[<p>Earth Day just passed, but that doesn’t mean we should stop caring. Some environmental issues won’t fix themselves, including micro- and nano plastic pollution, which have recently been raising serious health concerns for life on earth, including threats to fragile ecosystems, and cancer.</p>

<p>To get a perspective on how microplastics affect the environment and how students can help, we talked to Mr. Crumley, who teaches Honors Biology and BCD/CMD.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It [microplastics] could have an effect on you epigenetically, which means it could actually change the genes.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He adds that it could also cause hormone imbalance.</p>

<p>How do we avoid plastics when they are all around us? Mr. Crumley recommends buying boxed water, using reusable water bottles with filters (he recommends the brand Soma), or buying glass or bamboo containers.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Look into what you’re buying… because what you purchase is funding and telling the individual or company that you want this product… they’re gonna make it easier to get that product done and most of the time, it’s through plastic. Consider what products you’re using, what you do with those products after you’re done using them,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mr. Crumley says.</p>

<p>We also talked to Ms. Read, about environmental consciousness at school.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Our cleaning staff regularly swaps out for safer and greener products,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>she says. Admin have installed water bottle refilling stations, and “set certain metrics on the AC units so that they don’t kick on too soon and further stress the grid.”</p>

<p>For students who want to use less plastic, she recommends bringing lunch and water bottles. It’s also helpful to avoid buying synthetic fabrics like polyester, which release microplastics when washed.</p>

<p>We’ve taken so much from the Earth. Isn’t it time to start giving back?</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earth Day just passed, but that doesn’t mean we should stop caring. Some environmental issues won’t fix themselves, including micro- and nano plastic pollution, which have recently been raising serious health concerns for life on earth, including threats to fragile ecosystems, and cancer.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/care-for-earth.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/care-for-earth.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stress is Up as We Countdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/summer-countdown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stress is Up as We Countdown" /><published>2024-04-26T05:00:55-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T05:00:55-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/summer-countdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/summer-countdown/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="anxiety-during-the-countdown-to-summer">Anxiety During the Countdown to Summer</h3>

<p>With only two months left of school in the Spring semester, the heat and stress is on for seniors. We got into college, what happens next? What’s going to happen on our new journey? Have I made the right decisions? And seniors aren’t the only ones with worries as the countdown continues.</p>

<p>Mental Health should be a priority during this stressful time of year. Since summer is coming up, some students are struggling with the challenges of being stuck at home for 3 months.</p>

<h3 id="tough-times-and-test-taking">Tough Times and Test Taking</h3>

<p>This month, CSArts freshmen, sophomores, and juniors took the California Assessment of Student Performance and Progress. If you’re an underclassman, dont worry too much: the State only has access to junior test scores. Students’ scores do not affect their grades in class, but are used as a measurement tool by the State of California. This, however, does not negate the early start and stress of the test taking season.</p>

<p>Sophomore AP students will be taking their first AP test of their career: AP World History. Juniors and Seniors taking AP tests and finishing Citrus College Courses. They are feeling the heat, and we’re not talking about Spring temperatures.</p>

<p>Just a reminder, if you need support, CSArts counselors are available to talk with you when you’re having a tough time. You’re also invited to go to the Wellness Center at Room 111. The Wellness Center has several stations to help with stress, anger, and more! Whether you just need a few minutes to destress, take a breather, or process feelings with supportive people, the Wellness Center is a safe space for you. It’s available from Blocks 1-6. Mr. Austin and Mrs. Miranda is there to create a peaceful environment where students feel safe and secure.</p>

<h1 id="some-important-dates-that-students-should-keep-in-mind-are-the-following-there-will-be-no-school-this-monday-april-29th-ap-testing-begins-on-may-6-and-continues-on-until-may-17-our-last-day-of-conservatory-is-may-9th-seniors-dont-forget-prom-is-on-may-18-graduation-for-seniors-falls-on-may-31-and-the-last-day-of-school-lands-on-june-4th-if-you-are-a-senior-and-feeling-overwhelmed-csarts-has-created-a-senior-to-do-list-you-can-find-it-at-csartsnet">Some important dates that students should keep in mind are the following. There will be no school this Monday, April 29th. AP testing begins on May 6 and continues on until May 17. Our last day of conservatory is May 9th. Seniors, don’t forget, Prom is on May 18! Graduation for seniors falls on May 31 and the last day of school lands on June 4th. If you are a senior and feeling overwhelmed CSArts has created a “Senior To-Do List.” You can find it at <a href="https://csarts.net">csarts.net</a>.</h1>

<p>Remember, don’t let the added stress of these events bring down your overall happiness. Just stay focused and clear your mind. If you ever experience burnout, fatigue, depression or anxiety, take some time to yourself and allow yourself to heal in your own way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anxiety During the Countdown to Summer]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/summer-countdown.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/summer-countdown.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The California Fitness Test: A Mile Run or a Walk in the Park?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fitness-test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The California Fitness Test: A Mile Run or a Walk in the Park?" /><published>2024-04-26T05:00:50-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T05:00:50-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fitness-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fitness-test/"><![CDATA[<p>As the end of the year approaches with state testing in the rearview mirror, one test remains for freshmen that stands out from the others: The California Physical Fitness Test.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-california-physical-fitness-test">What is the California Physical Fitness Test?</h3>

<p>According to the California Department of Education, the Physical Fitness Test (or PFT) all ninth graders are required to take the test which contains five components: Aerobic Capacity, Abdominal Strength, Trunk Extensor Strength, Upper Body Strength, and Flexibility.</p>

<p>Each of these components comes with its own methods for testing. For Aerobic Capacity, there’s either the one-mile run, 20-meter Progressive Aerobic Cardiovascular Endurance Run (also known as the PACER), or the walk test. For Abdominal Strength, students will perform curl-ups, where “students lie on their back with their knees bent at a 140° angle, feet flat on the mat, and their hands at their sides, palms down. Moving slowly, students curl up, sliding their fingers across a measuring strip on the mat, and then curl back down until their head touches the mat.” For Trunk Extensor Strength, students will perform trunk lifts, where “While lying face down on a flat surface, students are asked to slowly lift their upper body off the floor, using the muscles of the back, to a maximum of 12 inches. Students need to hold the position for measurement.” For Upper Body Strength, students will perform push-ups. Then finally, for Flexibility, students will perform Bac-Saver Sit and Reach. “Starting in a sitting position, with the left leg extended (the foot is flat against the front side of the box needed for this test) and the right leg bent, the student reaches forward with both hands along the scale printed on the box. The same procedure is repeated with swapping legs to measure reach distance with the other side of the body.” Just reading this is painful for many.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-you-pass-the-pft">How do you pass the PFT?</h3>

<p>To pass the PFT, the student has to be in the “Healthy Fitness Zone” for each of the exercises. Each of these is calculated through a specific equation and being in the HFZ is also determined by factors like gender, height, and weight, as all of these are measured and kept to different standards.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-students-have-to-take-the-pft">Why do students have to take the PFT?</h3>

<p>The PFT is a resource our school can use to monitor the overall health and fitness of its students and is also helpful in monitoring the effectiveness of our physical education programs.</p>

<h3 id="should-freshmen-be-worried-about-the-pft">Should freshmen be worried about the PFT?</h3>

<p>No. Over the years the test has been changed to accommodate a variety of student needs and doing poorly on the PFT is not reflected in your transcript.</p>]]></content><author><name>Braedon Younger</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the end of the year approaches with state testing in the rearview mirror, one test remains for freshmen that stands out from the others: The California Physical Fitness Test.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/fitness-test.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/fitness-test.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Get Dressed for Less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/get-dressed-for-less/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get Dressed for Less" /><published>2024-04-26T05:00:45-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T05:00:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/get-dressed-for-less</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/get-dressed-for-less/"><![CDATA[<p>The average prom dress and suit costs somewhere in between $250-500, and on top of that, a ticket to even attend costs almost 100 dollars! If the prom expenses seem steep, there are plenty of affordable alternatives to explore, like renting attire or shopping secondhand. Everyone deserves to enjoy the celebration without financial stress. Belo</p>

<p><a href="https://www.friartux.com/rent/suits-and-tuxedos">Friar Tux</a> - Rental options under $100, 20% off code can be found</p>

<p><a href="https://www.promgirl.com/collections/dresses-priced-under-100">Prom Girl</a> - Options under $100</p>

<p>Nordtrom Rack (<a href="https://www.nordstromrack.com/clearance/Men/Clothing?breadcrumb=Home%2FClearance%2FMen%2FClothing">Suits</a> or <a href="https://www.nordstromrack.com/clearance/Women/Clothing/Dresses?breadcrumb=Home%2FClearance%2FWomen%2FClothing%2FDresses&amp;filterByProductType=clothing_dresses">Dresses</a>) - Options average at $100-200</p>

<p><a href="https://www.lulus.com/categories/701_693/prom-dresses.html">Lulu’s</a> - Options under $100</p>

<p>Local rental options! - Check local bridal shops and prom dress shops to see if rentals are available!</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The average prom dress and suit costs somewhere in between $250-500, and on top of that, a ticket to even attend costs almost 100 dollars! If the prom expenses seem steep, there are plenty of affordable alternatives to explore, like renting attire or shopping secondhand. Everyone deserves to enjoy the celebration without financial stress. Belo]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Commuter School Safety</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/commuter-school-sfaety/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Commuter School Safety" /><published>2024-04-26T05:00:40-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T05:00:40-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/commuter-school-sfaety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/commuter-school-sfaety/"><![CDATA[<p>High School safety includes much more than fire drills and practicing for disasters. CSArts is a commuter school, with limited parking spots, and hundreds of student and parent drivers picking up and dropping off every day. CSArts is constantly updating measures to keep streets and parking lots surrounding the school as safe as possible. This includes more security guards and staff in the parking lot before and after school, the presence of crossing guards, clearer signage, and stricter enforcement of parking permits. With all of these measures in place, accidents still happen.</p>

<p>On Thursday, April 11, one of the school’s crossing guards, Mr. Howell was slightly injured by a car at the Highland parking lot entrance according to Principal Dr. Gregory Endelman. Eyewitnesses said a parent was attempting to make a right turn into the lot, but didn’t see Mr. Howell in their blind spot. Paramedics were called, and Howell sustained minor injuries. Thankfully, Mr. Howell is now back at work and continuing to fulfill his vital role in ensuring the well-being of students and staff.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It all happened so quickly. One moment Mr Howell was helping me and my friend cross the street, the next he was falling to the ground. I rushed over right away, and I am so relieved that everything is alright now,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Maiya Bhatt said.</p>

<p>Wanting to express their gratitude for his dedication, students organized a heartfelt gesture by giving him get-well gifts.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I wrote him a card in order to wish him a safe recovery. He spreads a lot of positivity to not just the school, but the world, so I wanted to let him know that we all care a lot about him,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Isla Castellon said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Seeing Mr. Howell in the morning and afternoon is one of the best parts of my day. I am very appreciative of everything he has done, so I made him a basket full of goodies that I hope he enjoys,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>an anonymous student said.</p>

<p>Approximately 25,000 accidents occur in school zones each year, according to the Transportation Research Board. Make sure to be aware of surroundings and stay safe CSArts!</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[High School safety includes much more than fire drills and practicing for disasters. CSArts is a commuter school, with limited parking spots, and hundreds of student and parent drivers picking up and dropping off every day. CSArts is constantly updating measures to keep streets and parking lots surrounding the school as safe as possible. This includes more security guards and staff in the parking lot before and after school, the presence of crossing guards, clearer signage, and stricter enforcement of parking permits. With all of these measures in place, accidents still happen.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/commuter-school-safety.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/commuter-school-safety.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Remembering the Armenian Genocide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/remembering-the-armenian-genocide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remembering the Armenian Genocide" /><published>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/remembering-the-armenian-genocide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/remembering-the-armenian-genocide/"><![CDATA[<p>The Armenian Genocide Memorial Day is on April 24. It marks the day of the Armenian Genocide where 1.5 million lives were lost and is held annually to commemorate the victims. Although the Armenian genocide was in 1915, even today, the Armenian land, Artsakh is still being invaded and taken advantage of by its neighboring country. Due to the blockade by Azerbaijan, a humanitarian crisis, the Republic of Artsakh no longer exists. It is important to educate people about the genocide and these blockades so that history doesn’t repeat itself. Students at CSArts who are interested in helping out, getting informed, and making a difference can go to <a href="https://anca.org/">this link</a> to support. 1915 never again.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Armenian Genocide Memorial Day is on April 24. It marks the day of the Armenian Genocide where 1.5 million lives were lost and is held annually to commemorate the victims. Although the Armenian genocide was in 1915, even today, the Armenian land, Artsakh is still being invaded and taken advantage of by its neighboring country. Due to the blockade by Azerbaijan, a humanitarian crisis, the Republic of Artsakh no longer exists. It is important to educate people about the genocide and these blockades so that history doesn’t repeat itself. Students at CSArts who are interested in helping out, getting informed, and making a difference can go to this link to support. 1915 never again.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Navigating the Digital SAT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/navigating-the-digital-SAT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigating the Digital SAT" /><published>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/navigating-the-digital-SAT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/navigating-the-digital-SAT/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been keeping up with the news, there have been many headlines regarding the reintroduction of mandatory SAT scores in the college admissions process within prestigious private universities like Harvard, MIT, Yale, and Princeton. Although this may be an intimidating list of universities, there are still plenty of amazing schools that will keep the test optional as well as test blind, with the exception of CalTech, all California public schools and most private schools.</p>

<p>If you’re planning to take the SAT this year or next, be aware that the demand for the exam is high, partly because it’s now fully digital and interest has surged. To secure a spot close to you, register at least two to three months ahead of time. CSArts is not an official testing site and likely never will be. CSArts student counselor Ms. Shiroma said that in order to become an official testing site, the school would have to block off all outside events on the day of the test. This option is not realistic, because CSArts cannot close its campus on Saturdays due to year-round student performances.</p>

<p>Another new issue: limited resources to prepare for the SAT. This is due to The College Board’s digital SAT preparatory materials still being developed. Although two months of preparation is suggested, it’s recommended that students take at least four months in advance to prepare and get accustomed to the adaptive nature of the digital SAT.</p>

<p>The digital SAT is structured into modules to adapt to individual students’ capabilities, providing a personalized testing experiences. The digital SAT has two sections: Reading &amp; Writing and Math, each divided into two modules. The first module is similar for everyone and helps determine which second module a student gets. If you do well in Module 1, you’ll get the harder Module 2B; if not, you’ll get the easier Module 2A. The scoring reflects this difference—Module 2A has a maximum score of about 590, while Module 2B allows for higher scores. Due to this, the preparatory questions you may be receiving from Khan Academy, or College Board may not be completely accurate to the kinds of questions you will face in your adaptive exam, therefore starting studying as far in advance as possible is extremely necessary.</p>

<p>The shift in college policies regarding SAT requirements, coupled with the recent transition to a fully digital test format, has highlighted the issue of SAT accessibility. For Juniors entering Senior year who hadn’t planned on taking the SAT, the reintroduction of SAT requirements at prestigious universities makes preparation challenging, especially with the new digital format’s unfamiliar elements. The pressure to learn the new digital SAT requires students to adapt quickly if they aim to apply to schools that now require the test.</p>

<p>The disparity in access to resources, like tutoring and the ability to retake the exam, gives wealthier students a distinct advantage. Families with more resources can afford extensive preparation and multiple attempts, leading to test scores that may reflect socioeconomic status more than academic potential. This could reinforce inequities in college admissions, as SAT scores become a barrier for students from lower-income backgrounds.</p>

<p>Although the transition to the new digital SAT format and the shift in college admissions policies may seem daunting, remember that many schools continue to be test-optional, providing flexibility in the application process. Plus, the resources for SAT preparation are constantly evolving, with new and improved materials being made available. So while it may be stressful, don’t lose hope—there’s support to help you succeed, and plenty of paths to your academic goals!</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been keeping up with the news, there have been many headlines regarding the reintroduction of mandatory SAT scores in the college admissions process within prestigious private universities like Harvard, MIT, Yale, and Princeton. Although this may be an intimidating list of universities, there are still plenty of amazing schools that will keep the test optional as well as test blind, with the exception of CalTech, all California public schools and most private schools.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/digital-sat.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/digital-sat.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Belt it Out!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/belt-it-out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Belt it Out!" /><published>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/belt-it-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/belt-it-out/"><![CDATA[<p>On April 13th, CSArts Seniors and Juniors in Taekwondo competed in the annual Taekwondo black belt test at OCSA! After two months of intense training all students who participated succeeded in getting their black belts!</p>

<p>The rigorous test took all day, and measured endurance, strength, combat prowess, and memorization. The day before the test, younger Taekwondo students wrote letters of encouragement to their Junior or Senior of choice. According to Master Foyle, students shed some tears, showing just how much peer support means to them.</p>

<p>Taekwondo is a Korean martial art that specializes in kicks and forms called “Poomsae.” In Taekwondo, students learn how to kick, strike, submit, and grapple. These are then put to use in the “sparring sessions” or training drills. If you want a good workout, while also learning discipline and self-defense, give it a try next Fall!</p>

<p>This isn’t the end of the road for the Taekwondo students. On the afternoon and evening of May 11th, students of all grades in Taekwondo will hold a performance at the PAC. They are rehearsing diligently for a show of strength, discipline, and motion ( along with some awesome music too)! If you have any questions, you can contact Mr. Foyle.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ares Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On April 13th, CSArts Seniors and Juniors in Taekwondo competed in the annual Taekwondo black belt test at OCSA! After two months of intense training all students who participated succeeded in getting their black belts!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Therapy Dogs and Ice Cream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/therapy-dogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Therapy Dogs and Ice Cream" /><published>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/therapy-dogs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/therapy-dogs/"><![CDATA[<p>Stress from the testing week is finally over, but more stress is on the way! It is important for students to take breaks from their studies as we get closer to the end of the school year, and find moments to relax. CSArts helps by giving free ice cream with the opportunity to hang out with therapy dogs after classes on Friday, April 12th.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I really enjoyed the event, it was a great way to destress and end the state testing week on a good note. Thank you CSArts!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Freshman Karina Yue said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I personally really enjoyed that it was free because it gave all students an opportunity to destress without having to worry about bringing cash, afford it, or anything,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Luna Nyguen said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The event was really fun for me because I got to play with a bunch of dogs- there were only three, which was a little disappointing… but I still did get to play with them, and see their cuteness,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Julian Torres said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was really helpful because, after the testing week, I was feeling very tired and stressed, but then the dogs and ice cream helped me and made me happier.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mariani Ogata noted.</p>

<p>The “End of Testing Week Celebration” was sponsored by CSArts Leadership. The event reminded students and staff how important it is to take care of our overall well-being at school. Here’s to creating a school community where every student’s success and happiness are top priority!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park &amp; Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stress from the testing week is finally over, but more stress is on the way! It is important for students to take breaks from their studies as we get closer to the end of the school year, and find moments to relax. CSArts helps by giving free ice cream with the opportunity to hang out with therapy dogs after classes on Friday, April 12th.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/therapy-dogs.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/therapy-dogs.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comic: Water Leak</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comic: Water Leak" /><published>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-3/"><![CDATA[<p>Read “Spencer’s Show Pt. 3: Water Leak”</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/comics/comic-water-leakage.jpg" alt="Spencer's Show Pt 3: Water Leak" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Sofia Ruiz</name></author><category term="comics" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read “Spencer’s Show Pt. 3: Water Leak”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-leakage.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-leakage.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>