<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-16T16:22:11-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sweet and Sour: Halloween’s Impact on the Environment</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/halloween-impact/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sweet and Sour: Halloween’s Impact on the Environment" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/halloween-impact</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/halloween-impact/"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine: it’s the night of Halloween, and you’re taking a walk down the street to meet up at your friend’s house for a Halloween party. Your shoes crush candy wrappers scattering the floor, and little kids run by, hands clutching plastic bags full of sweets. Every doorstep is lined with carved pumpkins, skeleton garlands, and light-up ghosts; every lawn is covered with tombstones and zombie hands. People walk around decked out in skulls, masks, and faux bandages, fully immersed in the whirlwind of the holiday.</p>

<p>Pretty great, right? Sure. But after the spooky fun, a question arises: pumpkins, costumes, candy… what happens to all that stuff? In many cases, the answer isn’t as sweet.</p>

<p>Take jack o’ lanterns, for example. Out of the people who buy pumpkins to carve them, over half throw them away afterward. According to Hummingbird International, 18,000 tons of pumpkins – that’s like 360 million portions of pumpkin pie – are dumped in landfills, and they release methane gas when decomposed, a greenhouse gas that’s around 20 times more harmful to the environment than CO2.</p>

<p>But pumpkins aren’t the only thing that end up in landfills. Every year, 35 million Halloween costumes are thrown away. Not only that, but it takes more than half of these costumes 20 to 200 years to decompose. Another problem is that, as mentioned by Commons, many costumes are made from petroleum-based plastics, which use fossil fuels, a non-renewable resource.</p>

<p>Along with the costumes, Halloween candy contributes to a significant portion of plastic packaging waste at 30%.  A Californai  recycling website says candy wrappers are often made of a mix of materials, like aluminum and plastics, and they’re pretty small. This makes them hard to separate and sort, meaning much of it can’t be recycled.</p>

<p>So, how can you help?</p>

<p>One way is to find candy that uses reusable or biodegradable packaging, or even a replacement for candy instead, like cookies or oranges with jack o’ lantern faces. You can also repurpose, recycle, or donate your costumes, as less thrown away means less textile waste. Same idea for pumpkins: instead of chucking them, try composting them, cooking them, or feeding them to pets.</p>

<p>And remember, these aren’t the only actions you can take to make a change. Being eco-conscious starts with little things like this, but staying eco-conscious takes a little more effort. Those were just a few ways you and your community can help out the environment… so that next Halloween isn’t such a scare.</p>]]></content><author><name>Danica Chen</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine: it’s the night of Halloween, and you’re taking a walk down the street to meet up at your friend’s house for a Halloween party. Your shoes crush candy wrappers scattering the floor, and little kids run by, hands clutching plastic bags full of sweets. Every doorstep is lined with carved pumpkins, skeleton garlands, and light-up ghosts; every lawn is covered with tombstones and zombie hands. People walk around decked out in skulls, masks, and faux bandages, fully immersed in the whirlwind of the holiday.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/halloween-impact.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/halloween-impact.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Online Safety</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/online-safety/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Online Safety" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/online-safety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/online-safety/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s safe to say that the majority of high-schoolers, especially CSArts students, are very active online. Many may feel like their phones are extensions of themselves. It’s easy to become immersed in the whole spectacle and find a sense of community, but it’s becoming easier to stumble upon the darker sides of the web, especially given the current state of the world right now. Keeping yourself safe, prioritizing your mental health, and distancing yourself from the vitriol online is more important now than ever.</p>

<p>We at the CSArtisan believe that one should prioritize keeping up to date with current events and educating oneself about global issues, but not at the expense of your mental health and personal comforts. The internet can be used to learn about so much so thoroughly, but it becomes a problem when it affects our collective mental health.</p>

<p>It’s vital to be able to critically analyze and evaluate the sources of information or media on the internet. Information on the internet is everywhere, but so is misinformation. The skill to properly evaluate sources and separate fact from opinion is called media literacy. Here’s how you can start:</p>

<p>First, ask questions about the content you’re viewing. Who created it, and what’s their agenda? What do they want to convince you of? What kinds of bias might they have? What kind of emotional appeals are they using? Where do they get their information?</p>

<p>Second, diversify your sources to gain a broader perspective, and always fact-check information. While having too many sources can be overwhelming, having a variety of sources with different individual biases can be helpful in straining out the important details. It’s also very important to double check for the specific context and date of the information.</p>

<p>Third, reduce your exposure to violent or political content. There are many resources to help filter content that may be violent in nature, or generally stress-inducing. Using content filters and parental controls helps limit the amount of potentially violent content on your social media feed, and also helps you unplug generally and focus more on the real world.</p>

<p>Fourth, installing ad blockers and content filters is a good idea for any internet user, but especially those who want to avoid potentially troubling content. Your attention on the internet is a very valuable thing, and unfortunately people will go to great lengths to harness it by deliberately promoting provocative or unsettling content to bring in attention. Utilizing ad blockers will not only make your experience on the internet a little less annoying, but it also can protect you from triggering media.</p>

<p>Generally, the best way to ensure that you won’t be thrust into any uncomfortable or triggering online media is to be selective in choosing who you connect with online and where you get your information from.</p>

<p>We, at the CSArtisan, recognize that times are changing, and it’s scary, but in the face of it all remember that we each have the autonomy to create a better digital sphere and generally make the world a kinder place.</p>]]></content><author><name>Samson Khachatryan</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s safe to say that the majority of high-schoolers, especially CSArts students, are very active online. Many may feel like their phones are extensions of themselves. It’s easy to become immersed in the whole spectacle and find a sense of community, but it’s becoming easier to stumble upon the darker sides of the web, especially given the current state of the world right now. Keeping yourself safe, prioritizing your mental health, and distancing yourself from the vitriol online is more important now than ever.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/9.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/9.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Truth of Thanksgiving</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/truth-of-thanksgiving/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Truth of Thanksgiving" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/truth-of-thanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/truth-of-thanksgiving/"><![CDATA[<p>Thanksgiving is a time to remember the truth. For many years, the story of Thanksgiving has been rewritten to conceal its dark history. Some may have grown up with the story of a happy celebration between Indigenous people and Europeans, where both ate dinner together in peace. These sugar-coated stories – among many others – have caused lasting damage.</p>

<p>In reality, according to the Smithsonian Magazine, massacres and disease shaped the holiday into what is known today as Thanksgiving. The Wampanoag tribe, one of the indigenous tribes living in America at the time, was most connected with the story of Thanksgiving. Massasoit, the chief of the Wampanoag tribe, sought an alliance with the settlers of Plymouth. Many of his people had been infected with disease and he hoped for help.</p>

<p>This Thanksgiving “peace” did not last. The Wampanoag tribe and the settlers of Plymouth fought against France and other local indigenous tribes. As more Europeans arrived, the Wampanoag tribe continued to die from the diseases brought over by early settlers. After Massasoit passed away, his son Metacomet, known as King Philip, became chief. Soon the strained relations between the Wampanoag tribe and European settlers finally broke. Metacomet’s men were slaughtered for the murder of John Sassamon, a Ponkapoag interpreter and Christian convert, sparking a bloody and devastating war. Metacomet was beheaded and dismembered.</p>

<p>Due to the dark past of Thanksgiving, many U.S. citizens call for a reexamination of the meaning of the holiday. In 1970, the Aquinnah Wampanoag activist Frank James helped establish a National Day of Mourning, which occurs on November 23. The plaque at Cole’s Hill in Plymouth, Massachusetts states, “It is a day of remembrance and spiritual connection as well as a protest of the racism and oppression which Native Americans continue to experience.”</p>

<p>The true origin of Thanksgiving has been shrouded for generations. Many debate over the date of the first Thanksgiving. Some argue it occurred in 1637 when Governor John Winthrop celebrated the massacre of 900 Pequot indigenous people. Others think it was in 1621.</p>

<p>Now the world knows the truth of Thanksgiving. Communities around the world celebrate what they are thankful for while also remembering Thanksgiving’s past. Knowing the horrors of history has inspired people to enlighten others. We must all learn from past mistakes and work to maintain gratitude and peace.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanksgiving is a time to remember the truth. For many years, the story of Thanksgiving has been rewritten to conceal its dark history. Some may have grown up with the story of a happy celebration between Indigenous people and Europeans, where both ate dinner together in peace. These sugar-coated stories – among many others – have caused lasting damage.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/truth-of-thanksgiving.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/truth-of-thanksgiving.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Spooky Good Time</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/spooky-good-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Spooky Good Time" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/spooky-good-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/spooky-good-time/"><![CDATA[<p>Why did the ghost go to the Halloween party? Because he heard it was going to be “spook”-tacular! This October, CSArts had a “spooktacular” party of their own by hosting another amazing “Spooky Fest.”</p>

<p>The event consisted of many thrilling events such as trunk or treat, club fundraisers, student performances, and a student-directed haunted house! Located out on the field, parents and students decorated their cars with spooky ribbons, pumpkins, and spider webs, with games for students to have a shot at winning sugary treats. In the Quad, clubs held fundraisers, selling food and drinks like boba, root beer floats, and donuts, as well as trinkets like bracelets and plants. On stage, Popular Music, Dance, and Instrumental Music students wowed the crowd with their performances.</p>

<p>But the spookiest attraction of all was the haunted house located in the cafeteria. Directed by the Junior Co-Class presidents, the house consisted of students acting as bloody clowns, creepy contortionists, frightening carnival characters, and more. With student-done makeup, decorations, and costumes, the event was a huge hit, and had a line out the door the entire time. Students and adults alike were amazed by the effort and fun of the event. One student comments,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The haunted house was fun and I like the effort the actors put into it, from the costumes, to the makeup, and the props. Their acting was funny and entertaining!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This year, CSArts had a great spooky season, and we can’t wait for the next one!</p>]]></content><author><name>Juliet Martinez and Aryhanna Pham</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why did the ghost go to the Halloween party? Because he heard it was going to be “spook”-tacular! This October, CSArts had a “spooktacular” party of their own by hosting another amazing “Spooky Fest.”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanksgiving and Native American Artists</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/native-american-artists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving and Native American Artists" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/native-american-artists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/native-american-artists/"><![CDATA[<p>The American national holiday where most gather to feast on delicious traditional stuffed turkey and creamy mashed potatoes is just around the corner. Each year it is also a remembrance to the families and communities of Native Americans who share the history of the celebration. The first Thanksgiving lasted three days and was a banquet of unionizing the Wampanoag tribe and the Pilgrims who arrived from the Mayflower seeking a new life and work in America. On November 23, 1621, when there was roasted corn and vegetables, the Pilgrims betrayed the Wampanoag tribe by stealing their food, land and spreading diseases to the Native Americans.</p>

<p>Checking out Indigenous artists’ work during this year’s Native American Heritage Month is an amazing way to show support for the community. Published this year, Leah Myers’ memoir “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinning-Blood-Memoir-Family-Identity/dp/1324036702">Thinning Blood</a>” speaks on how growing up Native American and the trials and tribulations of the possibility of being the last member of her family to qualify in her tribe. Myers writes her poetry in the form of a totem, each pillar is dedicated to an important woman in her life. In this heart wrenching book there are elements of folklore, growing up and finding one’s true identity.</p>

<p>For the people who want to immerse themselves in a fantasy novel this autumn, “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shape-Dragons-Breath-First-Nampeshiweisit/dp/0593498283">To Shape A Dragon’s Breath</a>,” by Monique Blackgoose tells the story of a young Indigenous woman in the 19th century who learns to adapt and overcome her school’s racist and colonial environment. “To Shape a Dragons Breath” is just the beginning for Blackgoose’s Nampeshiweisit series where beasts and mythical creatures are met at every page.</p>

<p>Hulu dramedy, <a href="https://www.fxnetworks.com/shows/reservation-dogs">Reservation Dogs</a> takes place in Eastern Oklhoma where a teenage group of delinquents go about their day to day lives robbing and saving money to begin a rejuvenated life in their dreamy, romanticized California. This gem of a show targets the soul with its themes of grief and healing with a dash of laughter. It is a perfect binge-watch for this Thanksgiving break with friends and family.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Gutierrez</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The American national holiday where most gather to feast on delicious traditional stuffed turkey and creamy mashed potatoes is just around the corner. Each year it is also a remembrance to the families and communities of Native Americans who share the history of the celebration. The first Thanksgiving lasted three days and was a banquet of unionizing the Wampanoag tribe and the Pilgrims who arrived from the Mayflower seeking a new life and work in America. On November 23, 1621, when there was roasted corn and vegetables, the Pilgrims betrayed the Wampanoag tribe by stealing their food, land and spreading diseases to the Native Americans.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bees Swarm CSArts</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/bees-swarm-csarts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bees Swarm CSArts" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/bees-swarm-csarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/bees-swarm-csarts/"><![CDATA[<p>The buzz of bees around campus is bittersweet. Without them, our world would cease to exist.  With them, comes concerns, but you can help! Cleaning up after yourself might be the key to reducing the swarms. Recently, bees have been buzzing around and inside trash cans on campus and classrooms, as well as circling around students during lunch, crawling on, and eating their food. Some students are allergic to bees, so this is a source of concern. Epi-pens are available at the Health Office just in case.</p>

<p>Students have shown signs of discomfort toward the bees, likely because no one wants to get stung.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I tried to eat my lunch… outside and a bee also wanted to eat my lunch so I had to move locations,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Katie C. (VA ‘27).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve never been stung or anything, but they’ve been flying around and crawling on food we’re supposed to be eating,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Rochelle W. (CW ‘27).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That’s not cool.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>School administrators say there are solutions to the “bee problem.”  In the Weekly Wrap on November 3rd, 2023, CSArts administration issued a statement on the bees, writing:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Our Facilities Team completed an inspection and concluded that there are no active hives on campus. With this in mind, please understand that bees are a vital part of the natural ecosystem, and our campus does experience seasonal fluctuations of their activity throughout the year. The maintenance team is working hard to resolve some of the issues and concerns by increasing clean up on campus, landscaping, and frequently deep cleaning our trash cans, as bees are attracted to these areas.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As for what students can do to help with the bee problems, admin says,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Students can do their part by cleaning up after themselves and ensuring that their trash goes into the appropriate receptacles.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Other possible ways to avoid the bees include staying away from the trash cans or using smells that bees don’t like like cloves and peppermint. With work from both the maintenance crew and CSArts students, the bee issues should lesson as we head into colder temperatures and wet weather during the Winter.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ren Carr &amp; Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The buzz of bees around campus is bittersweet. Without them, our world would cease to exist. With them, comes concerns, but you can help! Cleaning up after yourself might be the key to reducing the swarms. Recently, bees have been buzzing around and inside trash cans on campus and classrooms, as well as circling around students during lunch, crawling on, and eating their food. Some students are allergic to bees, so this is a source of concern. Epi-pens are available at the Health Office just in case.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/bees-swarm-csarts.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/bees-swarm-csarts.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Power of Gratitude: Everyday Positivity</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/everyday-positivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Power of Gratitude: Everyday Positivity" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/everyday-positivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/everyday-positivity/"><![CDATA[<p>The same word is heard every Thanksgiving: gratitude. That leaves many wondering, what exactly is gratitude? What does it look like? Gratitude is so important in our daily lives, not just on Thanksgiving.</p>

<p>The Personal Excellence Foundation explains how gratitude impacts teens in everyday life. Gratitude positively affects learning and mental health and hosts many physical benefits. According to the Mayo Clinic Health System (MCHS), thankfulness should be practiced every day. Gratitude can be found everywhere: a teacher helping a student in class, a cup of coffee in the morning, or a friend cheering someone up when they’re down. Gratitude can also affect sleep, a necessity especially for students staying at school until 5:00!</p>

<p>One way to help remind yourself to be thankful is to keep a gratitude journal. MCHS suggests writing down something positive about your day, like hearing your favorite song on the radio, a friend helping you study, or maybe your significant other supporting you in challenging times. People create gratitude lists of seven things they are thankful for. They have to think deeply, about more than only pets or family, but anything meaningful to them.</p>

<p>To show thankfulness to others, some may host a Friendsgiving and celebrate with their chosen family. Others invite relatives to share food and thanks. Many of us may be familiar with “Table Sharing,” where everyone at the table shares something they’re grateful for. Some people even write gratitude cards, gifting them to friends, parents, or teachers. They bring positivity into the lives of others while brightening their own. Expressing gratitude is an important part of not only Thanksgiving but daily life!</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Linnea Venti</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The same word is heard every Thanksgiving: gratitude. That leaves many wondering, what exactly is gratitude? What does it look like? Gratitude is so important in our daily lives, not just on Thanksgiving.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/everyday-positivity.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/everyday-positivity.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">College App Deadlines Approach</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/college-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="College App Deadlines Approach" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/college-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/college-apps/"><![CDATA[<p>As the time to submit college apps comes closer and closer, stress builds as students are trying to complete their applications. The college application process can be an overwhelming experience for high school students. From choosing the right schools to crafting compelling essays, applicants often find themselves needing guidance. The CSArtisan interviewed some students on how they are feeling about college applications.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think college applications have hard parts, such as putting in academic classes, but I think my essays are going good right now,” Ryan Hori (VA ‘24)</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’m feeling stressed. I haven’t really started anything out, so I’m worried I’m going to do things wrong,” Tyree Dilihay (VA ‘24)</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s going a little bit better since early decisions and actions have passed. I think if I stay on top of it, I’ll be fine. As of right now, I am not, so it is getting a little stressful as the deadline is approaching,” Justin Cheng (IM-P ‘24)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Some students are ahead of the game, and have already gotten accepted.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve gotten accepted to a couple of colleges already and I’ve been offered some scholarships. I have applied to Azusa Pacific University and then a couple of smaller colleges in Scotland,” Vira Dowdle (MT ‘24)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>AP Literature teacher  Emma Thompson,  hosted one-on-one sessions to help students compose and revise college essays.</p>

<p>Students said it helps to have more than one pair of eyes on their applications and appreciated the extra help.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the meetings, we went over examples of other essays and saw what parts of them were good and what wasn’t, and different ways to make your essay more interesting,” said Aleen Kojikian (VA ‘24)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>School counselors are available to help with any college application questions in room 100 during office hours. They will available through the end of this semester.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mason Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the time to submit college apps comes closer and closer, stress builds as students are trying to complete their applications. The college application process can be an overwhelming experience for high school students. From choosing the right schools to crafting compelling essays, applicants often find themselves needing guidance. The CSArtisan interviewed some students on how they are feeling about college applications.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Podcast Alert!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Podcast Alert!" /><published>2023-10-20T07:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T07:01:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert/"><![CDATA[<p>Loving the CSArtisan newspaper but getting sluggish eyes? No worries! The CSArtisan has a brand new podcast: “CSArtisan Talks!”  It’s our goal to give students a “literal” voice and serve the student body with the most accurate information through our podcast! You can find “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0HJcSdDT6CnREdafnh1Ilo">CSArtisan Talks</a>” on Spotify. Look for new episodes with each issue.</p>

<p>CSArtisan Talks gives students a chance to listen to the latest students news at CSArts San Gabriel Valley! Don’t have time to sit down and read the latest news? We’ve got you covered!  In the car, on the train, or while you’re out for a jog!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As the creator of the podcast, I wanted to take different external and internal factors into consideration. I was inspired by Mr. Blair, creative writing teacher and club manager of the CSArtisan, who taught about making all stories and reports applicable to everyone! And CSArts has the core valley of  excellence and equity for all, while fostering a nurturing environment of creativity, respect, and collaboration. I hope to exemplify this  idea of being inclusive and creating an audio version with a podcast is the perfect way to meet these goals.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Karina Yue, Producer and Host of “CSArtisan Talks”</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When I heard about the podcast, I loved it, such a great way for everyone to listen!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Vana Kojikian, fellow writer of the CSArtisan.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Honestly, listening instead of reading the newspaper is so much more enticing. I’ll definitely go check it out, and everyone else should too!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Alyeen Park</p>

<p>You can find “CSArtisan Talks” <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0HJcSdDT6CnREdafnh1Ilo">on Spotify</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loving the CSArtisan newspaper but getting sluggish eyes? No worries! The CSArtisan has a brand new podcast: “CSArtisan Talks!” It’s our goal to give students a “literal” voice and serve the student body with the most accurate information through our podcast! You can find “CSArtisan Talks” on Spotify. Look for new episodes with each issue.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/csartisan-talks.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/csartisan-talks.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Hispanic Heritage Month</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Hispanic Heritage Month" /><published>2023-10-20T07:00:35-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T07:00:35-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Each September, Latino and Hispanic people throughout The United States observe their countries’ Independence Day on September 15th! The celebrations of culture and history don’t stop there!  Hispanic Heritage Month originally started as a week in August, 1968 by President Johnson. In August, 1988 the week was extended to a month (from September 15th to October 15th) by President Reagan. The declaration was created to celebrate Hispanic/Latino independence days and culture with parades, traditional foods, and parties.</p>

<p>The celebration recognizes the 64 million Americans of Hispanic/Latino descent, and their  important historical contributions. From political activism, to art, to entreprenuership, Hispanics and Latinos from the U.S have shaped the country into what it is today. Throughout the month, corporations like Starbucks, Target, and Barnes and Noble have participated in Hispanic Heritage month by promoting and incorporating the work of Latino and Hispanic people into their products. Barnes and Noble dedicated a wall specifically for books written by Hispanic authors, while companies like Starbucks and Target released merchandise specifically created by Hispanic artists.</p>

<p>At CSArts, Spanish teachers design special lessons during the month in order to  teach students about the many different cultures and traditions surrounding people of Hispanic and Latin origin. AP Spanish teacher Andrea Nelson, says the designated month  gives students a break from exams, and gives them insight into the culture and the important role the Hispanic and Latino community plays in the U.S.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Recognition and celebration are a good starting point for our year round focus on Latino culture. Two aspects are most important for AP Spanish, Spanish 4 Honors and Spanish 3 Honors: we celebrate by using the language as a means of communication and develop cultural appreciation for Latino influences around the world.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The learning experience isn’t just focused on books. Students passing by Spanish classrooms in the 400’s will hear music and the sounds of students competing as they play Spanish games in order to deepen their understanding and appreciation of the language and culture. The celebration doesn’t end there!</p>

<p>Just weeks after the end of Hispanic Heritage Month, El Dia de los Muertos will begin, honoring and celebrating the lives of those who have passed away. There are many traditions, holidays, and events etched into Hispanic and Latino culture that are worth celebrating and recognizing, as they have such a large impact on the U.S too. To learn more and connect with Hispanic and Latin culture, feel free to pass by a Spanish classroom, visit a LUCHA meeting, or even just watch some classic telenovelas!</p>]]></content><author><name>Juliet Martinez &amp; Sophia Gutierrez</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Each September, Latino and Hispanic people throughout The United States observe their countries’ Independence Day on September 15th! The celebrations of culture and history don’t stop there! Hispanic Heritage Month originally started as a week in August, 1968 by President Johnson. In August, 1988 the week was extended to a month (from September 15th to October 15th) by President Reagan. The declaration was created to celebrate Hispanic/Latino independence days and culture with parades, traditional foods, and parties.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/hispanic-heritage-month-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/hispanic-heritage-month-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>