<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-23T21:59:50-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Books, Bans and Control</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/book-bans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Books, Bans and Control" /><published>2025-10-26T05:50:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T05:50:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/book-bans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/book-bans/"><![CDATA[<p>The history of book banning in the United States runs almost as far back as its origin. Although lack of records makes it hard to pinpoint the first banned books in U.S. history, Uncle Tom’s Cabin is widely regarded as one of the first American books to be widely banned. Written by white abolitionist author Harriet Beecher Stowe, the novel followed the lives of a group of fictional enslaved people in the South. It became extremely popular in the North among abolitionists but faced harsh criticism in the South. Before long, widespread bans took effect across the region.</p>

<p>Book bans are not new. They are a recurring form of cultural control that often reflect a society’s deepest fears. <em>Uncle Tom’s Cabin</em> threatened both the economic and moral justification of slavery, and banning it became a way to maintain control over the narrative.</p>

<p>Examining historical examples of book bans is important because censorship has often served as a warning sign of larger shifts away from democracy. In Germany during the 1930s, books considered “non-German” were banned and burned during the “Campaign against the Un-German Spirit.” Jewish, queer, socialist, and Marxist works were targeted. The campaign operated under the guise of protection, claiming to “cleanse” Germany of dangerous ideas. The control of information became a way to control people, helping pave the way for the rise of the Nazi regime.</p>

<p>History shows us that book bans are rarely about protection. They are about power, deciding who gets to speak, and protecting existing power structures.</p>

<p>In modern times, book banning has re-emerged across the United States at an increasing rate, often in schools and public libraries. Thousands of titles have been challenged or removed, many for addressing race, gender identity, or sexuality. These stories are often targeted by claiming that they are a threat to “American values.”</p>

<p>Underdog Bookstore, a bookstore in Monrovia, CA, is a non-profit that features LGBTQIA+, BIPOC, Disabled and Neurodiverse authors. “Books by authors of color; stories that feature LGBTQIA+ characters; books by women, written about women…. all of these are banned at higher rates.” Said Underdog Bookstore President Kealie Mardell-Carrera and Underdog Bookstore Board Member, Banned Books Club Host Nicole Arca.</p>

<p>The argument of protection has been used to justify erasing what threatens the existing power structures and social norms. In the 1800s, it was stories about slavery. In the 1930s, it was Jewish writers. Today, it’s books that explore race, gender and sexual identity.</p>

<p>Many of the arguments in support of book bans in schools and libraries follow the idea that children do not need to be exposed to the idea of gender, sexuality and race.</p>

<p>One of the most vocal groups behind the modern wave of book bans is Moms for Liberty, a conservative organization that describes itself as advocating for parental rights in education. The group has gained significant influence at school board meetings and in local elections across the country, leading campaigns to remove books they deem “sexually explicit” or “politically biased.” While their stated goal is to protect children, their efforts have targeted books featuring LGBTQ+ characters, discussions of race, or social inequality.</p>

<p>“Limiting access to books, especially for younger readers, threatens our ability to understand parts of the world and people we may not encounter directly. There’s only so much we can see from our own lived experiences; books make the world a little larger for all of us and help us build empathy in the process. Those who claim that book bans protect children are often deliberately ignoring the difference between providing access to age-appropriate reading material, which is the norm in schools and libraries, and banning books because you personally disagree with the content.” Said Nicole Arca.</p>

<p>In recent years, these efforts have taken on a more organized and political form.  According to the American Library Association, “Pressure groups and government entities that include elected officials, board members, and administrators initiated 72% of demands to censor books in school and public libraries.” During the Trump administration, rhetoric about “fake news” and “indoctrination” in schools has deepened the distrust in education and media institutions. This growing skepticism created an environment where removing books seems necessary to some.</p>

<p>Project 2025, a political initiative backed by several conservative organizations including those closely tied to the Trump administration such as the Heritage Foundation, proposes widespread changes to federal policy, including reshaping education and cultural institutions to reflect “American” ideological values. While it doesn’t call for outright book bans, it is focused on controlling what is taught and how information is shared and places a heavy emphasis on white American nationalist evangelical viewpoints.</p>

<p>It is important to note that President Trump denied any connection to Project 2025 during his 2024 presidential campaign, even stating during a televised debate with Kamala Harris, “I have nothing to do with Project 2025. I haven’t read it. I don’t want to read it, purposely. I’m not going to read it.” However, in the past weeks he has held a private meeting with Russell Vought, one of the main authors of project 2025 and included him in an AI generated video posted on his “Truth Social” account.</p>

<p>It is important that we are able to recognize why certain books are being targeted and understand who it benefits. It’s also important to ask ourselves who it harms. The removal of inclusive books from accessible places like public libraries can cause harm to children who may have otherwise been represented in those spaces. It can create a stigma around topics that reflect many American’s everyday lives leading to more division and a gap in connectedness and empathy.</p>

<p>“When certain books or authors are stigmatized or silenced, it sends a message about which stories are considered acceptable and which are not. When censorship happens, it is definitely a warning sign of larger social and political issues. It is a clearcut attempt to eradicate original and individual thought by controlling the means by which people get their information. It’s no secret that knowledge is power, so banning or stigmatizing certain books is also a way to curtail the power of certain groups of people.” Said Kealie Mardell-Carrera.</p>

<p>The next time you hear about a book ban, ask yourself why was this book targeted? Who does the ban benefit and who does it harm? These attacks against literature are intertwined with the belief that controlling information can protect a nation’s identity. History shows that this control does the opposite. It weakens societies by cutting off conversation, empathy, and the exchange of ideas.</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The history of book banning in the United States runs almost as far back as its origin. Although lack of records makes it hard to pinpoint the first banned books in U.S. history, Uncle Tom’s Cabin is widely regarded as one of the first American books to be widely banned. Written by white abolitionist author Harriet Beecher Stowe, the novel followed the lives of a group of fictional enslaved people in the South. It became extremely popular in the North among abolitionists but faced harsh criticism in the South. Before long, widespread bans took effect across the region.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History Of Mexican American Music - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History Of Mexican American Music - Part 2" /><published>2025-10-26T05:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T05:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-part-2/"><![CDATA[<p>The era of 1960s and 1970s Mexican American music was significant. With the Chicano movement of the 1970s and national attention on Mexican Americans, musicians of this time reflected the era with their specific brand of music. Bands like El Chicano, Los Lobos are emblematic of this movement. While artists such as Linda Ronstadt and Santana were Main stage performers of this time, punk bands like The Zeros and Alice Bag, while less well-known, were highly influential.</p>

<p>Los Lobos, El Chicano, and Santana are often regarded as the leading Mexican American bands of this era. Although these artists had unique sounds, they shared similar qualities, playing music reminiscent of American styles of soul and jazz with Latin influences. El Chicano, a band most prevalent during the 1970s, covered both Herbie Hancock, a prominent funk musician, and famous boleros like "Sabor a Mi." El Chicano was a group influenced by the Chicano movement of the 70’s. Their music was representative of the Mexican American identity, blending Latin salsa influences and reflecting the fight for representation within American Society. Los Lobos is another band similar to El Chicano. It also had jazz and Latin influences along with folk, country, and rock. A group of high school students from East LA formed the band. The founding members bonded over their shared weird affinity for country music. The band members loved classic country and folk singers, such as Ry Cooder. They also loved to cover many of Riche Valens' songs. Much like the El Chicanos, Los Lobos were activists for the Chicano movement.</p>

<p>Santana and Linda Ronstadt are two other artists of the time who represented Mexican Americans as large stars of the era. Santana, a guitarist and activist, was part of the 1970s rock movement, playing with Jerry Garcia of the Grateful Dead. Santana has had a long and successful solo career, producing hit songs such as "Oye Como Va" and "Black Magic Woman." Later in his career, he was featured on Lauryn Hill's album, The Miseducation of Lauryn Hill, which is ranked as the number one album on Apple Music's list of the 100 best albums. Linda Ronstadt is a Grammy Lifetime Achievement Award winner who has performed across multiple genres, including rock, country, opera, and Latin Music. She was the first woman to have three consecutive platinum albums. Although Rondstandt did not celebrate her Mexican American identity until much later in her career, she was truly a pillar of Mexican American excellence during this time and beyond.</p>

<p>Another less discussed area of music is the Mexican American punk scene. Primarily centered in East LA during the 1970s and spanning into the 1990s, there was a big Mexican American punk scene. Two of the best-known bands were The Zeros and The Bags. The Zeros from Chula Vista, California, were commonly referred to as the Mexican Ramones. They played large concerts in Los Angeles and San Diego while they were still in High School and were actually one of the first U.S. punk Bands. They played with The Clash and Devo. The lead singer and guitarist, Javier Escovedo, came from a musical family. His dad played in a mariachi band and passed his passion to all of his 13 children. Javier's older brothers played with Santana and Malo. The Zeros' music library is limited, but I highly recommend that all readers check them out. Their style feels ahead of its time.</p>

<p>Alice Bag, on the other hand, was from East Los Angeles and created her own career as Alice Bag as well as a band called The Bags. She was a part of a wave of California punk artists that included Black Flag, X, and the Germs. Both of her parents were Mexican Immigrants. As with many Chicanos her age, Bag’s father immigrated through the Braseros program. Her experience as a Mexican American influenced her to be an activist and to come up with a style known as Punk-Chera. A blend of punk and ranchera performances.</p>

<p>These artists were not only impactful to Mexican Americans during their time but to the music as a whole, evidenced by their awards, social commentary, influence, and prevalence today.</p>]]></content><author><name>Henry Soderlind</name></author><category term="history" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The era of 1960s and 1970s Mexican American music was significant. With the Chicano movement of the 1970s and national attention on Mexican Americans, musicians of this time reflected the era with their specific brand of music. Bands like El Chicano, Los Lobos are emblematic of this movement. While artists such as Linda Ronstadt and Santana were Main stage performers of this time, punk bands like The Zeros and Alice Bag, while less well-known, were highly influential.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/history-of-mexican-american-music-part-2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/history-of-mexican-american-music-part-2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Senior Test Scores Down</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/senior-test-scores-down/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Senior Test Scores Down" /><published>2025-10-26T05:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T05:20:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/senior-test-scores-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/senior-test-scores-down/"><![CDATA[<p>High school seniors in the United States are experiencing steep declines in math and reading performance. With average scores at their lowest levels in over two decades, the issue is a serious cause for concern, especially among teachers and policymakers.</p>

<p>Findings from the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) indicated that 32% of 12th-grade students now perform below basic reading achievement levels, compared to 20% in 1992. Meanwhile, only 35% of seniors demonstrated proficient reading skills in 2024, down from 37% in 2019 and 40% in 1992. Similarly with math, only one-third of seniors performed at a level showing college readiness, compared to 37% in 2019.</p>

<p>“Despite spending billions annually on numerous K-12 programs, the achievement gap is widening,” said Education Secretary Linda McMahon.</p>

<p>There are several factors causing the downward trend. The COVID-19 pandemic significantly disrupted education and led to severe knowledge gaps. Changes in technology use and the way students consume information have also played a role.</p>

<p>However, CSArts-SGV Principal Nicole Read cautions against viewing test scores as the end-all be-all.</p>

<p>“There is so much going on right now, socially and emotionally, so I can see why students are struggling. I’m not surprised because scores have been on the decline for a long time, and this is just a continuation of that, unfortunately,” Read said.</p>

<p>Although important for determining academic readiness, parents and students should not only focus on standardized test scores to define their self-worth.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[High school seniors in the United States are experiencing steep declines in math and reading performance. With average scores at their lowest levels in over two decades, the issue is a serious cause for concern, especially among teachers and policymakers.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/senior-test-scores-down.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/senior-test-scores-down.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Day In the Life Of A Stage Manager</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/day-in-the-life-of-a-stage-manager/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day In the Life Of A Stage Manager" /><published>2025-10-26T05:10:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T05:10:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/day-in-the-life-of-a-stage-manager</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/day-in-the-life-of-a-stage-manager/"><![CDATA[<p>Stage managing is no easy feat, it’s one of the most demanding theater jobs and requires full attention. That's why only a select few are chosen to take on the task. CSArts' new upcoming acting shows, <em>Big Love</em>, <em>Women of Lockerbie</em> and <em>Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow</em>, give new opportunities for student stage managers to step into the spotlight. It’s an exciting lineup-it holds many new and unique responsibilities to the production and design students.</p>

<p>The stage manager for <em>Moscow</em>, Akira Mack (P&amp;D ‘26), is an example of the dedication and hard work put into the shows. Akira's stage manager duties begin after school for rehearsals, where he is responsible for coordinating communication between the crew and cast, taking detailed notes, calling cues and much more. With only a couple of minutes to eat food before rushing away to the studios to ensure everything runs smoothly. Afterwards, he sits next to the director for the full rehearsal and takes comprehensive notes. The notes help actors identify areas of improvement and assist the crew in managing props. Usually around 9:00, rehearsals end. They need to send out emails reminding actors and staff of important deadlines and upcoming duties.</p>

<p>Rehearsals are just the start, once tech week begins, the stage manager's list of jobs expands. Tech week stretches the times of rehearsal, making it end around 10-11:00 pm. Not to mention the stage manager has to start building the black box set for the actors. While also maintaining their original roles, stage managers must learn different blocking techniques, cues and tracking the actors on stage.” I’ve had to learn fair share rehearsal reports, block, short hand, track where the actors are on stage,” Akira explains. “And practically learn another language, almost like hieroglyphics, to memorize scenes.”</p>

<p>Although years in production and design have prepared him for this challenge, Akira reflects, “ There are a lot of personal emotions with the first time stage managing. Mistakes are guaranteed to happen on large projects like these, it’s the crew and actors' ability to compromise that makes this a beautiful experience.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Hannah Anderson</name></author><category term="conservatory" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stage managing is no easy feat, it’s one of the most demanding theater jobs and requires full attention. That's why only a select few are chosen to take on the task. CSArts' new upcoming acting shows, Big Love, Women of Lockerbie and Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow Moscow, give new opportunities for student stage managers to step into the spotlight. It’s an exciting lineup-it holds many new and unique responsibilities to the production and design students.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/day-in-the-life-of-a-stage-manager.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/day-in-the-life-of-a-stage-manager.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Spotlight: Lexy’s Nailsets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-lexys-nailsets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Spotlight: Lexy’s Nailsets" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-lexys-nailsets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-lexys-nailsets/"><![CDATA[<p>Calling all glam lovers! If you’re looking for a fresh new set of nails, look out for Lexy Nichols, a beginner nail tech and senior here at CSArts. Lexy began her nail journey her freshman year of high school, “I started doing it because it helped me cope in a way,” she said. After spending time practicing nails on her friends who appreciated her talents, she discovered her passion for the art form. Lexy has plenty of experience in the fine arts as a visual art student, and being able to apply her artistic skills in her nail business comes in handy!</p>

<p>It may seem difficult to balance school and an after-school business, but Lexy shows that despite the challenge, she is able to persevere with her interests. She said, “The school is very willing to work with me, so I have a good balance and schedule.” Living near campus makes her work more accessible to her classmates who can go straight to her house after school and still be able to take the metro home if needed. One of Lexy’s past clients–Ocean Van Dam, senior at CSArts–said, “I’m sure anyone would have a good experience with her … she was really happy to accommodate any adjustments I wanted.” Although Ocean had requested a short nail set, Lexy has shown her skill in all kinds of shapes and sizes, “She’s really meticulous with her nail art and skilled as well!” he said.</p>

<p>Many students at CSArts enjoy getting their nails done, and Lexy has expressed a desire for clients to begin coming in with more creative ideas. Her favorite trends at the moment are polka dots and 3D sculpted ladybugs and monkeys. She can do many different styles and likes to work with her clients' preferences. She currently charges $35-$50, depending on size and design, and is always looking for new clients. Lexy can be reached on Instagram <a href="https://instagram.com/lexxdonailss">@lexxdonailss</a> to book an appointment!</p>]]></content><author><name>Miranda Cervantes</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Calling all glam lovers! If you’re looking for a fresh new set of nails, look out for Lexy Nichols, a beginner nail tech and senior here at CSArts. Lexy began her nail journey her freshman year of high school, “I started doing it because it helped me cope in a way,” she said. After spending time practicing nails on her friends who appreciated her talents, she discovered her passion for the art form. Lexy has plenty of experience in the fine arts as a visual art student, and being able to apply her artistic skills in her nail business comes in handy!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/student-spotlight-lexys-nailsets.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/student-spotlight-lexys-nailsets.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Housewife to Director: Women in Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/women-in-media-and-film-csartisan-article/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Housewife to Director: Women in Media" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/women-in-media-and-film-csartisan-article</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/women-in-media-and-film-csartisan-article/"><![CDATA[<p>The early days of television had women playing housewives, mothers, and nurturing roles, but over the years, the involvement of women’s roles in media has taken a commanding shift. Women today are stepping into leading roles in front and behind the camera. These changes in the film and television industry positively increase the accurate portrayals of women in media.</p>

<p>In a CSArtisan exclusive interview with the Senior Vice President of Physical Production for Funny or Die, Whitney Hadock said, “Now you can find women that are messy, smart, powerful, the list goes on. More and more often, we're also seeing portrayals of women with more than one body type and from more diverse backgrounds.”</p>

<p>A few of the main outcomes this vital shift had on the media industry are business choices, demographics, and leadership. “Women in positions of power within the media enable stories about women by women to get told and get told with the nuance that a human story requires,” said Hodack. “Sometimes it takes someone of the same community to show the business that investing in female-centered stories is a good business choice because it opens up a whole demographic that is willing to lean in and watch your programming and has been left out due to portrayals of very flat female characters in the past.”</p>

<p>People tend to underestimate the power of film and how it shapes the way people view the world around them. “When we are able to show women in positions of power, solving hard problems, not being perfect, and all the things that are not always thought of as female jobs or qualities, we are showing the world the possibilities of what women are capable of,” said Hodack. And she says it affects the people watching. “When girls and women watch this content, they start to understand that they can do and be these things as well.” By featuring women from all backgrounds in film and television, filmmakers help to break the mold of how people think women are supposed to behave.</p>

<p>The effects media portrayals have on a young person’s understanding of gender roles, body image, or career aspirations are formed through the media they watched while growing up. Showing women in a subservient, perfect, happy role leaves unrealistic expectations on women and children. “Showing women portraying doctors and writers and athletes and anything your heart can think of gives examples of all the ways girls and women can see themselves becoming anything they want,” Hodack said.</p>

<p>This year, one-third of Emmy winners were women, and this ratio has become more favorable towards women over the years. The representation of women in the media industry doesn’t just fall under the acting category. “We need more female editors, DPs, and directors, roles that are traditionally thought of as male-dominated. When there are more women represented in each category, the odds of a woman winning increase, too,” Hodack said. “When I won my Emmy, there were ten producers on that project, and only two of us were women.”</p>

<p>Women in the media are breaking down the doors for the next generation. Women aren’t just motherly figures on screen; they are directors, screenwriters, cinematographers, and problem solvers.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The early days of television had women playing housewives, mothers, and nurturing roles, but over the years, the involvement of women’s roles in media has taken a commanding shift. Women today are stepping into leading roles in front and behind the camera. These changes in the film and television industry positively increase the accurate portrayals of women in media.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/housewife-to-director-women-in-media.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/housewife-to-director-women-in-media.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Research Trip to Citrus College</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research-trip-to-citrus-college/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research Trip to Citrus College" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research-trip-to-citrus-college</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research-trip-to-citrus-college/"><![CDATA[<p>How do you make a dual enrollment CSArts student feel like a Citrus College student?</p>

<p>Step onto a college campus. On September 12th, 55 students in Mr. William’s CCC English class spent a Friday at Citrus College to get help with their TED Talk research projects and explore resources.</p>

<p>In the past, CCC English blocks have talked with librarians through virtual Zoom meetings. This is the first time they went in person.</p>

<p>“I figured that by introducing students to the campus, actually exploring the resources, and meeting the people on campus, they’d feel more like citrus owls,” said Mr. Williams.</p>

<p>Students began their day at Citrus in the Hayden Memorial Library. Librarian Elizabeth Cook helped students access online databases for their project</p>

<p>They also toured the Learning Center, which has a testing room for students with accommodations, and a writing center where students can receive tutoring for papers or speeches.</p>

<p>“Any student at CSArts who is in a Citrus College dual enrollment class can access the writing center,” Williams said.</p>

<p>Students can also join Zoom sessions or send a quick email to the writing center.</p>

<p>Mr. Williams plans to repeat the field trip in the spring semester. Last week, Ms. Cook also visited his classes at CSArts last week to bring banned books for another research project and share additional resources.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you make a dual enrollment CSArts student feel like a Citrus College student?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Matcha: Cultural Drink or Social Media Prop?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/matcha-cultural-drink-or-social-media-prop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Matcha: Cultural Drink or Social Media Prop?" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/matcha-cultural-drink-or-social-media-prop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/matcha-cultural-drink-or-social-media-prop/"><![CDATA[<p>A recent online trend has created the label of “performative matcha lover” – a term used to define people, most often male, who use matcha as a way to appear more sensitive and feminist to appeal to women. This viewpoint, however, more often than not, does not truly explore the significance behind matcha itself.</p>

<p>The president of the Co Cha Cup Club at CSArts, Ayleen Park, says that while being a performative matcha lover is usually used negatively, they also “might start by enjoying matcha for its popularity but then gain a deeper appreciation for its culture and significance.”</p>

<p>While cultural foods in general becoming popular could cause commercialization that ignores its cultural origins (ie. matcha being from Japan/China), Park also believes it could be exciting in the way that it might introduce people to new flavors or traditions they might not have tried otherwise.</p>

<p>The Co Cha Cup Club is a place for people with similar interests to come together. While not explicitly a culture club, Park does say that the club “does touch on cultural aspects, since coffee, tea, and matcha all have deep historical roots”. The club is made to explore not only the drinks’ histories, but also to build communities, show support for local cafés, and to provide a welcoming environment for all students.</p>

<p>Matcha is not just a trend– it’s a cultural food. Dating back almost a thousand years to Tang dynasty China, it was later passed onto Japan, where it was truly popularized and continues to be produced today. According to <a href="https://tenzotea.co/blogs/matcha-handbook/where-did-matcha-come-from#:~:text=How%20is%20Matcha%20powder%20prepared,theanine%20is%20responsible%20for%20it">tenzotea.co</a>, matcha is so culturally significant to Japan that they carry out a tea ceremony known as Chado, also known as the way of the tea, just to honor it. While the idea of the “performative matcha lover” has only become quite popular in the past few months, matcha has been around since between the 7th and 10th centuries.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="student-life" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent online trend has created the label of “performative matcha lover” – a term used to define people, most often male, who use matcha as a way to appear more sensitive and feminist to appeal to women. This viewpoint, however, more often than not, does not truly explore the significance behind matcha itself.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/matcha-cultural-drink-or-social-media-prop.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/matcha-cultural-drink-or-social-media-prop.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Homecoming Financial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homecoming-financial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homecoming Financial" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homecoming-financial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homecoming-financial/"><![CDATA[<p>Homecoming is a time of year to celebrate, and it can seem magical, but how much does it cost? It turns out that setting up homecoming can cost tens of thousands of dollars, depending on the venue. This year specifically, CSArts is spending somewhere between $20,000 and $30,000 for the venue, food, entertainment, and other costs.</p>

<p>Because the goal with most school dances is to break even, ticket costs need to be high. This year, they cost 80 dollars, or half as much if you qualify for the free and reduced lunch program.</p>

<p>So what does it all add up to? “Over the course of the past few years, it has fluctuated a lot, so it’s hard to get exact numbers, but usually we make about 10,000 dollars,” said head of leadership Mrs. Cardenas. So remember that the cost of your ticket goes to making Homecoming just a little more magical.</p>

<p>How much does homecoming cost?</p>

<p>It really depends on the venue. Food, beverage, and venue costs.</p>

<p>Rough estimate this year: 20,000-30,000 for food, entertainment, etc.</p>

<p>How does this affect choosing a location?</p>

<p>How much are the tickets, and what does that make?</p>

<p>40$ or 80$ It really depends on the dance and on ticket sales. Our goal is always to break even. Over the course of the past few years, it’s fluctuated a lot, so it’s hard to get exact numbers. Income is usually around 10,000</p>]]></content><author><name>Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Homecoming is a time of year to celebrate, and it can seem magical, but how much does it cost? It turns out that setting up homecoming can cost tens of thousands of dollars, depending on the venue. This year specifically, CSArts is spending somewhere between $20,000 and $30,000 for the venue, food, entertainment, and other costs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/homecoming-financial.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/homecoming-financial.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Adolescence in the Digital Age</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adolescence-in-the-digital-age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adolescence in the Digital Age" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adolescence-in-the-digital-age</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adolescence-in-the-digital-age/"><![CDATA[<p>Social media promises connection, but it also hides the side effects of infinite doomscrolling. The dark side of digital life has revealed itself in the Emmy-winning Netflix series “Adolescence.” CSArts-SGV school psychologists say that the realities and accuracy aren’t far off.</p>

<p><em>Adolescence</em> is a Netflix limited series about the aftermath of a 14-year-old, Jamie Miller, killing a girl from his school, Katie. The show follows Jamie’s interrogation, family problems, and police investigation. The police investigation took a turn into the dark hole of social media, group chats, secret messages, and online bullying. And you may be asking, “How does the show connect to my life or the life of my friends and classmates?” (And if you’re not, bear with me). Although <em>Adolescence</em> can be seen as dramatized, it also accurately portrays the darker side of social media, which many teens and students of CSArts can relate to.</p>

<p>First, is <em>Adolescence</em> accurate? According to Dr. Maureen Davis, lead school psychologist: yes, it is correct. “I think it does a good job highlighting how pervasive it can be, but also how serious it can be…there’s a wide variety of ways people can be bullied via social media,” Davis said. She added that the show was accurate in the ways that social media can expose individuals to online radicalization (which is when someone spends a lot of time online and gets exposed to extreme ideas, which slowly change their beliefs and support harmful or dangerous views). It is also accurate in the way that parents can sometimes be oblivious to what their kids are going through.</p>

<p>The show’s accuracy also comes with teens and violence because of bullying. So, how does social media affect teens? “I think one of the main ways that social media affects mental health is that it increases anxiety and it lowers self-esteem…people don't put their worst days out on their Instagram page to show the world,” Davis said. Influencers only show the good things: the perfect shot, the perfect moment, the perfect look, the perfect plans. That idea of perfection is the catalyst for low self-esteem, anxiety, and depression. That comparison between the artificial life on an artificial screen and the reality someone is currently living in. There can also be something called FOMO, which stands for “Fear of Missing Out.” When someone sees their friends post pictures on social media and they are not included, it can make their anxiety worse. Davis described it as, “When you’re anxious long enough, you can become depressed…they’re best friends, anxiety and depression.”</p>

<p>Nevertheless, social media has its upsides: the connection you can have with your family and friends. Your family can be miles away, and the only way to communicate with them is through social media. And it’s easy to overlook the negative sides of social media because of the positive things.</p>

<p>But there are some habits we can pick up to have a healthy relationship with our phones. First, it is recommended that 16 years of age is the appropriate age to get social media. When exposed to blue light, take breaks every 20 or so minutes to look at something far away or across the room to maintain good eyesight.</p>

<p>When social media gets too overwhelming, take a break. It’s normal and healthy to withdraw from it. It doesn’t have to be for long, too. It can be for a day or an hour, or multiple days. Pacing yourself is important for your health, both physical and mental.</p>

<p>Have your phone turned off and stay off your phone for about an hour before going to bed for your brain to wind down. The Cleveland Clinic states, “Your mind can stay active and engaged long after you’ve scrolled through social media or responded to a few work emails.” They also state that the blue light from our screens affects our sleep, too, primarily our circadian rhythm. Our circadian rhythm works based on light and dark. So, we naturally feel more tired at night than in the morning. But the screens mimic daylight due to their artificial color, making us more alert. This leads to poor sleep quality, insomnia, and difficulties in falling asleep.</p>

<p>It is also important that your goals are attainable. They can be something small, like stop using your phone half an hour before bedtime, or take a one-hour break from your phone. By learning to use social media with intention, this generation might finally reclaim what it means to connect.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mariam Ghazaryan</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social media promises connection, but it also hides the side effects of infinite doomscrolling. The dark side of digital life has revealed itself in the Emmy-winning Netflix series “Adolescence.” CSArts-SGV school psychologists say that the realities and accuracy aren’t far off.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>