<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-01T14:48:05-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Student ran and written, rebranded.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">IA Romeo &amp;amp; Juliet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ia-romeo-and-juliet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IA Romeo &amp;amp; Juliet" /><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ia-romeo-and-juliet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ia-romeo-and-juliet/"><![CDATA[<p>Get ready to rock out with a rebellious twist on a timeless classic - Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet. This punk-rock adaptation is sure to leave audiences moshing in the aisles and reimagining the tragic love story in a whole new way.</p>

<h2 id="youre-reading-too-far">You’re reading too far!</h2>

<p>This post is simply filler, an excuse to use these photos until a real article is written.</p>]]></content><author><name>Octavia Roberts</name></author><category term="productions" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get ready to rock out with a rebellious twist on a timeless classic - Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet. This punk-rock adaptation is sure to leave audiences moshing in the aisles and reimagining the tragic love story in a whole new way.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/romeo-and-juliet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/romeo-and-juliet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts’ Enchanted Evening</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/CSArts-Enchanted-Evening/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts’ Enchanted Evening" /><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/CSArts-Enchanted-Evening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/CSArts-Enchanted-Evening/"><![CDATA[<p>As we settle into the second semester of the school year, it’s time to celebrate! On February 4th, CSArts students gathered together to dance with their friends at Winter Formal, held at the Springfield Banquet Hall. The theme of the night was Enchanted Evening, and many dressed in their finest dresses and suits, some with florals, lace, and greens and purples to match the theme.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“For this year’s winter formal theme, we wanted to go for a fantasy vibe, something that was really different from homecoming, Neon Nights. The venue had a whimsical feel and the potential to portray a fairytale scene.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Jolene Young said, one of the members of the CSArts Leadership dance committee. During the dance, the venue was decorated with a variety of fairy lights, flowers and vines, helping to create a truly ethereal atmosphere to the event. However, despite the beautiful decorations, some were apprehensive of attending the event at first.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“I was kind of worried about distance and finding people to spend time with, but that ended up not being a problem at all. I’m glad I went!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Rosie Williams (VA ‘23)</p>

<p>When asked about the process of choosing a venue, the dance committee said, “all venues are chosen prior to the school year by the leadership advisor. For these venues, the advisor looks at the venue capacity and having various spaces to accommodate all students. We also take into account the location, finding a place in the middle ground.”</p>

<p>No matter the distance or theme, all that were at Winter Formal can confirm that it was truly an enchanted evening to remember.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Brunet</name></author><category term="events" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we settle into the second semester of the school year, it’s time to celebrate! On February 4th, CSArts students gathered together to dance with their friends at Winter Formal, held at the Springfield Banquet Hall. The theme of the night was Enchanted Evening, and many dressed in their finest dresses and suits, some with florals, lace, and greens and purples to match the theme.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/10.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/10.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The History of Valentines Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-history-of-valentines-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The History of Valentines Day" /><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-history-of-valentines-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-history-of-valentines-day/"><![CDATA[<p>Between the kisses and candy hearts, Valentine’s Day is a celebration of the patron saint of beekeepers, epilepsy, and of course, lovers. Valentine’s Day is a commemoration of the bravery of a man who dedicated his life to nurturing and strengthening the love two people have for one another.</p>

<p>The origin of Valentine’s Day began in Rome during the reign of Emperor Claudius the Cruel. Under the Emperor’s iron fist, Rome necessitated a powerful army. However, young soldiers were more focused on dedicating themselves to their families, leaving Emperor Claudius’s military severely lacking. To combat the problem, Claudius decided to ban all marriages and engagements in Rome, catching the attention of a Roman priest by the name of Valentine.</p>

<p>Valentine determined that forbidding rituals of love was a devious act, and retaliated against the Emperor in secret. The priest bravely continued to marry young lovers in spite of the Empire’s decrees until he was caught in 270 CE. When Valentine was discovered, he was beaten and beheaded on February 14, becoming a martyr and saint within the Christian church. Valentine’s martyrdom is a symbol of persisting and uplifting love in the face of all odds, and if not for his bravery and values, the candy hearts and chocolate roses would be a slice of imagination.</p>

<p>Valentine’s Day is not only a couples holiday, but rather a celebration of all love—whether romantic, platonic, familial, or even artistic. The Day of Love is a reminder to us all to uplift ourselves and each other, in spite of any obstacles that may stand in our way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sevana Zadoian</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between the kisses and candy hearts, Valentine’s Day is a celebration of the patron saint of beekeepers, epilepsy, and of course, lovers. Valentine’s Day is a commemoration of the bravery of a man who dedicated his life to nurturing and strengthening the love two people have for one another.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/the-history-of-valentines-day.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/the-history-of-valentines-day.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Seasonal Affective Disorder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SAD/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seasonal Affective Disorder" /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SAD</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SAD/"><![CDATA[<p>Seasonal Affective Disorder, otherwise known as SAD or seasonal depression is a relatively common effect of shorter days with sunlight and colder weather. It can affect anyone, but, statistically, it is more common for those in their 20’s and 30’s. The combination of weather changes, less sunshine, and the onslaught of homework can affect students, even here in “sunny” California.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I just end up feeling really depressed and I find it really difficult to get any work done. Then I end up feeling guilty, because I am not being productive,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said an anonymous CSArts student.</p>

<p>This is not an uncommon occurrence of SAD and the slew of work students have during this time of year.</p>

<p>Although SAD is common, there are ways to help those who are affected by it. Doctors encourage those with seasonal depression to make sure they are getting exercise, outside, if the sun is shining. Sun provides us with Vitamin D as well. In the winter, it may be difficult to get enough vitamin D, so doctors suggest vitamin supplements. Wide spectrum lights simulate sunlight by using special light bulbs and can also make quite a difference. They can be found on Amazon. Most importantly, If you or anyone you know is struggling with SAD, you are not alone.</p>

<p>Here are a few resources to help!</p>

<ul>
  <li>Reach out to your teachers and counselors!</li>
  <li><a href="https://988lifeline.org">Suicide Hotline Number</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.crisistextline.org/">Crisis Text Line</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Luna Martinez-Granilo</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seasonal Affective Disorder, otherwise known as SAD or seasonal depression is a relatively common effect of shorter days with sunlight and colder weather. It can affect anyone, but, statistically, it is more common for those in their 20’s and 30’s. The combination of weather changes, less sunshine, and the onslaught of homework can affect students, even here in “sunny” California.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crazy Christmas Movie Conundrum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crazy-christmas-movie-conundrum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crazy Christmas Movie Conundrum" /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crazy-christmas-movie-conundrum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crazy-christmas-movie-conundrum/"><![CDATA[<p>Now that December has rolled around the holiday season is in full swing. Which means people are busting out the decade old Christmas DVDs and settling down on their couch to watch iconic Christmas movies such as “Home Alone” or “A Christmas Story”. But then there are the more contraversial choices. Movies that walk a thin line between actual Christmas movies or movies that were just released during the holiday season. These movies spark the age old debate of what qualifies as a Christmas movie?</p>

<p>Every month, student journalists at the CSArtisan get together and have a news meeting. We go over the news of the month, upcoming holidays, etc. all to figure out what’s gonna be our next headlining stories for the next issue. When I brought up this story I got some quizzical looks about what this article would be about. But when I brought up Die Hard as an example of a “Christmas Movie”… The whole room erupted into argument!</p>

<p>“It’s not a Christmas movie!” exclaimed our journalist M.J., “It just happens to take place on Christmas Day the plot doesn’t revolve around Christmas!” Though the beginning of the movie centers around Bruce Willis going to L.A. for his kid’s Christmas and getting roped up in his ex-wife’s office Christmas party, once the terrorist plot starts up you completely forget the Christmas parts of the movie.</p>

<p>Sidney, our graphic designer, had a different opinion, “It’s a Christmas movie because the idea surrounding it is that it’s set during Christmas so it should be regarded as a Christmas movie,”</p>

<p>And, as said previously, the plot does get kicked into motion by the terrorists hijacking the office Christmas party. Also, a lot of the trailers and promos about Die Hard really double down on the fact Die Hard is a Christmas movie I left the meeting feeling optimistic about this article. If even a throwaway mention of Die Hard sparked so much debate, I wondered what students thought of other infamous not-so-Christmas movies. So I set up a google form, to gauge what people classified as a Christmas movie. What I was expecting when sending out the Google form was maybe some lukewarm takes about Die Hard or the Nightmare Before Christmas. What I didn’t expect was people saying HOME ALONE (technically) ISN’T A CHRISTMAS MOVIE.</p>

<p>“There’s a difference between a story set in Christmas and a Christmas story,” says Alex the Christmas heretic,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sure, movies like Home Alone take place during Christmas, and are the reason for events to happen, they are not part of the real story. Christmas stories are about Christmas itself, and the values we associate with the holidays like family connection, thoughtfulness and giving. Therefore, movies set during Christmas but with no message or story connecting to Christmas values doesn’t fall under ‘A Christmas Story’ movie.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Despite how controversal Alex’s opinion is, I can see his point. Once the kid is left behind in house the Christmas aspect of the movie takes a backseat outside of Kevin’s clever traps using Christmas items. But even with the Christmas themed trappings he was just using what he could find around the house! I’d say the one thing against Alex’s argument is that the plot is set in motion by the family Christmas trip to France. If the family wasn’t going to France they probably would’ve waited out the power outage and had a regular Christmas at home.</p>

<p>The other thing I realized is how much this Home Alone argument echoed arguments about Die Hard. Both movies are centered around Christmas at the very beginning and the very end but the middle of the movie has next to nothing to do with Christmas! This is why I wanted to center an article around this topic. It so interesting to see people go into spirited fights over Christmas movies like they bet their life on this movie. It’s also fun to fight over things they don’t really matter! Especially with the world we live in nowadays.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rio A. Lee</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that December has rolled around the holiday season is in full swing. Which means people are busting out the decade old Christmas DVDs and settling down on their couch to watch iconic Christmas movies such as “Home Alone” or “A Christmas Story”. But then there are the more contraversial choices. Movies that walk a thin line between actual Christmas movies or movies that were just released during the holiday season. These movies spark the age old debate of what qualifies as a Christmas movie?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interviewing The Endelman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/interviewing-the-endelman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interviewing The Endelman" /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/interviewing-the-endelman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/interviewing-the-endelman/"><![CDATA[<p>Have you always wanted to know more about Dr. Endelman? Well
now you can! Members of CSArtisan recently interviewed the
campus’s most esteemed staff member in order to bring you the
inside scoop.</p>

<h3 id="endelman-secretly-in-the-pnd-conservatory">Endelman Secretly in The PnD Conservatory?</h3>

<p>Look out for Dr. Endelman hiding in the shadows at your next CSArts performance! When asked which conservatory he would be in, Endelman says he’s always been a PnD kid at heart. As a self appointed power-tool lover, he wishes he could learn more about set building, stage lighting, and sound systems. (Any PnD students want to take him up on the offer?)</p>

<h3 id="dr-endelman-before-the-fame">Dr. Endelman Before The Fame</h3>

<p>Before his rise to fame as the CSArts principal, Endelman was just like the rest of us. He took bowling as a class in his high school and, after graduation, secured a job at his local Burger King, where he was voted, “Employee of the Month.”</p>

<h3 id="what-does-endelman-do-off-the-clock">What Does Endelman Do Off The Clock?</h3>

<p>Despite working at an arts school, Dr. Endelman described one of his favorite hobbies as sports! He admires all aspects of the activity– playing, coaching, and watching. As a nature-lover, he loves being outdoors and can be found camping and hiking on the weekends.</p>

<h3 id="dr-endelman-no-uvula">Dr. Endelman No Uvula??</h3>

<p>Perhaps the most shocking portion of this whole interview, it was learned that Dr. Endelman has no uvula. As to why and how, we did not have the time in the interview to discuss. But, next time you pass him in the hall, feel free to press him a bit about this fun fact. And of course, be sure to have him say “ahhh” so you can confirm this for yourself.</p>

<h3 id="what-makes-the-endelman-wheels-turn">What Makes The Endelman Wheels Turn?</h3>

<p>On a more serious note, we also talked about Dr. Endelman’s identity and what inspires his everyday life. Based on a recently-taken “strength-based” assignment, Dr. Endelman describes himself as a coach, analyst, self-believer, catalyst, and Philomath (a lover of learning). He gets his inspiration from his students (woohoo!), family, mentors, music, learning, leadership, and coaching.</p>

<h3 id="most-importantly-is-dr-endelman-a-back-side-or-stomach-sleeper">Most Importantly, Is Dr. Endelman A Back, Side, or Stomach Sleeper?</h3>

<p>To this question he answered with a simple sentence– no fluff, no nonsense– and I quote, “I start on my back and end up on my side.” Do with that information what you will, CSArts.</p>

<p>In all seriousness, thank you Dr. Endelman for your participation in this interview. And thank you, reader, for taking the time to learn a little bit more about your principal.</p>]]></content><author><name>Eliza Kim</name></author><category term="comedy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you always wanted to know more about Dr. Endelman? Well now you can! Members of CSArtisan recently interviewed the campus’s most esteemed staff member in order to bring you the inside scoop.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/9.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/9.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Art Therapy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art-therapy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Art Therapy" /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art-therapy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art-therapy/"><![CDATA[<p>When imagining a professional conference, one usually pictures executives talking jargon in their crisp power suits of navy-blue and perfectly polished shoes, examining graphs and statistics of some really important things. But at this conference, there are no stoic business associates discussing forecasts and analyses. Instead, I see eclectic fashion, colorful glasses, big tote bags, and warm smiles.This, is the American Art Therapy Association’s (AATA) annual conference. But what is art therapy? According to AATA, “Art therapy is an integrative mental health and human services profession that enriches the lives of individuals, families, and communities through active artmaking, creative process, applied psychological theory, and human experience within a psychotherapeutic relationship.” That’s a lot, but it essentially means that art can heal everyone. Mid-November, I had the opportunity of attending AATA’s 53rd annual conference in Minneapolis. As a student who attends an art high school, exploring different art careers alongside my peers can be challenging. I interviewed various successful art therapists at the conference asking what their journey was like to gain inspiration for not only myself, but for other interested creative minds.</p>

<p>So, what are some of the paths towards art therapy? Professor Maria Riccardi who teaches at Concordia University in Canada said she was a curious and good student in high school.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I was Italian so I had a strict family, so I always had to have better grades and there was a lot of pressure… But yes I was art focused. I used to draw in everything I had, I took the art classes, and I started to really like it a lot.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Professor Joyce Yip Green, an assistant professor at Loyola Marymount University’s Department of Marital and Family Therapy/Art Therapy also shared what her high school experience was like. “I was a nerd, a straight-A student. But I was also really involved in different clubs on campus like Key Club and Yearbook Staff. I was an art focused person so that’s why I joined Yearbook Staff and the year I was the editor, our yearbook was nominated for best design.” However, despite being passionate about the arts, Professor Green had no idea about the world of art therapy until she was in college, “One of my mentors told me that there was a master’s degree in art therapy…They encouraged me to go to grad school to study art therapy because I was a psychology and studio art major.”</p>

<p>Like Professor Green, Professor Lisa D. Hinz, director of the art therapy doctorate program at Dominican University of California, didn’t discover art therapy in high school either. “In high school, I was an overachiever. I worked hard and I got straight A’s. I discovered art therapy when I became a psychologist. I had a PhD in clinical psychology and my first job was at the counseling center.” At the center, Professor Hinz gave college counseling and one day, volunteered to supervise an art therapy student. When observing the art therapy sessions, she was in awe of the process.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Everything I saw was so powerful. Because there’s a visual record, it doesn’t always have to involve so many words, and it was just - profound,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Professor Hinz.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Amanda Power who specializes in children and adolescents, tells a different story of her high school years. “I was kind of flying under the radar a little bit, school didn’t come super easy to me, but I worked pretty hard. I had some good teachers who helped guide me along the way and that was super helpful. Definitely not straight-A’s by any means but I managed to do okay,” Ms. Power said.</p>

<p>However, like the rest, she had never heard of art therapy until her later years in life. “I was really confused about what I wanted to do after graduating high school and I ended up starting university… but I followed my passion to go back to art school. When I was there, I had an amazing art history teacher who talked about art therapy…I thought it was such a cool idea because I always wanted to work in the arts and with people…I was always trying to do some other thing and it always led me back to art therapy!”</p>

<p>Finally, out of everyone I interviewed, Megan VanMeter who uses art therapy for burnout treatment was the only individual who discovered art therapy in high school,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I was a very good student. I was motivated, took my grades seriously, and knew I was heading to college. People were telling me all my life to be an artist so I didn’t want to be one. But when I was 13 I realized that I’m going to have to choose something so I guess I’ll do art. But I wasn’t convinced. When I was 15, I took the PSAT and checked the box saying I was interested in art careers and I got emails from college programs mentioning art therapy. And it just clicked in my head!…How wonderful to help people discover themselves through themselves.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>All of these people discovered art therapy in a serendipitous way. Through that one happen-chance, they all lept at the opportunity to help others heal through art. As Professor Hinz said, “I think it shows that it’s really powerful if you are a person who values art.” With this knowledge, as students of CSArts, we can bring kindness and love to others through art.</p>]]></content><author><name>MJ Cho</name></author><category term="essays" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When imagining a professional conference, one usually pictures executives talking jargon in their crisp power suits of navy-blue and perfectly polished shoes, examining graphs and statistics of some really important things. But at this conference, there are no stoic business associates discussing forecasts and analyses. Instead, I see eclectic fashion, colorful glasses, big tote bags, and warm smiles.This, is the American Art Therapy Association’s (AATA) annual conference. But what is art therapy? According to AATA, “Art therapy is an integrative mental health and human services profession that enriches the lives of individuals, families, and communities through active artmaking, creative process, applied psychological theory, and human experience within a psychotherapeutic relationship.” That’s a lot, but it essentially means that art can heal everyone. Mid-November, I had the opportunity of attending AATA’s 53rd annual conference in Minneapolis. As a student who attends an art high school, exploring different art careers alongside my peers can be challenging. I interviewed various successful art therapists at the conference asking what their journey was like to gain inspiration for not only myself, but for other interested creative minds.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/art-therapy.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/art-therapy.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Drowsy Chaperone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-drowsy-chaperone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Drowsy Chaperone" /><published>2022-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-drowsy-chaperone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-drowsy-chaperone/"><![CDATA[<p>Wedding bells rang, wedding bells chimed. In case you missed it, the Musical Theater Conservatory put on an early fall production of The Drowsy Chaperone. The show opened with a charming old man playing a record that ushered in a heartfelt comedy, titled The Drowsy Chaperone, about a beautiful actress quitting the glitz and glamour of show business to marry the man of her dreams. Behind the red curtain and bright lights, the relationships between the actors and their characters set the stage for a successful run. Many of the actors took it upon themselves to research their characters thoroughly in their own ways. Sawyer Valin (MT ‘23), who played The Man in the Chair, even contacted the actor who played his role in the original production of the show, Bob Martin, to flesh out his character as much as possible. Jolie Wang (MT ‘23), who played Mrs. Tottendale, the bubbly socialite with an enthusiasm for weddings, watched different videos of her Drowsy character.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I built my version of Mrs. Tottendale out of [the videos]. I sort of pieced together bits of all the Mrs. Tottendales I watched,” 
said Wang.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Though the show’s run at CSArts has come to an end, the cast of The Drowsy Chaperone will remember the family they formed and the lessons they learned through rehearsing, performing, and embracing the show.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You have so much more freedom and possibility as an actor when you are diligent with your character breakdown work, supportive of every member of your cast, production team, and crew, and consistently eager to learn about the show itself and the exciting process of putting on a show,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tara Moran (MT ‘23), who played Janet van de Graff, said.</p>

<p>Students learned to dedicate themselves to their roles thoroughly and make the most of their rehearsal time to produce a masterful performance for everyone to enjoy. The Drowsy Chaperone was the semester’s first performance, kicking off the new school year with comedy, music, and a reminder of what CSArts truly values: celebrating and honoring art as a community.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sevana Zadoian</name></author><category term="productions" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wedding bells rang, wedding bells chimed. In case you missed it, the Musical Theater Conservatory put on an early fall production of The Drowsy Chaperone. The show opened with a charming old man playing a record that ushered in a heartfelt comedy, titled The Drowsy Chaperone, about a beautiful actress quitting the glitz and glamour of show business to marry the man of her dreams. Behind the red curtain and bright lights, the relationships between the actors and their characters set the stage for a successful run. Many of the actors took it upon themselves to research their characters thoroughly in their own ways. Sawyer Valin (MT ‘23), who played The Man in the Chair, even contacted the actor who played his role in the original production of the show, Bob Martin, to flesh out his character as much as possible. Jolie Wang (MT ‘23), who played Mrs. Tottendale, the bubbly socialite with an enthusiasm for weddings, watched different videos of her Drowsy character.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/the-drowsy-chaperone.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/the-drowsy-chaperone.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Masters in Makeup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/masters-in-makeup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Masters in Makeup" /><published>2022-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/masters-in-makeup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/masters-in-makeup/"><![CDATA[<p>Makeup is an artform that allows us to express ourselves via colors and patterns, textures and techniques. At CSArts makeup is exactly that, an art form. However, with the rise of assignments and homework, it has grown to be an afterthought, something that is much more optional. With that being said, it is still a prominent part of students’ lives.</p>

<p>Makeup, is also an outlet and an expression that crosses differen subcultures and factions becoming an ionic and recognizable feature. Sophomore Levvy Butler says makeup started out as a way for them to fit in. They say they lacked the technique and skill, but are getting more comfortable experimenting with different eyeliner shapes and colors.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So now, I wear makeup because I like the way it looks, and not because I want to look older or fit in or anything.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Junior, Violet Zeug, says she wears makeup for a different reason. Makeup is less of a routine and more something she uses to improve how she feels. “I guess it’s some kind of insecurity, as far as feeling the need to be prettier/looking nicer/put together.” For her, makeup is a tool, to improve her day and to make her feel prettier. Not only that, but it also goes with what she plans to wear. For example, when she wears her leather jacket, she’ll wear thick eyeliner, but for a more laid back look, she uses thinner and much more breezy eyeliner.</p>

<p>An anonymous student said that for her, makeup is both therapeutic and creative. “It allows me to vent, and paint my emotions on my face, whether that means large pigmented red and black eyeliner, or soft green, and blue eyeshadow. ”Makeup is a creative outlet for her, one that has taken a lot of practice. “I find that there is no other form that allows me to be as creative and free as makeup does.”</p>

<p>Each student uses makeup with different goals in mind. For some it is artistry. For others, it is to fit in, or put on a protective mask. If you are interested in learning more about the world of makeup check out these artists! Nikkietutorials, MikaylaJMakeup, pippabarnes, sugarr.x.spice. All of these artists can be found on both Instagram and Tik-tok.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Brunet</name></author><category term="misc" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Makeup is an artform that allows us to express ourselves via colors and patterns, textures and techniques. At CSArts makeup is exactly that, an art form. However, with the rise of assignments and homework, it has grown to be an afterthought, something that is much more optional. With that being said, it is still a prominent part of students’ lives.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Glitz &amp;amp; Glamour — Old Hollywood &amp;amp; Winter Formal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/glitz-and-glamour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glitz &amp;amp; Glamour — Old Hollywood &amp;amp; Winter Formal" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/glitz-and-glamour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/glitz-and-glamour/"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, January 21st, the CSArts Leadership revealed the theme for the long-anticipated Winter Formal. Winter Formal was held on February 5th, and tickets were already sold out days later as students excitedly prepared for the event.</p>

<p>The theme for this year’s formal was Old Hollywood. Old Hollywood, also known as Classic Hollywood, is a term used to describe the fashion, film, and overall glamour associated with American cinema from the 1930s to the late 1950s.</p>

<p>Famous stars from this era would be actresses such as Audrey Hepburn, Marilyn Monroe, and Judy Garland, as well as actors like Henry Fonda and Marlon Brando. Old Hollywood is legendary, setting trends for both fashion and film.</p>

<p>The style of Old Hollywood is full of glitz and glam with an air of both sophistication and class. The women of Old Hollywood would don bright red lipstick and pearly white jewelry, complete with full-length gowns to shine and sparkle.</p>

<p>As for the male fashion, sharp fitted suits and tuxedos paired with fedoras and ties were the go-tos for male stars. Their hair would also be stylized to be prim and proper, and most important, quite dapper all together.</p>

<p>This year’s Winter Formal isn’t the first instance of taking inspiration from the past either. Earlier this year in October, CSArts had Homecoming, which was themed around the famous music festival Woodstock during the 1960s.</p>

<p>The style of Woodstock is a definite contrast to Old Hollywood, involving far less glamour and looser, casual clothing. However, each of the styles have their unique charms to them and are overall staples of American fashion as a whole.</p>

<p>It’s safe to say that many at CSArts were ready to party with their friends at Winter Formal, regardless of how red-carpet ready they dressed. After all, Hollywood still remains a beacon of the arts, no matter how much its style evolves and changes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Brunet</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Friday, January 21st, the CSArts Leadership revealed the theme for the long-anticipated Winter Formal. Winter Formal was held on February 5th, and tickets were already sold out days later as students excitedly prepared for the event.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/glitz-and-glamour.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/glitz-and-glamour.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>