<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-15T20:58:57-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">One Last Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/abigail-risdon-goodbye/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Last Time" /><published>2025-05-16T05:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T05:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/abigail-risdon-goodbye</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/abigail-risdon-goodbye/"><![CDATA[<p>Looking back on the past two years, I can confidently say that no club has shaped me, or received more of my time and dedication, than CSArtisan. And while it’s true I’ve spent many long nights trying to puzzle out the seemingly endless amount of things that can go wrong when one is putting together a newspaper publication, being involved in this whole process has truly allowed me to blossom into the writer I am today.</p>

<p>I’ve learned so much from every person who comes through the CSArtisan. I’m especially grateful for those who have helped me along the way. Thank you Mr. Blair, for fostering a love of newspapers in me despite the difficulties that arise with every publication. Thank you Evyn, not just for keeping me sane, but for helping me laugh through it all. And, thank you Minji, who showed me how to lead and be confident with every forward step I take.</p>

<p>One of the most rewarding parts of this process is just being able to read about events on campus and feeling like I get to attend every single one through each article. Over the past years I’ve learned just how important accurate news information is. Whether we’re reporting on a recent movie, a student play, or the effects of school policy on our student population, I’ve witnessed how helpful having access to accurate and unbiased information is. 	I have also, however, witnessed the importance of maintaining access to free and independent information. Around the world, journalism has often been one of the first things to come under fire in times of rising authoritarianism or political instability. Throughout history, we’ve seen how governments can manipulate information to control public perception. Even in modern contexts—from the targeted discrediting of AP News sources to media blackouts in conflict zones—these patterns persist.</p>

<p>That’s why media literacy matters now more than ever. We must stay vigilant, especially in a digital landscape where information is constantly fed to us by algorithms designed to reinforce existing beliefs. Here’s what I’ve learned to keep an eye out for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Check the source: Is it reputable, or does it have a clear political or commercial agenda?</li>
  <li>Look for sensationalism: Headlines designed to provoke emotional reactions often sacrifice accuracy.</li>
  <li>Cross-reference information: See if other reliable outlets are reporting the same facts.</li>
  <li>Beware of false balance: Not every issue has two equal sides—some “debates” are manufactured to create doubt.</li>
  <li>Analyze imagery and language: Are certain groups being portrayed with loaded words or dehumanizing visuals?</li>
  <li>Consider who’s being quoted—and who’s not: Whose voices are being centered or silenced?</li>
</ul>

<p>Propaganda thrives in environments where critical thought is discouraged. So let’s encourage each other to question, to read widely, and to protect the integrity of truthful reporting.</p>

<p>To everyone who’s been part of this journey—whether as an editor, writer, advisor, or reader—thank you. I’ve grown not just as a journalist, but as someone who believes deeply in the importance of truth, transparency, and community. Here’s to the stories we’ve told, the truths we’ve uncovered, and the voices we’ve uplifted. And here’s to continuing that work with courage, care, and curiosity.</p>

<p>Stay safe, stay sharp, and never stop asking questions.</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking back on the past two years, I can confidently say that no club has shaped me, or received more of my time and dedication, than CSArtisan. And while it’s true I’ve spent many long nights trying to puzzle out the seemingly endless amount of things that can go wrong when one is putting together a newspaper publication, being involved in this whole process has truly allowed me to blossom into the writer I am today.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Next Steps for Juniors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/college-tips-for-juniors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next Steps for Juniors" /><published>2025-05-16T05:29:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T05:29:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/college-tips-for-juniors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/college-tips-for-juniors/"><![CDATA[<p>The transition from junior to senior year is one of the most important, and demanding, parts of high school. With a packed schedule during the school year from homework, conservatory classes, and extracurricular activities, many students see the summer as an opportunity to relax. However, according to your CSArts counselors, it is also a great time to prepare for what’s ahead. The CSArtsian has created a list of next steps to help incoming seniors out.</p>

<h3 id="get-ahead-on-college-applications">Get Ahead on College Applications</h3>
<p>The Common App and UC Application open on August 1st. Begin drafting and brainstorming essays and personal insight questions. Juggling senior year coursework with college applications may be difficult, so starting early will reduce your stress in the fall.</p>

<h3 id="pursue-your-interests">Pursue Your Interests</h3>
<p>Explore the subjects and activities you are passionate about and want to pursue in college further. Whether it’s taking community college courses, summer programs, volunteering, or internships, these experiences can provide valuable insight.</p>

<h3 id="college-visits">College Visits</h3>
<p>Visiting different colleges can help you get a better idea of how the environment, student life, and academics are, which is essential when deciding what schools are the right fit for you later on. Many colleges offer campus tours, Q&amp;As, and information sessions.</p>

<h3 id="have-a-money-talk">Have A Money Talk</h3>
<p>Financial discussions with your parents or guardians about college are vital for the college planning process. Understanding the costs of tuition, housing, books, food, and more helps you make informed decisions when choosing where to apply.</p>

<p>“This is the last year to get involved in activities, clubs, and communities that you have not done in the past, so take advantage of what’s available at CSArts,” says Ms. Shiroma, Head Counselor.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The transition from junior to senior year is one of the most important, and demanding, parts of high school. With a packed schedule during the school year from homework, conservatory classes, and extracurricular activities, many students see the summer as an opportunity to relax. However, according to your CSArts counselors, it is also a great time to prepare for what’s ahead. The CSArtsian has created a list of next steps to help incoming seniors out.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/college-tips-for-juniors.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/college-tips-for-juniors.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Showcasing Production and Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crewlympics-25/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Showcasing Production and Design" /><published>2025-05-16T05:28:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T05:28:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crewlympics-25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crewlympics-25/"><![CDATA[<p>The Production and Design conservatory isn’t usually under the spotlight. That’s about to change at this year’s third annual Crew-Lympics on May 22nd.</p>

<p>Crew-Lympics tests P&amp;D skills in Olympic-style games. P&amp;D adopted it from other technical theatre departments. “It was a way that we can have our students showcased front and center onstage,” said director of P&amp;D Adam Roy. “Typically when they’re doing their jobs well, the audience doesn’t notice them at all.”</p>

<p>The games range from fake food prop designing or audio mixing contests to scene change or quick change races. There’s roughly one game or contest for each P&amp;D area of study, which fall under the umbrella of three tracks: Scenery and Props, Costume and Makeup, and Theatre Technologies.</p>

<p>For a bigger picture, CSArtisan talked to three P&amp;D students about their work and experiences in P&amp;D.</p>

<p>“When you do big shows, you always have to expect that you’re going to stay later for at least two weeks, so you always have to clear your schedule around this time,” P&amp;D sophomore Luna Nguyen said.</p>

<p>Luna has been in multiple P&amp;D roles, including deck crew (moving set pieces), props crew (organizing the prop table), and sound board operator (managing sound cues). She was also the assistant stage manager for Into the Woods. “It gets pretty hectic sometimes,” she said. “I tend to run backstage through the crossover a lot just to be able to communicate with the other people who aren’t on headsets.”</p>

<p>Senior Jayden Abogado also worked on Into the Woods, by designing costumes and running the costume shop in room 206. There, she filled out budgeting papers, sewed, and gave tasks to other students in the costume crew.</p>

<p>Sadie Ondich is a rising junior who is also interested in costumes and makeup. This year she worked on the Fall Festival and on the makeup for Arsenic and Old Lace. One day she hopes to be a head of a Costume or Makeup role, like designer, artist, or manager.</p>

<p>P&amp;D is the beating heart of any production whether it be helping set up a black box production at the PAC or carting supplies to off-campus plays and musicals, they are essential to the success of CSArts. Crew-Lympics is a way to celebrate their skills and accomplishments so make sure to purchase a ticket if you can!</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Production and Design conservatory isn’t usually under the spotlight. That’s about to change at this year’s third annual Crew-Lympics on May 22nd.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/crewlympics-25.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/crewlympics-25.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Elective Showcase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/elective-showcase-25/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elective Showcase" /><published>2025-05-16T05:27:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T05:27:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/elective-showcase-25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/elective-showcase-25/"><![CDATA[<p>Elective showcase was a success! It happens every year, where students from all conservatories get to explore the experience of performing on stage. Not only did the students at CSArts love to perform, the crowd loved it too! It was a chance to appreciate that elective classes are great opportunities to learn, and to show what they had been working on all year! Students in non-performing conservatories were able to feel the adrenaline rush of walking on stage–lights flashing, crowds clapping–something they normally wouldn’t do. After the show is completed, students in non-performing conservatories get experience in performing. This showcase gives a chance for students to recognize their growth and achieve an amazing accomplishment after this showcase.</p>

<p>Ms. Winans, a teacher who choreographed the ballet elective classes and helped organize the event says, “Elective classes and teachers really live in their own worlds on campus, so this event gives us the chance as teachers to come together and collaborate with each other.”</p>

<p>Her favorite part of the elective showcase is the dress rehearsal, because the audience gets really lively and supportive, encouraging their friends for the real performance.</p>

<p>Ballet wasn’t the only class that was shown! There was a variety of hip hop, Taekwondo, stage combat, tap, musical choir, and musical theater!</p>

<p>Ms. Winans says, “Elective showcase is such a special event. I also love being able to watch what my fellow teachers have choreographed. Every year, I am amazed and inspired by them.”</p>

<p>Not only does it show the hard work of the students, but is also a chance to appreciate the teachers and their dedication to make this an unforgettable event!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elective showcase was a success! It happens every year, where students from all conservatories get to explore the experience of performing on stage. Not only did the students at CSArts love to perform, the crowd loved it too! It was a chance to appreciate that elective classes are great opportunities to learn, and to show what they had been working on all year! Students in non-performing conservatories were able to feel the adrenaline rush of walking on stage–lights flashing, crowds clapping–something they normally wouldn’t do. After the show is completed, students in non-performing conservatories get experience in performing. This showcase gives a chance for students to recognize their growth and achieve an amazing accomplishment after this showcase.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mural, Mural On The Wall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/va-mural-25/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mural, Mural On The Wall" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/va-mural-25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/va-mural-25/"><![CDATA[<p>Did you see the new beautiful work of art on the administration outside wall facing the gymnasium? It’s a mural capturing different parts of nature. The mural was designed by students, bringing to life the magical ideas of each student. The mural tells a story of what students can create when they put their minds together.</p>

<p>John Scane, Mural Painting instructor, designs an annual project to teach his students how to create and design a mural. Then, they work together to incorporate each of their ideas into a finished project. The class, mainly made up of seniors, allows students to build their collaboration skills.</p>

<p>At the very start of the class students worked on their own sketches, incorporating their own styles and designs into the final product. “And at the end, everyone kinda put everything together like puzzles,” Sofie Davis said. “We split it into three groups so that everyone has one.” The class worked together to sketch, paint, and create their beautiful masterpiece before painting it on the wall beside the CSArts postcard mural.</p>

<p>Mural Painting gives students the opportunity to learn how to collaborate to bring a magnificent creation to life. Through expressing their different viewpoints, art styles, and creative thinking, students learn life skills before they go out into the world.</p>

<p>If you pass by a mural anywhere around the school, take a look at it. Think about how it makes you feel, as well as what it’s truly about. Cherish the memories, the artists’ perspective, and the beauty they provide the school.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="events" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did you see the new beautiful work of art on the administration outside wall facing the gymnasium? It’s a mural capturing different parts of nature. The mural was designed by students, bringing to life the magical ideas of each student. The mural tells a story of what students can create when they put their minds together.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/va-mural-25.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/va-mural-25.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Harmony of Fitness and the Arts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-harmony-of-pe-and-the-arts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Harmony of Fitness and the Arts" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-harmony-of-pe-and-the-arts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-harmony-of-pe-and-the-arts/"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, slips were delivered to the classrooms of freshman students informing them of their schedules for the fitness tests happening from May 13 - May 16. The fitness tests are state-mandated and issued to freshmen, along with diagnostics, mental health checks, and other student surveys often given to students throughout the year. The Physical Fitness Tests assess five different categories: Aerobic Capacity (PACER Test), Abdominal Strength and Endurance (Sit-Ups), Trunk Extensor Strength and Flexibility (Trunk Lift), Upper Body Strength and Endurance (Push-Ups), and Flexibility (Back-Saver Sit and Reach, Shoulder Stretch).</p>

<p>5th, 7th, and 9th grade public school students are required to take this test. While it does not affect your GPA or transcript, it is important to participate in these tests for students, parents, and staff to better understand the needs of students. According to a CSArtisan survey out of 16 students, 8 students felt nervous yet somewhat excited about the tests, 3 students were indifferent to it, 4 students felt extremely negative about it, and 1 student was extremely excited about it.</p>

<p>Students were also asked if they think fitness and being in shape is important, especially while attending conservatory. “I feel like it’s not that important.” says Ysa Alcisto, a freshman in Visual Arts, “You’re going to this specific school and you’re already focusing on the arts. It’s kind of hard for the student to have two things going on at once. Keeping in shape and practicing good habits are helpful, but I think it’s up to the student.”</p>

<p>Other students have similar responses. “Sometimes it’s difficult to fit into my schedule with conservatory and everything, but it does help me keep myself in a good headspace,” says Temujin Bachman-Williams, a freshman in Visual Arts. “Fitness is important but I think school is more important,” agrees Ari Dawson, a freshman in Creative Writing.</p>

<p>A handful of students, however, believe that fitness is a large, significant part of mastering the arts. “I do think it’s important to engage in fitness while honing your craft… fitness and art are similar,” says Sylvie Brinson, a sophomore in Acting. “Mentally and physically, they take time to perfect and you really have to work for your goal. No discipline means no results, for both fitness and art.”</p>

<p>Seamus McGarry, a freshman in Visual Arts, adds, “I think participating in fitness while doing the arts is super important. I exercise mainly because a healthy body and physical activity are key to a healthy mind. Fitness helps to motivate you to make art and lets you be loose and expressive when making art. It’s one of the best things you can do for yourself.”</p>

<p>Students with chronic illnesses have also agreed that even taking a short walk outside or doing light exercise in the gym can improve your physical and mental wellbeing, even aiding in familial ties. Dancers agree that conditioning and practice improves their performance as well.</p>

<p>Other ways to improve your fitness according to students include: participating in the large plethora of physical education classes at our school, doing cardio like running, hiking, walking, swimming, joining a sport outside of school, working out at the gym or at home with calisthenics, resistance and endurance training, and building muscle.</p>

<p>Though CSArts is an arts-centered school, this does not mean that fitness should be viewed as an entirely foreign concept. Being in shape impacts every aspect of your life, and even putting a little more effort into being physically active can be valuable.</p>]]></content><author><name>Delight Kim</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, slips were delivered to the classrooms of freshman students informing them of their schedules for the fitness tests happening from May 13 - May 16. The fitness tests are state-mandated and issued to freshmen, along with diagnostics, mental health checks, and other student surveys often given to students throughout the year. The Physical Fitness Tests assess five different categories: Aerobic Capacity (PACER Test), Abdominal Strength and Endurance (Sit-Ups), Trunk Extensor Strength and Flexibility (Trunk Lift), Upper Body Strength and Endurance (Push-Ups), and Flexibility (Back-Saver Sit and Reach, Shoulder Stretch).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Final Countdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-final-countdown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Final Countdown" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-final-countdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-final-countdown/"><![CDATA[<p>As the final days of the school year tick by, campus is buzzing with both excitement and emotion. For many students, this time marks the beginning of a bittersweet goodbye to senior friends who have become like family. With graduation only 8 days away, emotions are running high.</p>

<p>Senior Abigail Risdon reflected on her final weeks of high school, saying, “I’m going to miss my time so much here. I’ve made so many amazing friends and so many amazing memories. I truly could not have asked for a better community than the one I’ve found at CSArts.”</p>

<p>Goodbyes are not only difficult for the seniors preparing to walk across the stage, but also for the teachers who have watched them grow.</p>

<p>“It’s exciting and sad to see them go,” said Caballero, a 12th-grade English teacher. “I had my seniors do graduation speeches and as I’ve been reading them I’ve been like, bawling my eyes out. ”</p>

<p>Although many seniors are preparing to move away for college, saying goodbye doesn’t have to mean losing touch. In an age of texts, FaceTime, and social media, staying connected with your friends is easier than ever. Making the effort to check in, plan get-togethers during breaks, or even write the occasional letter can help preserve the friendships that have meant so much.</p>

<p>And while you probably won’t be calling up your teachers, many say they love when former students stop by to visit during breaks or send the occasional update. A quick hello or a thank-you in person can go a long way, and it means more than you might think.</p>

<p>So, as the countdown to graduation continues, take time to enjoy these last moments together and remember that goodbyes don’t have to be final!</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the final days of the school year tick by, campus is buzzing with both excitement and emotion. For many students, this time marks the beginning of a bittersweet goodbye to senior friends who have become like family. With graduation only 8 days away, emotions are running high.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stabbing at Sierra Madre Station</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stabbing-sierra-madre-metro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stabbing at Sierra Madre Station" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stabbing-sierra-madre-metro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stabbing-sierra-madre-metro/"><![CDATA[<p>A stabbing at the Sierra Madre Villa Station in April has left metro-riders shocked and unsettled. It happened on the morning of April 17th. The victim’s name and condition has not been released; however, they were transported to the hospital with multiple stab wounds.</p>

<p>The Los Angeles Sheriff’s department says it has arrested one person, Antonio Olivera, who remains in custody.</p>

<p>According to investigators, the suspect was wearing a security guard uniform, although authorities confirmed that he was not employed by metro. Police say the attack happened on the pedestrian bridge to the train platform. It was shut down for the investigation.</p>

<p>CSArts Senior Abigail Risdon said she arrived at the station that morning to take the train, but was quickly told to back away from the scene. She thought it was just normal police activity, but she wasn’t able to cross the bridge. Risdon was then taken to the next station by her aunt because there was no form of shuttling provided.</p>

<p>Olivera now faces one felony count each of assault with a deadly weapon and assault by means of force likely to produce great bodily injury. A future preliminary hearing will be scheduled to determine if there is sufficient enough evidence for the case to then proceed to trial.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joy Thomas &amp; Nico Deany</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A stabbing at the Sierra Madre Villa Station in April has left metro-riders shocked and unsettled. It happened on the morning of April 17th. The victim’s name and condition has not been released; however, they were transported to the hospital with multiple stab wounds.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/stabbing-sierra-madre-metro.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/stabbing-sierra-madre-metro.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Curve: Disabilities In School</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/learning-curve/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Curve: Disabilities In School" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/learning-curve</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/learning-curve/"><![CDATA[<p>After being diagnosed with a learning or processing disorder, or a mental or physical disability, students often must shift their focus to managing the challenges of their new reality. The constant questions from peers can trigger feelings of self-consciousness and anxiety. Whether it’s strangers asking about a mobility aid, commenting on stuttering or tics, or witnessing a panic attack, these experiences highlight how disorders can create significant challenges for learning and social life in high school.</p>

<p>According to the Child Mind Institute, the best ways to support those with disabilities are building self-confidence, finding a passion, and motivation.</p>

<p>“Having a disability is just one part of their life, albeit a big part, and does not define who they are or what they can accomplish,” Education Specialist Mr. Nathan Poole said. Understanding that everyone will use an accommodation someday, whether it’s reading glasses, a cane, or a wheelchair can help shift perspectives on disabilities. Rather than directly asking about someone’s disability, which can be a sensitive topic, focusing on developing a genuine relationship provides better support and reduces stress. “Once a relationship is established, I think it’s fine to ask questions about disabilities, as long as the person’ boundaries are respected,” said Pool. If the person is openly volunteering information, asking questions is a perfect way to learn.</p>

<p>There are many accommodations for students with disabilities. Using noise cancelling headphones, being in a quiet space, or extending time can support those with disabilities in the high school environment. “People with disabilities are not receiving ‘special treatment’ when they are provided accommodations,” Poole said. Working on understanding and using a calm approach is key to respecting the boundaries of those with disabilities. It’s important to approach sensitive topics with care and respect, ensuring that any questions about a disabled person’s struggles or life experiences are asked thoughtfully and at the right time. In a school environment, fostering understanding and empathy helps create a supportive atmosphere where all students can thrive.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being diagnosed with a learning or processing disorder, or a mental or physical disability, students often must shift their focus to managing the challenges of their new reality. The constant questions from peers can trigger feelings of self-consciousness and anxiety. Whether it’s strangers asking about a mobility aid, commenting on stuttering or tics, or witnessing a panic attack, these experiences highlight how disorders can create significant challenges for learning and social life in high school.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/learning-curve.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/learning-curve.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Summer School Programs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/free-summer-school-programs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Summer School Programs" /><published>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/free-summer-school-programs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/free-summer-school-programs/"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wanted to get ahead in school? Maybe retake a class over the summer? Or do you want to get a boost before your next year of school? If this is true for you, looking into summer programs is an amazing option.</p>

<p>“Aren’t those all super expensive though?” you may ask. Well, they don’t have to be.</p>

<p>There are many summer school programs that don’t cost any money at all.  CSArts school counselor Mindy Shiroma explained that the CSArts Counselor Corner website can provide information on these resources. The website lists free summer school programs where students can earn credit for school. The main programs highlighted include California Community Colleges and Opportunities for Learning, and Public Charter Schools. Another key factor to consider is whether or not the school will accept the credits given by the summer school programs.</p>

<p>“We will accept anything that is WACA (Western Association of Schools and Colleges) and UC approved,” said Shiroma. If you are unsure if a program is UC approved, you can visit the University of California A-G Course List. If you are looking to retake a class, students also have the option to take CSArts summer school courses. Hopefully, being aware of these options and resources will allow CSArts students like you to earn the credits they need!</p>]]></content><author><name>Aneira Tamppari</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wanted to get ahead in school? Maybe retake a class over the summer? Or do you want to get a boost before your next year of school? If this is true for you, looking into summer programs is an amazing option.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>