<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-31T15:44:11-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Transgender Awareness Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/transgender-awareness-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Transgender Awareness Week" /><published>2024-11-01T05:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T05:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transgender-awareness-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/transgender-awareness-week/"><![CDATA[<p>Transgender people are more than four times more likely than cisgender people to be violently attacked, according to a study by UCLA Williams Institute School of Law. Transgender Awareness Week is observed from November 13th to the 19th. The week is meant as a time to remember those suffering from transphobic violence, and a time to appreciate the rich history of trans people.</p>

<p>Social Sciences teacher Micahel Turf, is the advisor of CSArts’ SAGA club (sexuality and gender alliance). Turf is also earning his Masters in History with an emphasis on black and queer American history, including trans people of color.</p>

<p>“Appreciating the trans community […] allows us to honor the courage, resilience, and contributions of individuals who challenge societal norms and live authentically.” Mr. Turf says. “Trans people, especially from marginalized racial and ethnic groups, like Black trans women, face extraordinary systematic challenges yet continue to shape culture, politics, and justice movements.”</p>

<p>A famous example of this movement, Turf says, is Stonewall. Fighting for their rights, a large group of trans and black women protested against the inequality of the LGBTQ+ community. Marsha P. Johnson, a trans and Black woman, sparked the Stonewall protests in 1969. The 1980’s  HIV/AIDS crisis complicated issues for the queer community even more. During the struggle, Black and trans women supported those diagnosed from within the community and fought for treatment and a cure.</p>

<p>In 2024, 664 anti-trans bills have been introduced across the country, according to Trans Legislation Tracker.  The struggle for awareness of laws and violence in the LGBTQ+ community, and specifically the trans community is why advocates created a week of awareness. Groups like SAGA at CSArts continue to provide education, support and a safe space for LGBTQ+ people. If you would like more information on SAGA, contact Mr. Turf in room 208.  If you are in crisis, you can contact The Trevor Project Crisis Line to talk or text at 866-488-7386.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ari Dawson</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transgender people are more than four times more likely than cisgender people to be violently attacked, according to a study by UCLA Williams Institute School of Law. Transgender Awareness Week is observed from November 13th to the 19th. The week is meant as a time to remember those suffering from transphobic violence, and a time to appreciate the rich history of trans people.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/transgender-awareness-week.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/transgender-awareness-week.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts Breathes New Life into “Old Lace!”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/old-lace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts Breathes New Life into “Old Lace!”" /><published>2024-11-01T05:29:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T05:29:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/old-lace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/old-lace/"><![CDATA[<p>What happens when two hospitable old ladies and a twisted serial killer learn that they have something in common? What will they do about the policemen lodging in their home? Will they kill again? CSArts’ Acting Conservatory answered these questions on October 24th, when the theater doors to “Arsenic &amp; Old Lace” opened.</p>

<p>“Old Lace” was originally written in 1941, and enamored audiences of the time with its dark humor, wry wit, and near-farcical irony. The play follows the Brooklyn-living Brewster household, consisting of two homicidal old ladies, a homicidal brother, a brother that thinks he is Teddy Roosevelt, and the most normal of them all, a dramatic critic. Their home acts as a lodging place for the old, the lonely, and the ill. However, as Mortimer, the youngest Brewster, learns the hard way, his old aunts, Abby and Martha, have been poisoning these lodgers to put them out of their misery.</p>

<p>Even with such a dark plot, the humor of “Old Lace” bordered on slapstick at times, and had cast members running and jumping around the set. According to Karina Alvarez (ACT ‘25), who played Abby Brewster, the script constantly had her “trotting around on [her] tippy toes, sticking [her] butt out, and fiddling with [her] hands.”</p>

<p>Such a comedy requires a talented and experienced cast. The director, Christina Harris, found exactly what she wanted from this show in a cast of mainly Acting seniors. Many theatergoers may remember these leads from shows like “A Midsummer Night’s Dream,” “The 39 Steps,” or “John Proctor is the Villain.”</p>

<p>“I always try my best to bring all the energy and joy I have in myself into characters like [Teddy], so translating that into Teddy was really just an amazing process and a whole lot of fun,” said Matthew Guthrie (ACT ‘25), who played the pseudo-presidential Teddy Brewster.</p>

<p>As with any show, both cast and crew gave their all, putting on a show worthy of an audience, but experienced student designers and a student manager had some extra weight to carry.</p>

<p>“It was my first time ever being in a stage managing role, and it was very fun to just be a part of that community, because I made so many new friends,” said Alique Zadoian (P&amp;D ‘25), the show’s student Stage Manager.</p>

<p>“The most fun was found backstage, bonding with all the cast and crew and singing stupid songs in the dressing room were the greatest parts,” said Matthew.</p>

<p>Classics like “Arsenic &amp; Old Lace” hold up to this day in a theater scene where colleges and high schools are drawn to edgy new shows. Some theaters may insist upon performing hot new shows, but many will agree that sticking to the classics is a fantastic way to honor the history of theater.</p>]]></content><author><name>Octavia Roberts</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happens when two hospitable old ladies and a twisted serial killer learn that they have something in common? What will they do about the policemen lodging in their home? Will they kill again? CSArts’ Acting Conservatory answered these questions on October 24th, when the theater doors to “Arsenic &amp; Old Lace” opened.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/old-lace.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/old-lace.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Staff Spotlight: Bridgette Blankenhorn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bridgette/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staff Spotlight: Bridgette Blankenhorn" /><published>2024-11-01T05:28:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T05:28:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bridgette</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bridgette/"><![CDATA[<p>You may not know it, but the smiling face who greets CSArts students in the lobby every afternoon has been a TV star from the first day she was born. Bridgette Blankenhorn was featured on the TLC show A Baby Story, From music and tiktoks to having her birth on air, Bridgette has many stories to tell and talents to show!</p>

<p>An OSHA alumni, Bridgette loves musical theater, has a great voice, and a quick wit.</p>

<p>So, what about this early start in television? It turns out that she was born on a show called A Baby Story (s. 1 ep. 24). The reality TV show followed families into the delivery rooms, and Bridgette entered the world and stage from the very beginning. babies.</p>

<p>Bridgette is also a TikTok sensation with more than 400K subscribers. Her first viral moment was when she posted a video trying to find other people who were born on A Baby Story.</p>

<p>“I want to say going viral was like a snowball, but it was more like an avalanche. Every time I refreshed the page, views would go up by ten thousand. In the height of my virality I was averaging 200k views per video, but since 2021 it’s gone down by about 198k, but it was a lot of fun while it lasted. Internet fame is not forever!” Bridgette said.</p>

<p>You can find her on TikTok at <a href="https://tiktok.com/@bridgetteblank">@bridgetteblank</a> where she posts everything from music and to fun bits. But usually, you can find her saying hi in the office, so next time you see her, why not ask her about herself? She has some funny stories to tell.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ozzie Upton</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may not know it, but the smiling face who greets CSArts students in the lobby every afternoon has been a TV star from the first day she was born. Bridgette Blankenhorn was featured on the TLC show A Baby Story, From music and tiktoks to having her birth on air, Bridgette has many stories to tell and talents to show! An OSHA alumni, Bridgette loves musical theater, has a great voice, and a quick wit.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/staff-spotlight-bridgette.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/staff-spotlight-bridgette.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sade: 30 Years of Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sade: 30 Years of Music" /><published>2024-11-01T05:27:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T05:27:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sade</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sade/"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven’t listened to Sade’s music, her unique voice and songs can lift and break hearts. 30 years later, Sade’s back with a song for her transgender son and a new album.</p>

<p>Sade’s song, “Young Lion,” is an ode to her transgender son, Izaak Theo Adu. It’s part of compilation album titled, TRAИƧA. It includes more than 100 artists with songs to support transgender awareness.</p>

<p>Sade is also releasing an entirely new album almost 30 years to the day from her hit album, The Best of Sade.  It is the best, so, put it on your playlist and you won’t be sorry.</p>

<p>From her mellifluous voice to simultaneously sweet and somber lyrics, her 1994 album was a hit with critics and listeners, featuring songs like “Sweetest Taboo,” “Is it a Crime,” and her biggest hit, “Smooth Operator.”</p>

<p>In “Is It a Crime”, we’re met with poetic lyrics: “My love is wider, wider than Victoria Lake,  My love is taller, taller than the Empire State, It dives, it jumps, and it ripples like the deepest ocean.” Paired with Sade’s strong voice and background saxophone riffs, the song is beautiful and sensual. The song , “Kiss of Life” is also a standout song with stunning lyrics like: “There must have been an angel by my side / Something heavenly led me to you / He built a bridge to your heart, all the way” and a piano opening induction that is an alluring, intimate love song. 30 years later, Sade’s undeniable prowess still holds up.</p>

<p>So, look for both in the next month or two as Sade proves herself to be a current artist calling for acceptance and songs that are effortlessly timeless.</p>]]></content><author><name>Natalie Merino</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you haven’t listened to Sade’s music, her unique voice and songs can lift and break hearts. 30 years later, Sade’s back with a song for her transgender son and a new album.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/sade.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/sade.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Information for First Time Voters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first-time-voters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Information for First Time Voters" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first-time-voters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first-time-voters/"><![CDATA[<p>Early voting is already underway!  Next Tuesday, millions of Americans will head to the polls to vote in local, state, and national races. Some seniors will voice their choices as a vital part of democracy for the first time. If you’re a new voter (age 18+) or are eligible to register (age 16+) The CSArtisan Spoke with AP Government Instructor Timothy Skinner, students, and staff, and  have tips for you for Election Day, November 5th, and in the future:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Take the time to research the candidates and issues on the ballot. California has an extensive voting guide online at: https://voterguide.sos.ca.gov/</li>
  <li>Plan Ahead: Make a plan for when and how you’ll vote. Whether you’re going in-person or voting by mail, being organized can help reduce stress on Election Day.</li>
  <li>Discuss with Others: Talk about your thoughts with friends, family, or teachers. Engaging in discussions can help clarify your views and deepen your understanding.</li>
  <li>Local Government matters!  Do not let the noise of the presidential election overshadow the importance of local leaders and policies that directly affect you..</li>
  <li>Trust Your Instincts: Ultimately, it’s your vote. Listen to your values and beliefs,</li>
  <li>Celebrate the Experience: Remember that voting is a privilege and a key part of participating in democracy. Enjoy the experience and take pride in making your voice heard! Wear your “I Voted” sticker and put it on social media</li>
</ol>

<p>Some seniors aren’t at the legal age to vote but still want to prepare until the time comes. One of these Seniors, Abigail Risbon, had this to say when asked if they prepared for voting in any way. “I try to read through every unofficial ballot my parents receive and keep up with the news. One thing I would like to do more is keep track of important political events. Not just debates but movements in the house and legislation as well.”</p>

<p>When we asked Timothy Skinner about his own experience voting for the first time he said: “ When I voted for the first time, I felt a mix of excitement and nervousness […] I was a bit overwhelmed by the responsibility of making an informed choice. That experience really shaped my understanding and importance of staying informed, which I strive to pass on to my students today.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Arwen Mckay &amp; James N. Okon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Early voting is already underway! Next Tuesday, millions of Americans will head to the polls to vote in local, state, and national races. Some seniors will voice their choices as a vital part of democracy for the first time. If you’re a new voter (age 18+) or are eligible to register (age 16+) The CSArtisan Spoke with AP Government Instructor Timothy Skinner, students, and staff, and have tips for you for Election Day, November 5th, and in the future:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/first-time-voters.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/first-time-voters.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Fine Print Candy Investigation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fine-print/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Fine Print Candy Investigation" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fine-print</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fine-print/"><![CDATA[<p>Candy is a treat, but are all of its ingredients? Chew on the details of a few confusing compounds in popular Halloween candies, and see for yourself!</p>

<p>Let’s start with chocolate. M&amp;Ms, Hershey, Reese’s Peanut Butter Cups, Kit Kats, and Mars bars, to name a few, all contain something called lecithin. Lecithin, as explained by VeryWellHealth, is a natural fat found in foods like soybeans, egg yolks, and fish. It is used in chocolate to keep crystals or bloom from forming, or ingredients mixed together (as an emulsifier), among other things.</p>

<p>Some of these chocolate bars also contain another emulsifier called PGPR (short for polyglycerol polyricinoleate). According to the Hershey Company, PGPR comes from castor oil, and helps chocolate to flow better. Various studies have concluded that it has no negative health effects.</p>

<p>Apart from chocolate, things get a lot more sour–and I’m not just talking about flavor. Sour candies such as nerds, sour patch kids, starbursts, skittles, and smarties contain artificial colors like red 40, yellow 5, yellow 6, blue 1, and blue 2. Surprisingly, the FDA says that these colors, sometimes known as “coal-tar colors”, are derived from petroleum.</p>

<p>What about the dextrose ingredient in many of the candies mentioned? As the suffix “-ose” suggests, dextrose is a type of sugar. According to WebMD, it comes from corn and is added to food to enhance flavor or shelf-life.</p>

<p>Lastly, a wax called carnauba wax adds polish to candies like M&amp;Ms, Nerds, and Skittles. According to Encyclopedia Britannica, carnauba wax is harvested from the fronds of the carnauba palm plant.</p>

<p>So check on the fine print on the candy wrapper before you open it. You may choose not to partake!</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="essays" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Candy is a treat, but are all of its ingredients? Chew on the details of a few confusing compounds in popular Halloween candies, and see for yourself!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/fine-print.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/fine-print.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Dia de los Muertos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dia-de-los-muertos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Dia de los Muertos" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dia-de-los-muertos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dia-de-los-muertos/"><![CDATA[<p>While Halloween decorations are put away, you will see “ofrendas” with similar Halloween colors on the CSArts campus. These altars are to celebrate Dia De Los Muertos (or in English- The Day of The Dead) which happens every year on November 1st. Dia de los Muertos is a holiday rich in culture and tradition, celebrating family and friends who have died.</p>

<p>Dia de los Muertos is celebrated by making an altar and putting up photos and objects of those who passed away, an idea that you might recognize from the Disney movie Coco.</p>

<p>In Mexican culture this allows the spirits of the dead to visit when the barrier between the land of the living and the land of the dead is at its thinnest. The altar is decorated with items like candles, flowers and food to help guide the spirits.</p>

<p>If you want to celebrate Dia de los Muertos on campus, you will find an “ofrenda” in the creative writing library set up by Creative Writing Conservatory Director, Timothy Gomez.</p>

<p>Although the holiday is known to be on November 1st, Dia De Los Muertos is a series of days. It begins with a day to honor pets who have died on October 27th.  October 28th is a day to remember those who died unexpectedly, or tragically in an accident. October 30th is dedicated to remember those who are in limbo, a plane for those who died before being baptized. It’s often thought that the October 30th celebration is what inspired modern day Halloween.  November 1st is specifically for children and November 2nd is for adults.</p>

<p>Dia de los Muertos also holds a lot of meaning for those who celebrate it. “Dia de los Muertos is a holiday in which we recognize our ancestors. With family and friends we are able to talk to each other and reminisce about those who have passed. It helps us understand who the people before us were and helped shape who we are today,” Spanish Teacher Fatima Ruiz said. Family, friends, and faith  are the focus of Dia De Los Muertos and the holiday is a powerful way to form connections.</p>]]></content><author><name>Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Halloween decorations are put away, you will see “ofrendas” with similar Halloween colors on the CSArts campus. These altars are to celebrate Dia De Los Muertos (or in English- The Day of The Dead) which happens every year on November 1st. Dia de los Muertos is a holiday rich in culture and tradition, celebrating family and friends who have died.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/dia-de-los-muertos-2024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/dia-de-los-muertos-2024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Latest Salem’s Lot, Bad But Good</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/salems-lot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Latest Salem’s Lot, Bad But Good" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/salems-lot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/salems-lot/"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes bad movies are really good. Ask any Stephen King fan if they liked the latest MAX movie, Salem’s Lot, and you are likely going to get an ear full.  But, If you know nothing about  King’s 1975 book, and have never seen the other versions, it’s actually an entertaining film!</p>

<p>If you’re in the mood for a chilling journey  through the darker corners of human nature and the supernatural, Salems Lot is an entertaining hour and 53 minutes.</p>

<p>The made-for-TV movie brings the small town of “Jerusalems Lot” to life, with vampires and even creepy children with fangs.The director, Gary Dauberman, creates an eerie atmosphere, making the town itself a character. The story centers on Ben Mears, a writer who returns to “Jerusalem Lot” to face his past, and ultimately comes face to face with evil. As the townspeople begin to change in strange ways (and grow fangs), Mears realizes he is up against forces beyond his control. Yes, there is little character development, but that means there are no “sappy feels” for the vampires victims. Plus, eerie silences will leave you on the edge of your seat, and jump scares will leave horror lovers screaming with delight.  It’s campy; it’s cheesy; and it’s not going to be up for an Oscar Nomination, but Salem’s Lot does entertain. You can Watch Salem’s Lot on MAX.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nola Shields</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes bad movies are really good. Ask any Stephen King fan if they liked the latest MAX movie, Salem’s Lot, and you are likely going to get an ear full. But, If you know nothing about King’s 1975 book, and have never seen the other versions, it’s actually an entertaining film!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/salems-lot.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/salems-lot.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts: The Untold History</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/csarts-the-untold-history/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts: The Untold History" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/csarts-the-untold-history</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/csarts-the-untold-history/"><![CDATA[<p>The California School of the Arts was founded in 2017, and during these 8 years, it has already made a mark and a difference in the lives of its students. The school was officially established as a charter school and formed a public-private partnership with the Duarte Unified School District. The school has rapidly grown since its founding. In the first year, the school’s population was around 700 students. Now, it’s 1200. CSArts was originally created by OCSA, so more prospective students could get a chance to explore the arts. Many of its classes and conservatories are modeled after the Santa Ana school as well.</p>

<p>Mr. Turf has been a CSArts teacher since day one.</p>

<p>“I would say the overall energy of CSArts and the range of students–how everyone comes from all over–it’s such a diverse group and yet we all connect and feel like family.”</p>

<p>Turf said during the first year at CSArts,  there was no senior class which explains the smaller number of students the first year. With the addition of a senior class and the school becoming more popular, CSArts has grown substantially.</p>

<p>“Having small classes was nice, of course, but CSArts has grown so much and it is such a good thing, and I am so proud of the school CSArts is today. Students today are so passionate about their conservatories and it’s so interesting to see all these different artists with different backgrounds and talents. I will say though, one thing I miss from the earlier years was no bathroom lines!”</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian &amp; Tara Terzic</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The California School of the Arts was founded in 2017, and during these 8 years, it has already made a mark and a difference in the lives of its students. The school was officially established as a charter school and formed a public-private partnership with the Duarte Unified School District. The school has rapidly grown since its founding. In the first year, the school’s population was around 700 students. Now, it’s 1200. CSArts was originally created by OCSA, so more prospective students could get a chance to explore the arts. Many of its classes and conservatories are modeled after the Santa Ana school as well.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">“Beetlejuice Beetlejuice” Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beetlejuice-beetlejuice-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Beetlejuice Beetlejuice” Review" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beetlejuice-beetlejuice-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beetlejuice-beetlejuice-review/"><![CDATA[<p>Fans of the 1988 classic Beetlejuice have been awaiting its remake, and Beetlejuice Beetlejuice  does not disappoint. Directed by Tim Burton, the film brings back most of the beloved characters while introducing new faces that keep the spooky charm alive.</p>

<p>The Original Beetlejuice is an academy award winning musical film, and one of Tim Burton’s more famously known films. The new film supplies new music and introduces Jenna Ortega to the comical crew including Winona Ryder, Kathleen O’Harra, and  Michael Keaton. Beetlejuice Beetlejuice explores the idea of afterlife, with alluringly written music and costuming, and sets.  The film explores themes of family, loss, grief, and the passage of time. It reflects on how we confront our pasts and how those experiences shape our identities now.</p>

<p>Tim Burton’s signature aesthetic projected spookily throughout the film. The authentic, lime-green and dark purple colors, gothic designs, and whimsical, chilling atmosphere, transported viewers once again to the world of eerie afterlife. Burton’s flair of fusing humor with horror remains intact, ensuring that audiences are both entertained and slightly spooked, crafting imaginative scenes that balance the film’s darker themes, heartfelt moments and lighthearted moments. This fusion of emotions resonated deeply with this critic, making it more than just a spooky comedy to watch during fall.</p>

<p>This film definitely did not let down the original fans, and definitely brought some new ones, making it one of the biggest releases this year..</p>]]></content><author><name>Joy Thomas</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans of the 1988 classic Beetlejuice have been awaiting its remake, and Beetlejuice Beetlejuice does not disappoint. Directed by Tim Burton, the film brings back most of the beloved characters while introducing new faces that keep the spooky charm alive.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/beetlejuice-beetlejuice-review.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/beetlejuice-beetlejuice-review.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>