<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-03T20:11:35-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>The official website of the CSArts student newspaper. Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bat Boy: A Cast &amp;amp; Crew Perspective</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bat-boy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bat Boy: A Cast &amp;amp; Crew Perspective" /><published>2024-10-04T05:10:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T05:10:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bat-boy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bat-boy/"><![CDATA[<p>CSArts has always been a unique space for the production of unique shows, and this year’s “Bat Boy: The Musical” was no exception. Opening on September 26th, “Bat Boy” offered theatergoers a dark, twisted comedy featuring a terrifying main character, clad in bat prosthetics, greenish-gray body paint, and fake fangs.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s a story about a half bat, half human, and how he adapts to society and how society adapts to him,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Grace Dominguez (MT ‘25), who played Bat Boy’s sister, Shelly.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>[He] eventually becomes educated and more intelligent than the rest of the townsfolk and looks to join them in their society. [He] gets rejected by nearly all of them as they scapegoat [him] for their problems until [he] chooses to embrace the true persona of a monster that was forced upon [him],”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Ryan Backstrom (MT ‘26), who played the titular Bat Boy.</p>

<p>Grace Dominguez (MT ‘25), commented on the unique style of performance that the show demanded:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The most difficult part [of the performance] was mastering this ‘style’ because the show … plays into archetypes of people,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Grace.</p>

<p>There were many memorable moments in the show. Notably, those who saw the show will distinctly remember Bat Boy climbing, crawling, and creeping around the stage; however, what Ryan Backstrom distinctly remembers was the toll performing like that took on him:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I had to miss conservatory at least once to go to the chiropractor because I was cramping and my neck hurt so bad. There were a couple of times in rehearsal where I couldn’t sing the notes anymore because I had already been singing for two hours on top of having to make lots of loud noises without stopping,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Ryan said.</p>

<p>On top of the extraneous performances from Ryan, the show was made challenging to produce because of its generous use of fake blood. Big moments in the musical are punctuated by untimely character deaths, complete with big red blood spots on characters’ wardrobes where they were bitten or stabbed.</p>

<p>May Acero (P&amp;D ‘25), the show’s Assistant Stage Manager, recalls having to slather Ryan in fake blood before the climax of Act 2 and how hardworking backstage crew had to mop up said fake blood after every show.</p>

<p>While cast and crew are sad to see the show come to a close, they are incredibly proud of the product of their hard work.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am honestly at peace with the show being over because I feel very artistically fulfilled after this production. Although I’m sad that it is over because I will miss the friends I made throughout the process, I’m just grateful that I was able to have this experience,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Maisie Brown (MT ‘25), who played Bat Boy’s mother, Meredith.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Seeing my close friends do such good work that I’ve never seen them do before was just so inspiring. It was a reminder that hard work always pays off. And how important it is to acknowledge others’ growth, including your own.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Grace.</p>

<p>The backstage crew also had a blast with the production of the show, and the design of all of its elements.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This show was one of the best I’ve worked on and I will miss every single element. The smoothie of designs and collaborations was just really beautiful,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said May.</p>

<p>And audience members agree that the cast and its amazing pit orchestra of the show put on a brilliant &amp; hysterical spectacle of a two-act performance. Its catchy live band performance left those who heard it humming songs from the show, most of which being about learning to read, loving thy neighbor, or accepting your “beast” inside.</p>]]></content><author><name>Octavia Roberts</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSArts has always been a unique space for the production of unique shows, and this year’s “Bat Boy: The Musical” was no exception. Opening on September 26th, “Bat Boy” offered theatergoers a dark, twisted comedy featuring a terrifying main character, clad in bat prosthetics, greenish-gray body paint, and fake fangs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bat-boy.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bat-boy.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet Your Co-Class Presidents!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meet-your-co-class-presidents-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Your Co-Class Presidents!" /><published>2024-10-04T05:09:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T05:09:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/meet-your-co-class-presidents-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meet-your-co-class-presidents-2024/"><![CDATA[<p>While election season in the United States is in full swing, CSArts have already cast their votes and elected co-class presidents. Each grade has two leaders who speak and act for the student body and the CSArtisan spoke with the co-presidents to hear their plans for the year.</p>

<p>Senior Co-Class Presidents Charlie Pokaski and Ivy Kim say they wanted to run in order to make sure the class of 2025 had the best leaders and planners to ensure the best school experiences possible. Senior year is the busiest, as they plan all the important senior events like “senior sunrise,” “senior week,” and activities surrounding graduation.</p>

<p>Zakai Haynes and Frankie Fontana are the Junior Co-Class Presidents. They say that the process of running and getting elected was a lot of work, but it paid off.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was an opportunity to help cultivate a positive and unique community,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Haynes said.</p>

<p>Haynes and Fontana want to increase participation and passion from Juniors by adding a class point system for rewards. They also want to focus more on school clubs and encourage collaboration.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We believe that clubs are the creative collective of our school,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Haynes said.</p>

<p>The Sophomore Co-Class Presidents, Tempele Stewart and Isla Castellon want to set up a student board to gather feedback on certain ideas.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There are a few different roles; some are your typical roles like treasurer and a fundraising consultant. But we also have other fun positions like Food Connoisseur, Voice of the Community, and Communicator of the people,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Castellon said. Their goal is to increase student involvement to change the school community for the better.</p>

<p>Evie Linchangco and Kayla Minasian serve as Freshmen Co-Class Presidents. They say their focus is on creating a positive and safe school environment for the Class of 2028.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve always aspired to take on leadership roles, and helping others through volunteering. I truly care about creating a school environment that feels like home, where everyone feels seen, valued, and supported. Freshman year is a pivotal time, and I’m eager to help make this transition smoother for all of us,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Minasian said. The two are also focused on addressing student concerns, including improvements to lunch lines and are working on creating a Google Form to gather student feedback on various issues.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We want to ensure everyone’s voice is heard and that we’re addressing the needs of the students,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Linchangco said.</p>]]></content><author><name>First Last</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While election season in the United States is in full swing, CSArts have already cast their votes and elected co-class presidents. Each grade has two leaders who speak and act for the student body and the CSArtisan spoke with the co-presidents to hear their plans for the year.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/meet-your-co-class-presidents-2024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/meet-your-co-class-presidents-2024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Demonstrated Interest: Secret to College Admissions?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/demonstrated-interest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Demonstrated Interest: Secret to College Admissions?" /><published>2024-10-04T05:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T05:08:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/demonstrated-interest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/demonstrated-interest/"><![CDATA[<p>As we ease into the school year and application season approaches, one term keeps coming up: “demonstrated interest.” Understanding how to effectively showcase your best qualities for prospective schools could be the key to standing out.</p>

<p>“Demonstrated interest” is defined as “the effort a student makes through their college application and actions showing a genuine interest in a specific school.” In other words, you’re letting the college know the likelihood that you will enroll if accepted. This may include attending college fairs, visiting the campus, emailing admissions officers, applying for early decision, and even connecting on social media.</p>

<p>While “demonstrated Interest” is not as important as a stellar transcript and strong leadership, it can be the icing on the cake.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We don’t consider demonstrated interest when looking at applications but it can still be a great way to learn about the prospective school and see if it is a good fit,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>University of California Santa Barbara representative said. Other schools, however, do factor in “demonstrated interest” when making admissions decisions.</p>

<p>The CSArtisan has compiled a list of schools and the degree of importance of “demonstrated interest.” If you are interested in a school that is not on the list, see your counselor for more details.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/demonstrated-interest-table.png" alt="demonstrated-interest-table.png" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we ease into the school year and application season approaches, one term keeps coming up: “demonstrated interest.” Understanding how to effectively showcase your best qualities for prospective schools could be the key to standing out.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/demonstrated-interest.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/demonstrated-interest.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Fall Breeze Accompanied with June Beetles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/june-bugs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Fall Breeze Accompanied with June Beetles" /><published>2024-10-04T05:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T05:08:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/june-bugs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/june-bugs/"><![CDATA[<p>Green patches of grass throughout CSArts are filled with students laying down and enjoying their break. That is until June Beetles invade. June bugs are known for their beautiful green fluorescent shell, but they have been known to fly into students’ heads and hair. This is a new phenomenon at CSArts and the green bugs may be here because of the new greenery on campus.</p>

<p>There is a myth that June Beetles are blind, but according to Bugology.com, the beetles can see; they are just clumsy fliers! They are also a great alternative to pesticides, because they kill harmful soil dwelling insects.</p>

<p>Yes, with the Beetlejuice sequel on the big screen, these bugs may be getting a bad rep. Yes, they are not coordinated fliers, but these green bugs have a purpose: to get rid of harmful insects. So, “Bee” kind the next time you see one flying clumsily through the air.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aryhanna Pham</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green patches of grass throughout CSArts are filled with students laying down and enjoying their break. That is until June Beetles invade. June bugs are known for their beautiful green fluorescent shell, but they have been known to fly into students’ heads and hair. This is a new phenomenon at CSArts and the green bugs may be here because of the new greenery on campus.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/june-bugs.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/june-bugs.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Scaries on Screens: A CSArtisan Student Movie Poll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/scaries-on-screen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scaries on Screens: A CSArtisan Student Movie Poll" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/scaries-on-screen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/scaries-on-screen/"><![CDATA[<p>One of the highlights of Halloween is watching frightening films! We had CSArts students take a poll of their favorite fun Halloween movies and their favorite horror movies.</p>

<p>In the fun and less frightening category, the top three movies were:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Corpse Bride with 50% of the vote.</li>
  <li>Hocus Pocus with 25%. And</li>
  <li>The original Beetlejuice at 15%</li>
  <li>The Nightmare Before Christmas and Coraline were honorable mentions</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Corpse Bride is my favorite Halloween/Fall movie, because, in my opinion, it’s the best movie to curl up on the couch and watch, especially if it’s cold and dark outside!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Nico Deany, a 10th grader here at CSArts.</p>

<p>The top Horror films according to The CSArtisan poll were:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Conjuring with the majority of the votes and</li>
  <li>Scream, It, and Megan evenly split.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>I loved the cinematography and the eerie atmosphere in The Conjuring!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Joy Thomas, a 10th grader here at CSArts.</p>

<p>If you’re looking for fresh frightful films, Steven King’s Salem’s Lot new adaptation is available on MAX. <em>Terrifier 3</em> opens in theaters on October 11th, and <em>Smile 2</em> hits theaters on October 18th. The final season of <em>What We Do In The Shadows</em> premieres on FX October 21st.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the highlights of Halloween is watching frightening films! We had CSArts students take a poll of their favorite fun Halloween movies and their favorite horror movies. In the fun and less frightening category, the top three movies were: Corpse Bride with 50% of the vote. Hocus Pocus with 25%. And The original Beetlejuice at 15% The Nightmare Before Christmas and Coraline were honorable mentions]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts Students Go International</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/students-go-global/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts Students Go International" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/students-go-global</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/students-go-global/"><![CDATA[<p>Study abroad opportunities are usually only available for college students, but CSArts-SGV gives you the opportunity while you are here. This means you can jetset across the globe through the Council on International Education Exchange or CIEE. Trips are during the Summer, and last year 14 CSArts students studied abroad in Spain, China, France, Portugal, and England.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The benefits of visiting another country, engaging with native speakers, and becoming immersed in a cultural experience that can’t be understood from academic study alone,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Principal of Arts, Dr. Stephen Cook. Of course, plane tickets, food, and housing make this an expensive learning experience. For more information, you can contact Dr. Cook.</p>]]></content><author><name>First Last</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study abroad opportunities are usually only available for college students, but CSArts-SGV gives you the opportunity while you are here. This means you can jetset across the globe through the Council on International Education Exchange or CIEE. Trips are during the Summer, and last year 14 CSArts students studied abroad in Spain, China, France, Portugal, and England.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/students-go-global.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/students-go-global.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Prepare To Scare: Getting Ready for Halloween</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/prepare-to-scare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prepare To Scare: Getting Ready for Halloween" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/prepare-to-scare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/prepare-to-scare/"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven’t experienced Halloween at CSArts-SGV, you are in for a (trick or) treat. While other schools restrict wearing costumes to class, CSArts rolls out the red carpet for students and staff alike to show off their creativity!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The variety of student costumes is incredible. Teachers and Administrators take part in the fun as well,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Social Science teacher Mr. Pegan.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A CSArts-SGV halloween actually gives West Hollywood a run for its money.  It’s a holiday based on creativity and costuming, so of course, it’s a huge deal!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Creative Writing Instructor, Mr. Blair</p>

<p>CSArts hosts an annual costume contest judged by teachers and administrators. Teachers usually have a theme too, but it is a guarded secret until October 31st!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ozzie Upton</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you haven’t experienced Halloween at CSArts-SGV, you are in for a (trick or) treat. While other schools restrict wearing costumes to class, CSArts rolls out the red carpet for students and staff alike to show off their creativity!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/prepare-to-scare.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/prepare-to-scare.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Safety Implementations for the Metro: What Students Should Know</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/metro-safety/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Safety Implementations for the Metro: What Students Should Know" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/metro-safety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/metro-safety/"><![CDATA[<p>Every day, large numbers of CSArts students rely on the Metro to get to and from school. Many students are aware of the possible dangers that riding the metro may present, as crime incidents on LA Metro have increased over the years along with the number of riders.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So far this year, there have been 2.18 crimes per 100,000 riders, compared to 1.2 at this time in 2021 and 0.84 in 2019,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Jenna Peterson from Cal Matters.</p>

<p>LA Metro has responded to the increase in crime on its trains and platforms in major ways. They have increased the amount of cameras and lights in and around trains. Cameras are used to ward off any criminals and keep track of any active criminal activities. Studies show that just by seeing cameras’ presence, many criminals are deterred and don’t go through with their plans.</p>

<p>Better visibility is a great resource, especially on a ride back home at night. Because of that, lots more lighting was added in. This is important for students as we lose more daylight and for the elderly population as the tracks and platforms are better lit.</p>

<p>In addition to partnering with local law enforcement agencies, LA Metro has also hired more well-trained security guards to patrol the trains and be on the lookout for dangerous incidents. Metro has also hired more “ambassadors,” who are there to assist those who need physical assistance and are able to report suspicious activity.</p>

<p>Another concern is the rise of unhoused people in the Los Angeles area who face mental health issues and who also rely on the Metro. In response, LA Metro created the Metro Homeless Outreach team, which was made by partnering with the Los Angeles Department of Health Services. Those who are a part of the team are set up at different locations to provide essential resources to people experiencing homelessness on the Metro system.</p>

<p>These implementations are hoped to immediately increase rider safety.  LA Metro is also looking toward the future with its “Vision Plan,” which is set to be finished by 2028 for the upcoming LA Summer Olympics. While exact details of the plan have not yet been released,  Metro’s Vision 2028 released a statement about their project that hopes to: “provide high-quality mobility options that enable people to spend less time traveling; deliver outstanding trip experiences for all users of the transportation system; enhance communities and lives through mobility and access to opportunity; transform LA County through regional collaboration and national leadership; and provide responsive, accountable, and trustworthy governance within the Metro organization.”</p>

<p>It is important for students who ride Metro to be aware of their surroundings and it is never a bad idea to travel with another student. If you have any questions about Metro  safety, you can contact Assistant Principal, Leon Metoyer, or Metro Community Relations Officer Daniel Gonzalez.</p>

<p>It’s also a good idea to save these important numbers in your phone:</p>

<p>CSArts-SGV Security Cell: (626) 205-4001
LA Metro Non-Emergency Concern Line: (323) 563-5000
LA Metro Police &amp; Security Line: (888) 950-7233</p>]]></content><author><name>Ariella Dawson &amp; Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every day, large numbers of CSArts students rely on the Metro to get to and from school. Many students are aware of the possible dangers that riding the metro may present, as crime incidents on LA Metro have increased over the years along with the number of riders.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Horror Night Showdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/horror-night-showdown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horror Night Showdown" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/horror-night-showdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/horror-night-showdown/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s that time of the year again: spooky season! Don’t know which parks to go to? We’ve got the info, and two teachers who offered a review of two of the most famous freight fests in Southern California.</p>

<p>The most popular are: Universal’s Halloween Horror Nights and Knott’s Scary Farm. Knott’s Scary Farm’s general admission price is $59.99. You can also get the famous “boo-fit” with your regular admission for $74.99. Universal Halloween Horror Nights tickets are around $77. Both parks have different tier prices for express tickets. Price-wise, Knott’s Scary Farm appears more affordable than Halloween Horror Nights, but which one is better?</p>

<p>We talked to terrified teachers about their experiences this year- Creative Writing Instructor Robert Blair, as he and Social Sciences teacher Michael Turf have already gone to both. Mr. Blair left Horror Nights feeling disappointed and had a better time at Scary Farms.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This year, you’re going to get more jump scares for your money at Knotts.  And that wasn’t the case last year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Universal is known for capturing the macabre through movie-themed mazes. Knotts has a variety of mazes with different themes.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I mean they’re both different. One’s a little campier, Knotts is campy, and fun. Universal is usually scarier with props because it’s Hollywood. But this year, you  get more for your money at Knotts.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Blair said his favorite maze at Universal was Death Exposure: Death Valley.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was like a radioactive desert and there were some great jumpscares, but for the rest of them, I was kinda disappointed. I could tell there weren’t many employees in the mazes.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mr. Blair then said that if he could recommend one of the parks for a second visit it would be Knotts, “A lot more jumpscares, and campy, and fun, and a lot less expensive.”</p>]]></content><author><name>James Okon</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s that time of the year again: spooky season! Don’t know which parks to go to? We’ve got the info, and two teachers who offered a review of two of the most famous freight fests in Southern California.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/horror-night-showdown.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/horror-night-showdown.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Service, Out of Luck</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-closure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Service, Out of Luck" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-closure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-closure/"><![CDATA[<p>During the past few weeks, Northview Field and the back of the PAC were set off-limits, followed by the temporary closure of several restrooms. 
Student use of the field during lunch and office hours has been suppressed, due to a staff shortage. Vaping has been a consistent problem on the field, and there have been multiple reports of students smoking. Administrators say that in order to open the field back up there needs to be more supervising staff.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We’re actively looking to hire a campus supervisor, we sent multiple things to try to find someone who fits our school and is talented and capable enough to do the job,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Leon Metoyer, Assistant Principal. The school is hoping to gain more security, to supervise the field and open it back up. Metoyer says that when they do get more staff, the field will definitely be open.</p>

<p>Vaping has also been an issue in the gender-neutral restrooms in the studios. They are also closed during office hours and after school because of vaping.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That is when 80% of our vape sensor detection alarms go off. I’ve been told by students that that is like a place where a lot of people vape. So right now, we’re a little short on staff as far as campus supervisors are concerned, so that area is closed,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<p>Additionally, administrators added a gate in the back of the PAC.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The gate’s there … to make sure our students and staff and faculty are secure. It’s always been a restricted area, and now there’s a gate,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<p>Administrators and security are working on hiring new staff to re-open areas where students enjoy spending time and keep our campus safe.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joy Thomas &amp; Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the past few weeks, Northview Field and the back of the PAC were set off-limits, followed by the temporary closure of several restrooms. Student use of the field during lunch and office hours has been suppressed, due to a staff shortage. Vaping has been a consistent problem on the field, and there have been multiple reports of students smoking. Administrators say that in order to open the field back up there needs to be more supervising staff.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/field-closure.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/field-closure.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>