<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-27T22:01:06-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Success Beyond Selectivity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ivy-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Beyond Selectivity" /><published>2025-03-28T05:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T05:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ivy-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ivy-day/"><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all heard of the Ivy League. The eight shiny schools, ever-prestigious and for many,  the ultimate accomplishment for high school students.</p>

<p>For countless students, chasing prestige can feel like an exhausting all-consuming race. It’s not too dramatic to say that sometimes, one grade, one missed opportunity, one mistake and it suddenly feels like all hopes of getting into your dream college are at risk. So much of the process is hidden behind closed doors. That means it  can feel like you are grasping  at something that doesn’t exist, and trying  to compartmentalize yourself into that “perfect student.”</p>

<p>Is this really how access to higher education is supposed to feel?	Much of the obsession with these elite institutions can be traced back to how American culture glorifies college rankings. In the 1980s, the U.S. News &amp; World report released its first ranking list, designed to offer a digestible hierarchy of undergraduate universities based primarily on reputation. Though initially intended as a simple tool to compare universities, it quickly became a culture stable, fueling a hyper-competitive college admissions environment. Today the rankings are a dichotomy of something influential as well as contentious, having faced accusations of data manipulation and unreliable methodologies. Critics question whether it’s appropriate, or even accurate, to rank colleges on a simplistic scale. And it’s not just universities who are ranked lower that protest. Harvard, Yale, Columbia, and Stanford are amongst the universities who benefit the most from this scale and yet now refuse to submit their own rankings of other universities.</p>

<p>The problem runs deeper than just flawed rankings; college acceptance rates at these hyper-selective institutions now hover around 10% or lower, making the process feel like a game of chance rather than a reflection of merit or hard work. Acceptance rates are often manipulated to appear more exclusive through sometimes encouraging unqualified applicants to apply (i.e. sending students mail who might be below their GPA or SAT score bar). In January of 2023, Intelligent.com surveyed over 1,600 current 4-year college students along with those who have graduated from a 4-year school within the last five years, and found that 6 in 10 college applicants lie on their resumes, driven by the pressure to stand out in an ever more competitive pool.</p>

<p>Ironically, despite the seemingly relentless assurance from society that Ivy Leagues and the peer institutions have the best to offer, they are not necessarily the best in the world. When compared internationally, many American universities fall behind in terms of educational quality and accessibility. Germany, the Netherlands, and Switzerland boast world-class institutions that rival or even surpass the most prestigious universities and don’t rely on hyper selectivity or require students to craft resumes filled with endless extracurriculars. Instead they emphasize rigorous academics, accessibility, and affordability allowing students to focus on intellectual growth rather than resume padding.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the toll this prestige-driven mindset takes on students is undeniable. The pressure to “succeed” by attending a top tier college has been linked to anxiety, depression, and burnout. Many students become so fixated on a single path to success that they lose sight of the broader picture: why higher education exists in the first place. College is a place of self-discovery as well as learning. Schools are supposed to offer increased job opportunities, higher earning potential, greater job security, as well as the chance to develop valuable skills and build a professional network. Many less selective or lesser known colleges offer just as much, if not more access to all of the above. We need to stop believing in the lie that low acceptance rates equal an institution that has everything you need to not just succeed but thrive.</p>

<p>What should truly matter when it comes to evaluating a college is not a rankings list determined by a simple list of data and its perceived sense of exclusivity, but how schools align with an individual’s personal goals and interests. Factors like academic programs, campus culture, financial support, and career services should carry more weight than a school’s brand name. Consider if you are disabled, or neurodivergent, does this school provide good resources that will support my success? Yet the cultural narrative surrounding college admissions often prioritizes prestige over personal fit.</p>

<p>Rejection from a prestigious university does not define your worth or dictate your future. While it’s easy to feel like a door has closed, it’s important to remember that countless paths to success exist outside of Ivy League walls. Some of the world’s most influential figures build their legacies at institutions that wouldn’t make it to the top of any ranking list. Steve Jobs, co-founder of Apple dropped out of Reed college, Oprah Winfrey, one of the most successful media moguls of all time, attended Tennessee State University, Howard Shultz, former CEO of Starbucks went to Northern Michigan University. These stories remind us that success is not determined by the prestige of one’s alma mater, but by the passion, dedication, and resilience brought to one’s pursuits. Your value doesn’t diminish because of an admissions decision.</p>

<p>Coping with rejection is challenging, but it’s also an opportunity to reassess and refocus. Allow yourself to grieve and process your emotions. Talk to trusted friends, family, or mentors about how you’re feeling. Then, start researching schools that may not have been your first choice but still offer excellent academic programs, vibrant communities, and opportunities that align with your goals. Lean into the mindset that success comes from what you do with the opportunities you have, not just where you go to school.</p>

<p>Ultimately, moving beyond the prestige myth means acknowledging that fulfillment and accomplishment are not tied to a single institution. The most important thing is to find a place where you can thrive and grow into the person you’re meant to become.</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve all heard of the Ivy League. The eight shiny schools, ever-prestigious and for many, the ultimate accomplishment for high school students.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/ivy-day.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/ivy-day.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Writing on The Stall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-writing-on-the-stall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Writing on The Stall" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-writing-on-the-stall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-writing-on-the-stall/"><![CDATA[<p>Vandalism at CSArts has been increasing. It started with the social media craze around the world with the defacement of keyboards in chromebooks, and has worsened to broken equipment and vandalized bathrooms.</p>

<p>Principal of Academics Nicole Read encourages students to read the vandalism policy on the school website. Even though school administration  reviewed the policy at Welcome Week and Morning Announcements, there has been an increase in incidents and these incidents have serious consequences.</p>

<p>Students found guilty could face suspension, even expulsion depending on how severe the action was. “The school can charge the family for the cost of restoring the building or equipment and labor involved,” Read said. Repairing the restrooms can cause them to be closed for many school days.</p>

<p>The custodial staff are deeply impacted by the trend. Vandalism takes them away from important tasks that keep the campus running smoothly, and prolongs their shifts. “I don’t think students understand how tight any schools’ budgets are,” Read said. “This recent spat of vandalism has cost us thousands. That is money better spent on instruction or supplies.”</p>

<p>Administration understands students’ passion for sharing their voices, but they encourage students to use the art they create in conservatory to express themselves. Students can also express their emotions to school admin and counselors, who will support and listen to their needs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vandalism at CSArts has been increasing. It started with the social media craze around the world with the defacement of keyboards in chromebooks, and has worsened to broken equipment and vandalized bathrooms.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Zine Scene</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/zine-scene/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Zine Scene" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/zine-scene</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/zine-scene/"><![CDATA[<p>Zines are a dying art form, but you wouldn’t have guessed it as more than a thousand people attended the L.A. Zine Fest in Los Angeles March 1st and 2nd.</p>

<p>Zines are a type of magazine, often created first hand by the artist, and self-published, to display art and stories. This two day zine production was hosted by the Broad, a contemporary art museum in Downtown L.A. More than 85 artists shared, sold, and discussed their work.</p>

<p>CSArts is filled with young artists, yet few of them share their work with the world. This is often because there aren’t always accessible ways to put your work out there, and it can be intimidating to share your art. Zines are a wonderful medium with which to put art out there, and explore other artist’s work.</p>

<p>Mel Henderson, one of the artists and print-shop owners at this event, explains what made her start making zines and sharing her work, saying, “Your art is going to be loved by somebody, it’s all about finding your people. I would just encourage anybody, if you make zines, if you make any kind of art, just put it out there.”</p>

<p>At the event, there were thousands of different zines. The amazing aspect of exploring all of the art was that every zine was completely unique and expressed something different, yet everything that was expressed was important. There were booths with zines centering around personal struggles, political stances and issues, social injustices, and interests ranging from punk rock bands to childhood dreams.</p>

<p>“I’m an artist of several different mediums, so I make prints, I do photography, and zines was just this really magical way for me to mix all the mediums that I do into one. And it’s just so tactical and I’m also just in love with paper, so zines checked a lot of boxes,” Henderson says.</p>

<p>Zines are an easy way to express yourself, share your art, utilize different mediums and interests you have, and work with paper—a dying art form in itself. Henderson advocated for the creation of zines from all young artists. She says, “I made my first zine about a year and a half ago, and I just have not stopped since!” If you’re looking for a way to express yourself through art, Zine’s could be the perfect artform for you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Nico Deany</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zines are a dying art form, but you wouldn’t have guessed it as more than a thousand people attended the L.A. Zine Fest in Los Angeles March 1st and 2nd.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/zine-scene.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/zine-scene.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Adiós, Señora Yadira!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/senora-yadira/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adiós, Señora Yadira!" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/senora-yadira</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/senora-yadira/"><![CDATA[<p>This year marks the end of an era in CSArts’ in the World Languages Department. After 8 years of teaching Spanish at CSArts, Sra. Yadira Rivera shared with her students that this is her last semester. Rivera says her retirement is bittersweet. She loves being with students, and “chismeando” (Spanish for “gossiping”) with them. Even through all of the tedious grading, she finds joy in teaching and says it is rewarding to reunite with past students who remember and thank her for her sweet and generous character.</p>

<p>Rivera will be making a big move in the months ahead. She will be returning to her homeland, Puerto Rico. Her retirement plans include spending time with her family and traveling around the world. Her first stop after Puerto Rico? Ireland! Then it’s off to a fourteen-day cruise to Iceland, and a week in France. After she’s done vacationing around the world, she plans on fulfilling a life-long dream of living in Spain for a year. Thank you for your dedication, support, and heart Sra. Rivera! We will miss you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Mariam Ghazaryan</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year marks the end of an era in CSArts’ in the World Languages Department. After 8 years of teaching Spanish at CSArts, Sra. Yadira Rivera shared with her students that this is her last semester. Rivera says her retirement is bittersweet. She loves being with students, and “chismeando” (Spanish for “gossiping”) with them. Even through all of the tedious grading, she finds joy in teaching and says it is rewarding to reunite with past students who remember and thank her for her sweet and generous character.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interact Club Recognized with City of Hope Award</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rotary-club/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interact Club Recognized with City of Hope Award" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rotary-club</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rotary-club/"><![CDATA[<p>In early March, the CSArts-SGV Interact (Rotary) Club was recognized with the City of Hope Award. The award was for students demonstrating their dedication to serving the community. Senior Blood Drive Coordinator Francis Fong honored CSArts students Natalie Lanza, Marley Lemaire, Karina Yue, and Macy Mananquil at the Board of Trustees Meeting.</p>

<p>For the first time since its founding, the Interact club independently organized and hosted a blood drive in partnership with City of Hope, a nationally recognized cancer treatment and research center. More than 50 CSArts-SGV students, faculty, parents, and guardians rolled up their sleeves, each giving up a pint. Due to a blood shortage emergency across the country, these selfless actions have a large impact. In fact, a single blood donation can save up to 3 lives.</p>

<p>“I am extremely honored for the chance to be awarded. I am very grateful that I was able to give back to my community and make a difference like this,” junior Natalie Lanza said.</p>

<p>“This experience was amazing and I was honestly so thrilled to be part of it. Taking the initiative to do good is very important to me,” junior Marley Lemaire said.</p>

<p>As the Interact Club goes forward, members are committed to furthering their impact with new fundraising efforts, partnerships, and volunteer opportunities. They emphasize the importance of upholding their values of “Service Above Self,” every step of the way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In early March, the CSArts-SGV Interact (Rotary) Club was recognized with the City of Hope Award. The award was for students demonstrating their dedication to serving the community. Senior Blood Drive Coordinator Francis Fong honored CSArts students Natalie Lanza, Marley Lemaire, Karina Yue, and Macy Mananquil at the Board of Trustees Meeting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/rotary-club.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/rotary-club.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Purrs and Paws for the Applause</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/respect-your-cat-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Purrs and Paws for the Applause" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/respect-your-cat-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/respect-your-cat-day/"><![CDATA[<p>Cats have been the pinnacle of animal worship since Ancient Egypt, and they act like they know it! Whether they are the spawn of gods or couch potatoes, felines love respect, laser beams, and catnip. Today is “National Respect Your Cat Day.”  This feline-loving CSArtisan Journalist spoke with four other cat owners on how they honor their cat, and what they’d say to them if they could understand.</p>

<p>“Morris is an 11 year old American Shorthair. He isn’t all that smart, but is such an extroverted, gentle cat. He’s also very, very, big. He’s very picky about his food and environment and requires a certain brand of pretty much everything, so we respect that to the best of our ability. Not to be corny, but I’d tell him that we love him very much.” said Jane Kistner,  freshman, Creative Writing conservatory.</p>

<p>“My cat’s name is Ollie. He’s a tuxedo cat and is 2.5 years old. He is super friendly and is active. I show love and respect to my cat by taking photos of him and playing with him, and giving him lots of attention. I would like to say to my cat thank you for peeing in the sink and pooping outside so I don’t have to clean up after him,” said Lula Seifert, freshman, Integrated Arts conservatory.</p>

<p>“Burger is a white Khao Manee and Paris is a Black Tuxedo. Burger is only 8 months old and Paris is 3 years old. Burger is very social and friendly.  He loves to go outside and play with the neighbors, while Paris is calmer and more introverted. I show my cats that I love them by playing with them and cuddling them and secretly giving them treats without my mother knowing to make them happy. My cats are the sweetest cats ever and I am so incredibly thankful to have them a part of my life every day,”said  Lyna Chataignoux, freshman,  Musical Theater Conservatory.</p>

<p>“My cat is named Hannah. She’s 8 years old and she hates being pet. She only wants love through food, so to her, I only show respect 3 times a day. If I could talk to my cat I would tell her to shower.” Ari Dawson, freshman, Creative Writing conservatory.</p>

<p>I used to have a cat as well- a gorgeous white and gray Persian longhair. His name was Roko, and he passed away a few months ago at the impressive age of nineteen! He was cautious around strangers, but gentle to my family. As a baby, I attempted to crawl over him and often pulled at his hair, but he never lashed out. He came by our side when wanted to be petted, and cried when we closed bedroom doors. I loved him dearly still, and if I could, I would tell him that I love and miss him so much. My family and I pay our respects to him with a small altar near our stairs, and go through photos of him. Even though he’s not with us anymore, he was one of the biggest parts of my childhood, and I’m sure that whatever afterlife he is in, he stares down at me strangely when I make bad decisions.</p>

<p>According to the American Veterinary Association, a third of American households have cats as pets.  That makes almost 74 million domesticated cats!  This shows cats are important beings that continue to grace us with their presence on Earth!</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/posts/respect-your-cat-day.jpg" alt="CSArts cats" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Delight Kim</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cats have been the pinnacle of animal worship since Ancient Egypt, and they act like they know it! Whether they are the spawn of gods or couch potatoes, felines love respect, laser beams, and catnip. Today is “National Respect Your Cat Day.” This feline-loving CSArtisan Journalist spoke with four other cat owners on how they honor their cat, and what they’d say to them if they could understand.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Perfect Play Performances</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/small-plays/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perfect Play Performances" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/small-plays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/small-plays/"><![CDATA[<p>Everyone has heard about the big musicals like Into The Woods and Once Upon A Mattress, but what about the smaller performances? What about workshops? The Acting Conservatory has been putting on smaller performances called Play Readings. These readings showcase students’ acting abilities in a smaller, less professional setting. The performances are made up of multiple scenes that are acted out by the students.</p>

<p>“We only had two weeks to rehearse so, a very short time,” said Freshman Araceli Prasarttongsoth, who is in the Acting Conservatory and performed in Metamorphosis. Since the rooms normally used for performances, like the cafeteria, were occupied, this play reading took place in room 301 in the music building. Although these performances are not as extensive and well known, they represent the student’s work and their progress in acting. It is important to recognize all the performances CSArts put on, the big and the small. If you are intrigued by these performances, some of their actors are performing them in the upcoming Season Finale for the school. We hope to see you there!</p>]]></content><author><name>Aneira Tamppari</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone has heard about the big musicals like Into The Woods and Once Upon A Mattress, but what about the smaller performances? What about workshops? The Acting Conservatory has been putting on smaller performances called Play Readings. These readings showcase students’ acting abilities in a smaller, less professional setting. The performances are made up of multiple scenes that are acted out by the students.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/small-plays.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/small-plays.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blue or Gold Day?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pocket-calendar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blue or Gold Day?" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pocket-calendar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pocket-calendar/"><![CDATA[<p>You wake up on Monday with one question on your mind: is it a Blue or Gold Day? Keeping track of whether to go to blocks 1-3, or 4-6 can be that one last stressor of the morning.</p>

<p>After 3 years of the struggle, Ada Schmidt (CW ‘25) created a solution to the “Blue Day/Gold Day” problem and created “CSArts Pocket Calendar.” It’s a handy app on your phone which tells you the day’s color. The app is downloadable on the app store on Apple, and Ada is currently working on bringing it to the Android store with the help of Computer Science and English Teacher, Jake Read.</p>

<p>“I finished the Intro Computer Science program early, and Mr. Read suggested I use my time in the class to develop an app that would show what color day it is,” Schmidt said.</p>

<p>In regards to the challenges, Mr. Read said, “I think the hardest thing is to find the problem to solve, or the concept.” Ada said her toughest challenges were with the genuine code. “I didn’t know any Javascript (which is what I used to code the app) so I had to teach myself little by little. It was actually a really helpful learning tactic!”</p>

<p>The app is free, and to all Android users: the CSArtisan will let you know when it is available for you.</p>

<p>iOS users can use the app by downloading it on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/csarts-pocket-calendar/id6738809787">App Store</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kalyan Mukhopadhyay</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You wake up on Monday with one question on your mind: is it a Blue or Gold Day? Keeping track of whether to go to blocks 1-3, or 4-6 can be that one last stressor of the morning.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/pocket-calendar.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/pocket-calendar.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Journey to Jobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/journey-to-jobs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journey to Jobs" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/journey-to-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/journey-to-jobs/"><![CDATA[<p>Many CSArts students are eager to work, whether it’s to gain experience, save money for college, help their families, or look for a source of income before they go out into the world. Before they can legally work, students must fill out and obtain a work permit from their schools. It’s a necessary step to ensure balance with academic and work responsibilities.</p>

<p>Work permits are required for students under 18, in order to protect them under California labor laws. The permits regulate hours, types of jobs, and compliance requirements while safeguarding academic success and well-being. Younger students, under the age of 16, face stricter regulations to prevent job-related exploitation and excessive workloads.</p>

<p>According to paperwork shared by CSArts’ Director of Attendance Monica Bolton, students must “obtain a job first before getting a work permit and have satisfactory grades and attendance records.” Bolton also said that students must be older than 14 and provide the name, address, and phone number of their employer, as well as their supervisors’ name. Processing of the work permit application can take up to a week.</p>

<p>Some students at CSArts aren’t interested in jobs because of the long school hours, distance, and driving restrictions. “I’m not old enough to drive so I can only bike to places. But I’m not going to bike to go super far every single day after conservatory. I can’t really manage that,” Freshman Kalyan Mukhopadhyay said.</p>

<p>Teachers have noticed the stress students are under with academics and their job. “It takes a lot of energy to focus on both working and balancing the studies,” Social Sciences teacher Michael Turf said. Many students, however, are searching for a sense of freedom and cash. “I want a job because I want to experience working and getting my own money,” Freshman Kristina Ghazaryan said. “I also want to contribute to my family’s finances like electricity bills to get a feeling of what it’s like.”</p>

<p>No matter your standpoint with obtaining jobs, knowing our school’s job permit requirements and steps is not only important, it’s the law.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many CSArts students are eager to work, whether it’s to gain experience, save money for college, help their families, or look for a source of income before they go out into the world. Before they can legally work, students must fill out and obtain a work permit from their schools. It’s a necessary step to ensure balance with academic and work responsibilities.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Into the Woods Recap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/into-the-woods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Into the Woods Recap" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/into-the-woods</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/into-the-woods/"><![CDATA[<p>Two girl scouts lost in the woods, classic fairytales with a twist, and a singing wolf?  Into the Woods has it all!  Integrated Arts put on the production in the PAC January 27th to February 1st. The CSArtisan talked to some talented students and the IA director on their thoughts and experiences on bringing this phenomenal show to life.</p>

<p>“A big challenge on stage was during Act II. Cinderella (Sara Fitzrandolph) dislocated her knee, so we had to adjust the blocking,” said Cami Macias (Little Red). “Even with the injury, she gave an amazing performance. It was tough seeing that happen, but I’m so proud of her and grateful to have worked with her.”</p>

<p>Shane Taylor, who performed as the Dance Captain and as an Ensemble member, said his favorite scene to perform was the Prologue of Act I. “I loved being able to do each different dance part, and I liked the music that I was dancing to and the people I was doing it with. We spent a lot of time on that number, and I feel like it has a special place in my heart now.”</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the technical side of the show brought its own set of challenges. Gabriel Ewan, a member of the crew for Woods, said that taking down the beanstalk without being seen was tricky.</p>

<p>Pianist Nicole Lebaron said that playing live music came with its own pressures. “The biggest challenge was handling those little moments when mistakes happened. But overall, the show went really smoothly, and I’m proud of how we pulled everything together!”</p>

<p>IA Director and Producer of Into the Woods, Joey Ancona, shared the vision that brought Into the Woods to life. “While it already has dark elements, we aimed to amplify the atmosphere with more dance, a stronger ‘creepy’ vibe, and an overall immersive experience,” he said. Inspired by Tim Burton, the team incorporated his signature style into every detail from costumes and makeup to hair and set design.</p>

<p>More than just a performance, Ancona hopes the show left a lasting impact on both the cast and audience. “My hope is that the CSArts community eagerly anticipates our IA show each year, knowing it will always be fresh, exciting, and creatively inspiring. They put in so much hard work and formed such a strong bond— there were plenty of tears on closing night,” he shared. “But more than anything, I hope they feel a deep sense of pride in themselves and in their conservatory.”</p>

<p>With yet another unforgettable production, Integrated Arts continues to push creative boundaries and leave audiences in eager anticipation. If Into the Woods proved anything, it’s that the magic of storytelling— combined with passion, talent, and innovation—can make for an unforgettable night at the Performing Arts Center.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two girl scouts lost in the woods, classic fairytales with a twist, and a singing wolf? Into the Woods has it all! Integrated Arts put on the production in the PAC January 27th to February 1st. The CSArtisan talked to some talented students and the IA director on their thoughts and experiences on bringing this phenomenal show to life.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/into-the-woods.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/into-the-woods.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>