<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-27T10:59:50-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Chromebook Creeper or Helper?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/chromebook-creeper-or-helper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chromebook Creeper or Helper?" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/chromebook-creeper-or-helper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/chromebook-creeper-or-helper/"><![CDATA[<p>As schools begin to embrace the digital age, teachers find their own ways to combat distractions and make sure students stay on task.</p>

<p>Imagine, you’re sitting in your English class, writing a long, tedious essay. Leaning back in your chair, you stifle a groan. You feel you’ve worked hard for a solid 30 minutes, and deserve a break. You glance towards your teacher who seems to be paying no mind to what you’re doing, too engrossed in their own matters. You move your cursor across the tabs, switching to one you feel will offer more entertainment, but before you can truly engage with it, you’re met once again with your English essay. Looking back at your teacher, they peer at you with a cunning glare. You know then, with absolute certainty this is none other than the work of GoGuardian.</p>

<p>As of the 2023 school year, CSArts has decided to implement GoGuardian into the classroom. GoGuardian is an educational technology company that allows teachers to monitor their students’ online activity, filter content, and alert school officials of threatening (either to self or other) behaviors on the district owned chromebooks. It is primarily used as a monitoring service to help students stay focused and engaged with their classroom tasks.</p>

<p>Michael Turf, a history teacher at CSArts welcomes the new system into his classroom this year.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s a brand-new system that the school is using and a bit of an adjustment period, but I am happy the school is investing in programs that support students and teachers in the classroom.”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>GoGuardian was brought on board to help with staying focused and provide students with some focus and guidance from these distractive behaviors. Especially teaching AP classes, classroom time is extremely valuable, and GoGuardian allows me to monitor student computer behaviors and provide interventions throughout class time. GoGuardian provides a platform for me to intervene without calling attention to a specific student in front of the Class, ”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Turf.</p>

<p>A student in Ms. Nelson’s class also agrees that GoGuardian can be helpful.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The only teacher that I have that uses it is my Spanish teacher. She uses it all the time so I  think she likes it. I don’t really mind it. It keeps me on track and forces me to do my work.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="not-everyone-is-a-fan">Not Everyone Is A Fan</h3>

<p>While monitoring all students’ screens may make it easier for teachers to intervene, is constant supervision the best route to take? While teachers do think that it is helpful for classroom control, students might not like the idea of being monitored for doing their work.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think it can enhance classroom productivity,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Emma Thompson, an English teacher who decided not to use the monitoring application says,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>but it can also create tension in a classroom.“</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Students had different opinions on the use of GoGuardian.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It used to bother me (especially in elementary school) when I would want to play online games instead of working in class,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One student said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>But now I have to admit it’s good for staying on task and preventing people from cheating during tests,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said one anonymous student. Another student argues that it causes them stress in class, disrupting their work time.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sometimes I feel like I have to pretend that I’m doing my work even though I’m actually doing my work.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/goguardiantable.png" alt="Credit: Karina Hill and Aryhanna Pham" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Hill &amp; Aryhanna Pham</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As schools begin to embrace the digital age, teachers find their own ways to combat distractions and make sure students stay on task.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/goguardian.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/goguardian.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We Have Your Future Covered</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-covered/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Have Your Future Covered" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-covered</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/future-covered/"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how you can make a living with your true passion for art? Whether it is music, acting, singing, writing, dancing, or drawing, CSArts gives you the head start on a career in the arts! Hard work, practice, education, passion, and classes here, are a launching pad to make you a star with your talents. We’ve done the research, and here are some of the careers CSArts prepares you for in the next chapter in your success! You <em>could</em> be a successful:</p>

<h3 id="animator">Animator</h3>

<p>Just imagine seeing your drawings come to life! CSArts will help you create an amazing portfolio of your work! And who knows, maybe one day you could work for Disney!</p>

<h3 id="art-teacher">Art Teacher</h3>

<p>If you love your CSArts teachers, you can be one too! CSArts has some of the best teachers in their specialty areas! Not only will you be teaching something you are passionate about, but you will be preparing the next generation of artists!</p>

<h3 id="makeup-artist">Makeup Artist</h3>

<p>The human face is a canvas and you are the painter! As a makeup artist, you are helping people look their best! Some of those people will be in the entertainment industry. CSArts paves the way for you to be a makeup master in Hollywood!</p>

<h3 id="graphic-designer">Graphic Designer</h3>

<p>Use your skills to combine art and technology into one. You might be the brainchild of a million-dollar advertisement campaign!</p>

<h3 id="actor">Actor</h3>

<p>You go to an arts school in the entertainment capital of the world  Whether it is on stage or the silver screen, CSArts, not only gives you the education, but teachers in the acting conservatory work in entertainment themselves! You’re already ahead of the rest of the world!</p>

<h3 id="music-therapist">Music Therapist</h3>

<p>If you love music and helping people, you found the perfect job. You can use music to help people express their feelings and heal.</p>

<h3 id="sound-engineer">Sound Engineer</h3>

<p>Combining art and technology you will be recording, mixing, and producing music. A musician is only as good as their sound engineer.</p>

<h3 id="music-producer">Music Producer</h3>

<p>You can oversee the process of music projects, arranging each step in the production of music. You will guide musicians with song selections and special projects. It’s your chance to work with your heroes!</p>

<h3 id="music-teacher">Music Teacher</h3>

<p>Imagine being able to help students find their passion for music. You will teach the next generation of musicians vital skills and guide them to be the best they can be!</p>

<h3 id="set-designer">Set Designer</h3>

<p>Wouldn’t it feel amazing to design sets for films, TV shows, and theater productions? CSArts gives you the foundation of skills so that you can watch your set come to life on stage and on screen.</p>

<h3 id="choreographer">Choreographer</h3>

<p>Imagine creating dance routines for concerts, videos, stage, and screen! You design the moves, coach, and critique. Imagine the feeling of watching a dance you designed come to life!</p>

<h3 id="dance-therapist">Dance Therapist</h3>

<p>Dance therapy is becoming more popular with research. This career combines art and healing. Using movement, you will help others express their emotions, and help them heal physically, spiritually, and emotionally.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how you can make a living with your true passion for art? Whether it is music, acting, singing, writing, dancing, or drawing, CSArts gives you the head start on a career in the arts! Hard work, practice, education, passion, and classes here, are a launching pad to make you a star with your talents. We’ve done the research, and here are some of the careers CSArts prepares you for in the next chapter in your success! You could be a successful:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/art-careers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/art-careers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sensors in the Bathrooms</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sensors-in-the-bathrooms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sensors in the Bathrooms" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sensors-in-the-bathrooms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sensors-in-the-bathrooms/"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most talked about, and perhaps most controversial new additions to the CSArts campus, are bathroom sensors. Students and faculty have many questions about the new technology. The CSArtisan talked with CSArts Principal Dr. Gregory Endelman for details what they do, and why they are needed.</p>

<p>First and foremost, students, parents, and  teachers have been pushing for ways to make the campus safe from drugs.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This has actually been an ongoing conversation that really has been led mostly by the students, and then their families. Students in various forms have been reporting that they would like the bathrooms to be drug free.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Last year’s campus-wide lockdown brought student safety into focus.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Some of the students were asking, ‘Can we have a panic button?’ So we looked into a variety of options. And these detection devices were recommended to us,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Endelman said.</p>

<p>The sensors have two main jobs: to pick up on smells and sounds.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They detect chemicals in the air that are associated with tobacco products and marijuana products. It also has the capability to detect certain threats. It’s not recording what students are saying in the bathroom …[but] if there’s something happening in the bathroom that spikes noise, it’s going to alert administration”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Endelman said.</p>

<p>You can thank AI for this new technology.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The way that they are designed, it’s a form of artificial intelligence, and they get hosted by these third parties, through a server. So they’re internet connected. And they do that so they can constantly install updates. But I do suspect that as technology evolves, these things are going to become very, very sophisticated.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This safety net, while keeping the campus safe, is expensive.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Each device itself is about $1,500 … but this is not like … putting batteries in a regular smoke detector. They have to be wired. They have to be linked to the internet, and they have to be hosted. So the installation for the devices run around $30,000- $60,000. It’s a substantial investment. But it’s one of those things that we … think is important,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Endelman said.</p>

<p>While you may not be able to see the sensors, they are installed, working, and adding a new layer of protection on campus.</p>]]></content><author><name>Braedon Younger</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most talked about, and perhaps most controversial new additions to the CSArts campus, are bathroom sensors. Students and faculty have many questions about the new technology. The CSArtisan talked with CSArts Principal Dr. Gregory Endelman for details what they do, and why they are needed.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/sensors-in-the-bathrooms.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/sensors-in-the-bathrooms.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Space for Wellness</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/wellness-center/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Space for Wellness" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/wellness-center</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/wellness-center/"><![CDATA[<p>CSArts is back in session! With new classes, homework, and conservatory activities, it’s important for students to remember self-care.  Luckily, the school has lots of resources available to make sure you are physically and emotionally well! A brand newly designed Wellness Center is in Room 111, and The CSArtisan reached out to Mrs. Alisha Miranda, special services faculty member, to answer some questions about it!</p>

<h3 id="what-resources-does-the-wellness-center-provide-for-students">What resources does the Wellness Center provide for students?</h3>

<p>The Wellness Center, open Monday through Friday from 8:15am-2:15pm, is designed to be a quiet space, where students can relax and decompress for a few minutes. Students are invited to rest or meditate, read, color or draw, use a relaxation or fidget tool, speak with a counselor, practice evidence-based coping strategies, research wellness topics, listen to music, take a walk, stretch/yoga, do guided breathing, and stay for 20 minutes to utilize all of these resources and more.</p>

<h3 id="how-can-students-without-a-504-or-iep-access-the-wellness-center">How can students without a 504 or IEP access the Wellness Center?</h3>

<p>Students MUST have a Wellness Center Pass from their teacher, counselor, or another CSArts staff member in order to be admitted into the Wellness Center. You do not need a pass if you are visiting before school or in between classes.</p>

<h3 id="in-what-situations-would-the-wellness-center-be-of-help-to-a-student">In what situations would the Wellness Center be of help to a student?</h3>

<p>There are various situations that might cause a student to need to utilize the Wellness Center.  For example, panic/anxiety attacks, depression, restlessness, low motivation, mental health disorders, counseling and guidance, general anxiety, meditation, brain break, or loss of focus.</p>

<p>Want to help out? The Wellness Center is accepting donations. To find out more, students and/or guardians can contact Mrs. Miranda via email at alisha.miranda@sgv.csarts.net. And remember, if the day gets too tough, feel free to stop by Room 111 to take a breath for the Wellness Center is open to all.</p>]]></content><author><name>Danica Chen &amp; Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSArts is back in session! With new classes, homework, and conservatory activities, it’s important for students to remember self-care. Luckily, the school has lots of resources available to make sure you are physically and emotionally well! A brand newly designed Wellness Center is in Room 111, and The CSArtisan reached out to Mrs. Alisha Miranda, special services faculty member, to answer some questions about it!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/space-for-wellness.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/space-for-wellness.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vital Tips to Avoid Burnout at CSArts</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/vital-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vital Tips to Avoid Burnout at CSArts" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/vital-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/vital-tips/"><![CDATA[<p>After a sunny and warm fulfilling summer break, students adjust themselves back into their school routines and into the academic and conservatory groove. Our performing arts students prepare themselves for rehearsal’s, while our P&amp;D students begin to work on this year’s showcases. CSArts shows like BCD,  CMD Winter Showcase, IM’s Fall Ensemble Concert, CW’s Open Mic and our Acting showcases will be returning. Plus, you can look forward to  new exciting productions like  MT’s “Ride the Cyclone” IA’s “Mean girls’’, and the Popular Music’s Conservatory first Fall showcase this year. We also can’t forget this year’s all school musical “Floyd Collins”.</p>

<p>All of this excitement takes hours and hours of work. If you are a new student, you will be experiencing long days and deadlines the first time! Here our upperclassmen share some tips on managing the workload and long after- school activities:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When going through a tech week, always be prepared to be doing things! Some may think it’s extra time to be hanging out with your friends, but it’s not. Just be very attentive and friendly to those you’re working with… Don’t be afraid to ask for help and support, most of the time you will get it if you ask! You’ll have fun no matter what, and enjoy it as best you can. Best of luck to you!”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>May Acero (P&amp;D, ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Some tips for doing homework while having rehearsals is getting as much done during the breaks or before rehearsal starts. Then complete anything you can while you have time. Just making the most of what you can with the time you got”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Kayla Rigo (IM, ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Before my first tech week I wished I knew how little sleep you would actually be getting so definitely take time to rest and recharge. Also, I wish I knew that other people are in the same boat as me. We both don’t know the material or where rehearsal will go. You end up making new friends you never thought you would even speak to.”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Ines Arroyo (MT, ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<p>It is all about balance and using time wisely. Remember the importance of eating healthy, keeping hydrated and getting enough sleep.  Understanding what you need and your limits will be keys to success in academics and conservatory.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Gutierrez</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a sunny and warm fulfilling summer break, students adjust themselves back into their school routines and into the academic and conservatory groove. Our performing arts students prepare themselves for rehearsal’s, while our P&amp;D students begin to work on this year’s showcases. CSArts shows like BCD, CMD Winter Showcase, IM’s Fall Ensemble Concert, CW’s Open Mic and our Acting showcases will be returning. Plus, you can look forward to new exciting productions like MT’s “Ride the Cyclone” IA’s “Mean girls’’, and the Popular Music’s Conservatory first Fall showcase this year. We also can’t forget this year’s all school musical “Floyd Collins”.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/vital-tips.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/vital-tips.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts PSAT Cancelled</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/psat-cancelled/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts PSAT Cancelled" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/psat-cancelled</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/psat-cancelled/"><![CDATA[<p>As more colleges and universities shift away from standardized testing for admission criteria, CSArts decided on a shift as well. Part of that decision meant The PSAT was canceled. CSArts administrators and counselors cut the PSAT due to declining student interest and the financial strain it put on the school.</p>

<p>The cancellation has raised concerns by students and parents because the PSAT provides helpful practice for the SAT, and high scores on the practice test can qualify students for merit awards and thousands of dollars in scholarships.</p>

<p>By the time the cancellation was announced and CSArts families started to raise concerns, administrators said that they were, “beyond all of College Board’s deadlines for establishing our school’s PSAT administration, ordering exams, collecting payment, and registering students to test.” This resulted in many students scrambling to find a solution, mostly looking to other local schools. The problem, however, is that many schools don’t allow outside students to take the test.</p>

<p>CSArts is in the process of talking with Duarte Unified to figure out a solution. Duarte Unified has offered to register students and host the PSAT for CSArts students. The details of the deal between CSArts and Duarte are still being worked out.</p>

<p>The CSArtisan asked student counselor, Ms. McMillen, what students could do as an alternative in order to be eligible for scholarships similar to The National Merit Scholarship. McMillen said that students can find other scholarship resources updated monthly on Student Square in the “your counselor section.”</p>

<p>The issues regarding future standardized testing at CSArts and nationally raises important questions regarding the importance of tests for college admissions and the impact on student opportunities. It should also serve as a reminder of the necessity for clear dialogue between administrators and students regarding the changing landscape. Although the PSAT may be less important for college admission, there are still valuable opportunities for students that must be considered.</p>]]></content><author><name>MJ Cho &amp; Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As more colleges and universities shift away from standardized testing for admission criteria, CSArts decided on a shift as well. Part of that decision meant The PSAT was canceled. CSArts administrators and counselors cut the PSAT due to declining student interest and the financial strain it put on the school.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/psat-cancelled.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/psat-cancelled.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Classy Classrooms</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/classy-classrooms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Classy Classrooms" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/classy-classrooms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/classy-classrooms/"><![CDATA[<p>The creative classrooms of CSArts reflect our unique student body. From math classes to Mandarin 1, the academic classes are just as inventive as conservatory courses. Teachers shape their lesson plans to fit their specific goals of the class; it is rare to find two classes that are exactly the same.</p>

<p>The creativity of teachers is apparent in their classrooms. In Room 101, the walls of Mr. Bowman’s classroom are covered with posters, student work, and shelves of mementos.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Keeping someone’s attention for a full ninety minutes can be really difficult. When students start to space out, they can find something in the room that interests them. Wherever they look, there’s something to see,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Mr. Bowman. His classroom is famous for its calm environment, stock of emergency granola bars, and other essential supplies available for all students.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I want it to be a welcoming space; that’s my goal.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Just a few doors down is Mr. Y’s math class in Room 105, where his students try to fill the “mistake counter” by spotting any mistakes in his lesson.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think it keeps them a little sharper and more focused,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Mr. Y.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Every year [the students] get more and more creative with finding math mistakes.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Many of Mr. Y’s students also know of the xylophone in his classroom, which he originally received as a gift.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I thought it was a strange gift, so I thought it’d be even stranger to bring it to school,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>he says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I like to play children’s songs, like the one about the lamb. Someone had a little lamb.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>However, creativity isn’t always shown through physical objects and settings. It can also be shown in the ways teachers manage their classrooms. In Mandarin 1, which is located in Room 401, most of the vocabulary isn’t pre-planned. Instead, the teacher, Nana Yang, asks the students questions such as what they did on their weekend. She translates their response into Mandarin Chinese. This results in a lot of varied vocabulary. She says that she was inspired by how parents used to ask questions to their children to teach them Chinese.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A lot of times the questions are based off of daily life,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>she explained.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So most of [the] topics [we learn in class] are based on real life situations.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mr. Pegan, who teaches Early World History in Room 301, also has an interesting approach to teaching. The questions on his assignments have to do with forming an opinion about the topic, not memorizing historical facts like you would expect.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A lot of highschool math or a lot of highschool history isn’t driven as much by being able to remember names and dates,” he says. “It’s driven by using historical facts to make an argument.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Also, Mr. Pegan doesn’t lecture for most of the class. Instead, he gives the students nearly all of class time to work on assignments. When asked why he made this choice, he said,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Lecture’s a more passive form of teaching. By having you dig in and having to do all the work, you’re the center of the learning.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He added that this also gives him time to answer questions and help students with the assignment.</p>

<p>These are only a few examples of how CSArts is a school where both students and teachers can express their creativity. These teachers choose to make creative or pleasant classrooms all over the CSArts campus, whether this is through aesthetic decorations and physical objects, or the way they manage their classroom. Every teacher gives their students the opportunity to learn and grow in a unique environment.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linnea Venti &amp; Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The creative classrooms of CSArts reflect our unique student body. From math classes to Mandarin 1, the academic classes are just as inventive as conservatory courses. Teachers shape their lesson plans to fit their specific goals of the class; it is rare to find two classes that are exactly the same.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Chat With Counselor Christy</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/counselor-christy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Chat With Counselor Christy" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/counselor-christy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/counselor-christy/"><![CDATA[<p>New schedules, new classes, new teachers, college essays, APs, the list of what a new school year entails goes on and on. It’s scary; it’s stressful; it’s overwhelming, and it’s a lot of work. However, it can be manageable. All it takes is a little bit of guidance, and the making of some good habits. The CSArtisan has the top 4 tips and tricks to have a productive and stress free school year, brought to you by one of CSArts’ very own school counselors, Ms. Christy.</p>

<h3 id="tip-1-make-to-do-lists-and-take-it-one-step-at-a-time">Tip #1: Make to-do lists and take it one step at a time!</h3>

<p>With deadlines approaching and assignments piling up, it can be hard to not get overwhelmed. Sometimes, big to-do lists can be astonishingly long, and so it can be helpful to “prioritize in terms of what’s urgent and most important, and then make a smaller to-do list… starting with little chunks,” Christy says. By separating your to-dos into smaller chunks, breaking it into a more manageable manner, motivation can be boosted, and, “It can make you feel more accomplished and increase focus because you feel like you’re actually getting something done.”</p>

<h3 id="tip-2-use-a-planner-or-other-organizational-tools">Tip #2: Use a planner or other organizational tools!</h3>

<p>With Seniors being faced with the challenging task of college applications, Freshmen still adapting to the ropes of highschool, and other students being thrown into the new schedules and classes that come with starting a new grade, it can be difficult to stay organized. One tip that Ms. Christy has is to “have a blue day and a gold day binder” or a planner to keep the two schedules separated. For Seniors, Christy suggests that “getting organized first is one of the best things that you can do. This is a really great time to get organized because deadlines aren’t quite happening yet.” It can be really helpful to create “Excel sheets, or some kind of organizer or trackers of all the schools that you want to apply to, and then all the upcoming application materials that you need” so that it can all be in the same place.</p>

<h3 id="tip-3-utilize-office-hours">Tip #3: Utilize office hours!</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Utilizing office hours is going to be one of the most helpful things that you can do here at CSArts.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Christy says. With many schools not offering one-on-one time for students to interact with teachers, office hours can be an incredibly helpful tool.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Utilizing even 25 minutes twice a week can be a really great opportunity to get some studying done, rather than waiting till you get home.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="tip-4-take-care-of-yourself-and-dont-forget-to-have-fun">Tip #4: Take care of yourself and don’t forget to have fun!</h3>

<p>Starting a new school year can be stressful and draining for everyone. CSArts requires a lot of hard work and dedication, and the school days are long.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I always recommend making sure to get enough sleep,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Christy says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That’s when our brain grows the most, when you’re of this age.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s also very important to “bring plenty of snacks for conservatory and utilize office hours to get some homework done.” Social aspects are also vital in having a productive and fun school year, and so Ms. Christy suggests getting involved in some of the many clubs at CSArts. Finding other people to bond over similar interests can be really helpful, especially for Freshmen and other new students. Also, don’t forget that you don’t have to sign up to a club right away at Club Rush, you can still join any time!</p>

<p>For more information or advice, contact your school counselor, Ms. Shiroma (grades 9-11, A-F, and grade 12, A-G), Ms. Christy (grades 9-11, G-M, and grade 12, H-O), or Ms. McMillen (grades 9-11, N-Z, and grade 12, P-Z)</p>]]></content><author><name>Juliet Martinez</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[New schedules, new classes, new teachers, college essays, APs, the list of what a new school year entails goes on and on. It’s scary; it’s stressful; it’s overwhelming, and it’s a lot of work. However, it can be manageable. All it takes is a little bit of guidance, and the making of some good habits. The CSArtisan has the top 4 tips and tricks to have a productive and stress free school year, brought to you by one of CSArts’ very own school counselors, Ms. Christy.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Club Rush 2023</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/club-rush-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Club Rush 2023" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/club-rush-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/club-rush-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>With the first few weeks of school starting to settle, student and teacher-run clubs come together to provide opportunities for service hours, experience for college applications and just plain fun! Club Rush was held on campus on September 14th &amp; 15th. </p>

<p>It showcased booths from groups like LUCHA, BSU, to Soccer Club, Swifty Club and even Crochet and Felting Club. If you weren’t on campus or just didn’t have time to get to every booth, don’t worry! You can contact Leadership in room 200 to get in touch with any clubs.</p>

<p>If you want a full comprehensive list, go to student square, where information will be available online about each club. If you go to the “groups” tab on student square, there should be a full page of clubs if you want to see announcements and updates specific to the club you joined. Also, many clubs this year have started a Google Classroom so be on the lookout for an invite!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/club-rush-2023-wordcloud.png" alt="Wordcloud of all student clubs @ Club Rush 2023" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the first few weeks of school starting to settle, student and teacher-run clubs come together to provide opportunities for service hours, experience for college applications and just plain fun! Club Rush was held on campus on September 14th &amp; 15th. ]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/club-rush-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/club-rush-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AP or Dual Enrollment? Which is better?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AP or Dual Enrollment? Which is better?" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment/"><![CDATA[<p>Every spring, students at CSArts debate on whether they’ll take AP courses or Citrus College classes. For some, this debate goes on throughout the summer, and some hope for the best in the fall about their decision. But even after having put in so much thought, is one actually better than the other?</p>

<p>On one hand, AP courses tend to have a higher demand of students interested rather than Citrus classes. This is due to the prestigious look of it on transcripts, as it shows that students were able to challenge themselves throughout their high school careers.</p>

<p>Although even with such advantages, AP courses also have their downfalls; they demand a strong work ethic and resilience. Throughout the year, students are expected to prepare themselves for the final AP exam through countless homework assignments and lengthy tests. This can be hard for CSArts students to manage considering the extra work of conservatory many have to manage, as well as rehearsals and shows to prepare for.</p>

<p>In addition, college credit for these courses is also not always guaranteed. According to the CSArts handbook, students will only receive credit after passing a two to three-hour-long exam. This is a huge deciding factor for most students, considering that if you fail the exam, then you may feel that it was all a huge waste of time and money, since the exams usually cost a certain fee in order to take the test.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Citrus College courses differ between subjects depending on if it is popular during a certain year. The difficulty of these classes ranges depending on the subject.</p>

<p>Overall, Citrus College courses  can be considered to be the “easier” option because of the automatic college credit granted if students pass the class, no matter what. These courses are also free of charge, and are a lot less anxiety-inducing when it comes to exams and credit.</p>

<p>Dual enrollment courses, like AP classes, also offer a GPA boost for students. However, some students seem to dislike the structure of Citrus College classes, considering it isn’t your typical high school class, and while it can be good practice for college, it can be a hard adjustment for some people. Grade formatting isn’t the same as in regular classes, and student and teacher relationships can be hard to establish depending on the class. There are also many student complaints about the Canvas platform used in Citrus classes, due to the confusing structure of grade reports and assignments. Therefore, all aspects of AP courses and Citrus College courses should be taken under consideration before making a decision on which to take.</p>

<p>As students prepare for the upcoming school year, it is also important to hear what their counselors have to say about AP and dual enrollment courses. Counselors will be able to help students take in both pros and cons of the two choices and support them in coming to the best decision.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For students already enrolled in an AP course, it makes sense for them to take the test at the end because you already work so hard the whole year. So, might as well take the exam and see if you can get college credit for it. Although if you are debating between taking an AP course in the fall or a CCC college course, it all depends on the student. Both can give you college credit but dual enrollment is automatic just by passing the class. For the AP courses, you have to pass the exam. So personally, I am biased, and I would lean towards the dual enrollment classes,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Ms. Shiroma, one of the counselors here at CSArts.</p>

<p>Teachers who teach these college level courses are also a great source for more in depth information regarding the course, considering they are highly aware of student habits and common experience among the school population.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The fact that the college credit all comes down to one exam might be stressful for some students. On the other hand, having to focus on preparing for an exam might provide some students with a clearer vision of what they need to do in the class. Of course, both AP and CCC classes are going to have college level work expected… In terms of deciding, it is important to think about whether you want to focus on taking an exam or not. The AP exam is a multi-hour exam, and it will require extra preparation time outside of class. The CCC class doesn’t have that type of all or nothing exam but it does have several writing assignments that are challenging. The courses are just different and one might work better for different students,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Mr. Pegan, who teaches the community college course for US history.</p>

<p>School staff and students have very distinct perspectives on whether or not which course is better, and opinions vary based on your plans for the future and your current circumstances. Students who experience the courses firsthand have a more valuable take on how both courses can affect their academic or social life. Here is what some students had to say about their experiences in both courses:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The dual enrollment classes can sometimes have an exaggerated workload which can interfere with your personal life but in the end, I’d say it is less harsh than AP courses”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Alina Ayala (VA ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Citrus classes tend to be less manageable and more professional, leading it to be more difficult. Although sometimes it can be the better route to go down because AP tests are expensive and it isn’t as important when you’re an underclassman”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Kayla Rigo (IM ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>AP classes are decent as long as you keep up with the work. They also have very helpful benefits if you take advantage of them”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Joann Cruz (VA ‘24)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Emotionally AP classes are overwhelming to a degree, depending on the student. They have their advantages academically but it takes a lot of commitment. Depending on the subject I would take an AP class again”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Maddalena Cano  (VA ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<p>In the end, there is no “perfect” option for every individual. The demands of the classes differ and the factors that come into the decision-making such as testing, course work, and even what one wants in their high school experience. There are pros and cons to both sides, but the best choice is to go with what suits you the best.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jocelin Lila-Cruz</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every spring, students at CSArts debate on whether they’ll take AP courses or Citrus College classes. For some, this debate goes on throughout the summer, and some hope for the best in the fall about their decision. But even after having put in so much thought, is one actually better than the other?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>