<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-19T18:45:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">NHS: The Connection Between Academics And Community</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nhs-the-connection-between-academics-and-community/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NHS: The Connection Between Academics And Community" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nhs-the-connection-between-academics-and-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nhs-the-connection-between-academics-and-community/"><![CDATA[<p>By Salvador</p>

<p>The National Honors Society is a great way to spice up a college application while holding up the core pillars of CSArts. Applicants have learned whether or not they got in last month, and are beginning to add to their service hours.</p>

<p>NHS focuses on its pillars: <em>Leadership</em>, exemplified through taking opportunities. Service, exemplified by the 25 service hours that members complete each semester, <em>Character</em>, demonstrated by following CSArt’s core pillars, finally <em>Scholarship</em>, shown by maintaining a GPA of at least 3.5 GPA.</p>

<p>As for the service hours, many members are part of separate clubs that provide opportunities for service, and the monthly meetings allow members to organize large projects. Michael Turf, the teacher in charge of NHS, also has recommendations about where you can find service hours. “One of the most popular ways students obtain service hours is by peer tutoring. Students work alongside teachers during office hours in tutoring and that counts towards the service hours,” Mr. Turf also recommends using <a href="http://interview.org">[Interview.org]{.underline}</a> to find service opportunities in your area. You can also work through certain conservatories.</p>

<p>Service hours aren’t just for NHS students either. You or anyone you know can collect service hours for college applications. For more information about NHS, check <a href="http://nationalhonorssociety.org">[nationalhonorssociety.org]{.underline}</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Salvador]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lead With Your Type</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lead-wth-your-type/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lead With Your Type" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lead-wth-your-type</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lead-wth-your-type/"><![CDATA[<p>The CSArts-SGV Interact Club is back with its annual blood drive. Held on November 14th in partnership with City of Hope, the drive is an opportunity for students, parents, and faculty to give a gift that truly saves lives.</p>

<p>“Being able to do something that directly benefits cancer patients is very important to me. It’s inspiring to see how CSArts students continue to impact the community, and we hope to see an increase this year,” said Natalie Lanza, president of the Interact Club.</p>

<p>Blood drives are essential in ensuring that patients have the resources they need to continue fighting. Nationwide shortages and declining donor turnout have made donations more valuable than ever.</p>

<p>“It’s a simple act, but can truly make a difference for the patients at City of Hope,” said Francis Fong, Senior Blood Drive Coordinator. “Even in my own life, my son was diagnosed with leukemia when he was just eight years old. Thanks to the treatment he received and the generosity of blood donors, he is now a two-time leukemia survivor and recently celebrated his 25th birthday.”</p>

<p>Appointments can be made by scanning the QR codes posted around campus. Walk-ins are also accepted. Donors must be at least 16 years of age, weigh a minimum of 110 pounds, provide a valid photo ID, and be in good health.</p>

<p><strong><em>Give hope, it’s in your blood.</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSArts-SGV Interact Club is back with its annual blood drive. Held on November 14th in partnership with City of Hope, the drive is an opportunity for students, parents, and faculty to give a gift that truly saves lives.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/lead-with-your-type.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/lead-with-your-type.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tribute to Jane Goodall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tribute-to-jane-goodall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tribute to Jane Goodall" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tribute-to-jane-goodall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tribute-to-jane-goodall/"><![CDATA[<p>1934-2025</p>

<p>There are few people in the world who have penetrated the public consciousness like Jane Goodall has. When she died, it sent a shock wave through the hearts of every person that learned about her brave work. I want to pay tribute to Jane Goodall and all the good she did for the Earth, and what her life encourages us to do.</p>

<p>Jane Goodall first came into the public consciousness in 1963 when National Geographic published a groundbreaking article on her work studying Chimpaneeze’s. Her research on prime apes widened our understanding of our genetic siblings, and brought us closer to understanding our origin more than ever. Jane Goodall would continue working with Chimpaneeze’s for the rest of her life, becoming the official ambassador for chimpanzees all around the world. In her later years, she would go to classrooms all around the world to educate kids on our place in the world and the ways we can protect it.</p>

<p>Creative Writing Instructor and minister of Unitarian Universalist Congregation Fullerton, Robert Blair, delivered a sermon dedicated to Jane Goodall and the Legacy she left behind.</p>

<p>“The woman in her nine decades made so many changes in people's hearts and minds and spirits regarding the animal population, and how we humans have damaged and destroyed much of their living spaces and the environment that they lived in. She is prophetic in the way that she guided a young population mainly, to understand what we have done and how to make things right.”</p>

<p>I wanted to know why she was such a presence in our modern society, and why people loved her so much, and Mr. Blair gave me a goldmine:</p>

<p>“She spoke languages between species, and spoke languages between generations,” Mr. Blair then goes on to talk about the last thing she did in life, which hit close to home. “She died in Pasadena on October 1st, getting ready to plant trees in Altadena because of the fire and getting ready to do her part with younger people, to try and correct what had been done.”</p>

<p>Jane Goodall will always stand in our hearts as a figure of grace, exploration, and valor and a symbol for the good a single person can do. Rest in Peace.</p>]]></content><author><name>James Okon</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1934-2025]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/jane-goodall.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/jane-goodall.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Spotlight: Julia Trinh</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-julia-trinh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Spotlight: Julia Trinh" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-julia-trinh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/student-spotlight-julia-trinh/"><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kat Bartholomaus</p>

<p><strong>Julia Trinh: A Student Spotlight</strong></p>

<p>Once the Friday school bell rings, most students can’t wait to get home, take a nice warm shower, and nap through the whole weekend. For sophomore Julia Trinh, that’s far from normal. Trinh spends her free time educating young minds and volunteering at hospitals, speaking about the dangers of drug use and teaching Sex Ed in a safe manner. As a former foster kid, Trinh shared that her passion for volunteering came from her family history, a family member she watched walk down the wrong path and got involved in drug use. Trinh spoke about her volunteering work and the type of work they put in.</p>

<p><strong>What is your main goal for your extracurricular activities?</strong></p>

<p>“Well, I fall under three categories: legislative, school policies, and restorative practice, which is a kind of harm reduction. That’s where I teach people about Fentanyl, overdosage, and narcan. And then I also sex education. But my goal is just to educate everyone on my topics that I work on and hopefully to make a better place.”</p>

<p><strong>What or who got you started in your activities?</strong></p>

<p>“I think, myself, but for mostly harm reduction, which is what I mostly deal with. I would say when the family member did substances when I was younger. I saw the effects of what had happened and I wanted to make sure another family doesn’t have to go through that. Or at least, like, know how to go through it properly and get them treatment. And then for legislative work, this world is a little tough with the laws and stuff, and I think it needs to be fixed.”</p>

<p><strong>What’s your favorite thing about these activities?</strong></p>

<p>“I think my favorite activity within these is meeting new people all over Los Angeles County. We really get to see a bunch of different aspects of lids within LA, especially since I think we all know LA’s a very vast community and I think getting to see that personally is really interesting. And going to different places all around is really fun. I get to see new things and meet new people. So I think it’s really nice to meet new people and then really use their experience and use that for good.”</p>

<p><strong>On average, how long do you spend time volunteering?</strong></p>

<p>“I would say at least five hours a week.”</p>

<p><strong>Where do you tend to volunteer?</strong></p>

<p><strong>“</strong>I work at, I kinda work cause I do get paid for it, Reach LA, which is a LGBTQ-BIPOC nonprofit in downtown Los Angeles and that’s where I do my Sex Education and legislative. Then Children’s Hospital Los Angeles, with the collective of theaters, where I do my harm reduction. So yeah, it’s mostly there.”</p>

<p><strong>What would you want to say to somebody who wants to get into this field?</strong></p>

<p>“I’d say building a network is very important. That’s how I go to so many places. And work on public speaking cause that’s a very critical component. Also, depending on what you do, like what I do, making presentations. It’s also just about having a heart and understanding. Personally, I don’t think you should do it for any college things. It’s a very personal work so I think you are made for it, but sometimes it need to be found.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Written by Kat Bartholomaus]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/student-spotlight-julia-trinh.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/student-spotlight-julia-trinh.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Terracotta Warriors: Appreciation of Culture</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jessica-pang-terracotta-warriors-appreciation-of-culture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terracotta Warriors: Appreciation of Culture" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jessica-pang-terracotta-warriors-appreciation-of-culture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jessica-pang-terracotta-warriors-appreciation-of-culture/"><![CDATA[<p>A recent visit to a museum introduces students to part of a Chinese army of warriors, as a result of joint efforts between school personnel, the museum, and a private organization.</p>

<p>On Saturday, October 11th, a group of CSArts students, parents, and teachers visited the Bower’s Museum in Santa Ana on a mission: to see the Terracotta Warriors in person. The terracotta warriors are an army of an estimated eight thousand unique statues, built by the first emperor of China Qin Shi Huang over 2,000 years ago to protect his belongings from tomb robbers. Of these eight thousand, the Bower’s museum had five on display–the third ever time they have been displayed in southern California.</p>

<p>It all started with an email. According to Nana Yang, the Mandarin teacher at CSArts, the chairman of the Chinese American Federation (CAF), Fei Pang, emailed her with the offer of free tickets to the Terracotta Warrior exhibition at Bower’s Museum. Yang, knowing how important Chinese history is to the Chinese AP exam, accepted almost instantly.</p>

<p>The trip was split into two parts, including a guided tour of the exhibit, and a crafting activity where visitors had the opportunity to make their own miniature terracotta warriors out of clay.</p>

<p>During the tour, the guide in particular stood out to Yang. “She started her presentation to introduce herself with her connection with China and her understanding of Chinese culture,” says Yang, appreciating the tour guide’s traditional Chinese robes.</p>

<p>But Yang says the crafting activity was even better. “That was my favorite part of the tour– the museum visit,” says Yang. The differences in the handmade student terracotta warriors show how each student views the Terracotta Warriors– and, on a broader level, Chinese history. Yang hopes that this trip has shown her students, even at a beginner level, an exploration of Chinese history, and she hopes that they are able to explore it with an open mind.</p>

<p>To Yang, the most valuable part of the visit was the connections built between the people who attended– students, parents, grandparents, teachers, and CAF members, all coming together to learn Chinese history and culture. However intangible, a bond, a connection is built, with a mutual appreciation for two thousand year-old culture.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jessica Pang</name></author><category term="academics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent visit to a museum introduces students to part of a Chinese army of warriors, as a result of joint efforts between school personnel, the museum, and a private organization.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of Mexican American Music - Part 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of Mexican American Music - Part 3" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history-of-mexican-american-music-3/"><![CDATA[<p>The 1980s and 1990s saw Mexican American musicians break through into a variety of popular music genres in ways past generations had not. Some of the biggest artists of the era were Rage Against the Machine, Selena, Linda Ronstadt, and Ozomatli. All of whom built on the foundations of artists who had come before them. Mexican American musicians were truly mainstream. Linda Ronstadt, whose career began in the sixties as a folk singer, made the cover of Rolling Stone Magazine as a rock singer. It is challenging to characterize this era with a single sound or type of artist. Ozomatli was a funk band, Selena was the Queen of Tejano music, and Rage Against the Machine was a multi-style band with politically charged lyrics. Funny enough, the different styles of these musicians are in direct relation to artists of the past. At this stage of history, a throughline can be seen from past artists. In this article, I aim to highlight these artists and reflect on their impact on shaping the traditions of Mexican American Music.</p>

<p>Linda Ronstadt, discussed in the previous article, was a popular mainstream artist well into the 1980s. She was a rock singer who was not known for her Mexican American heritage, similar to Riche Valens. However, in the late 1980s, she won numerous awards by finally embracing her Mexican American heritage and releasing an album in Spanish, “Canciones de Mi Padre”. She spoke of the difficulty of getting her record label to agree to produce the album. Ronstandt fought to have it released, as it honored her father and the music she grew up listening to on her family’s ranch. She described making the album as a vital part of her artistic journey. </p>

<p>Rage Against the Machine, although not being an entirely Mexican American band, had a lead singer who was mixed-race and proud of his Mexican American heritage. The band even released a track called “People of the Sun” about Mexicans. Rage Against the Machine, being a multi-styled musical band, can be seen as an evolution of the Zeros and their style of music, as well as their strong ties to Los Angeles. Ozmatlie has a similar relation to their predecessors. In many ways, Ozmatlie does have its own unique blend of jazz and even hip hop; however, it does share similarities with past Mexican American Funk Bands, like El Chicano. Ozamtlie builds upon the foundation set by El Chicano, creating a genre-defying sound.</p>

<p>Selena is perhaps the most interesting and direct connection to Mexican American musicians of the past. She was a tejano artist who was considered equally as popular in the U.S. as she was in Mexico. Her fame was wide, and her music was classic. A strong comparison can be drawn between her and the artist, Lydia Mendoza. Selena was often referred to as the Queen of Tejano music, while Mendoza was believed to be the first queen of Tejano music and a pioneer of the style. Selena played a big role in popularizing the genre. Both artists also had the unique ability to capture audiences in both the U.S. and Mexico. </p>

<p>The 80s-90s were a time of modernizing tradition and building upon the legacies of those who came before. The artists of the 90s found mainstream fame and perfected genres of the past. Without this generation, the explosion of modern Mexican music in the modern era would not have occurred.</p>]]></content><author><name>Henry Soderlind</name></author><category term="history" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 1980s and 1990s saw Mexican American musicians break through into a variety of popular music genres in ways past generations had not. Some of the biggest artists of the era were Rage Against the Machine, Selena, Linda Ronstadt, and Ozomatli. All of whom built on the foundations of artists who had come before them. Mexican American musicians were truly mainstream. Linda Ronstadt, whose career began in the sixties as a folk singer, made the cover of Rolling Stone Magazine as a rock singer. It is challenging to characterize this era with a single sound or type of artist. Ozomatli was a funk band, Selena was the Queen of Tejano music, and Rage Against the Machine was a multi-style band with politically charged lyrics. Funny enough, the different styles of these musicians are in direct relation to artists of the past. At this stage of history, a throughline can be seen from past artists. In this article, I aim to highlight these artists and reflect on their impact on shaping the traditions of Mexican American Music.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mexican-american-music-3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/mexican-american-music-3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Community Under New Leadership</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/community-under-new-leadership/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Community Under New Leadership" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/community-under-new-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/community-under-new-leadership/"><![CDATA[<p>“Wherever art is going in the world, we should be able to provide that for our students,” says Allison Hennessey, the new assistant principal of the arts at CSArts. With that philosophy in mind, she is stepping into the role with a vision to inspire both students and teachers alike.</p>

<p>Hennessey has been with CSArts since the school first opened in 2017. She was the Chair of the Dance Conservatory. Even after her move to Ohio, she stayed with the school. With Dr. Cook’s resignation as Assistant Principal of the Arts, she decided to apply for the open position.</p>

<p>With a strong foundation in dance, she emphasizes that leadership isn’t about controlling every corner of the arts program, but about trusting the experts who surround her. “I believe in supporting people so they can flourish in what they do,” she said, explaining that trusting each director to lead their programs is central to her approach.</p>

<p>“Sometimes with growth, there also needs to be a moment of settling into them…and really fulfilling what we already have,” Hennessey said. With the addition of the Popular Music Conservatory and the 6th-grade program, the school is allowing some time for easing into those expansions. So, we won’t be seeing any drastic changes made to the Conservatories. Instead, she and her team will focus on improving current conservatories and on supporting Conservatory directors and teachers to provide the best programs for students.</p>

<p>As she steps into her new role, her goal remains clear: to strengthen a community where every artist, teacher, and student can thrive.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mariam Ghazaryan</name></author><category term="student-life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Wherever art is going in the world, we should be able to provide that for our students,” says Allison Hennessey, the new assistant principal of the arts at CSArts. With that philosophy in mind, she is stepping into the role with a vision to inspire both students and teachers alike.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/community-under-new-leadership.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/community-under-new-leadership.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clumsy Critters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/clumsy-critters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clumsy Critters" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/clumsy-critters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/clumsy-critters/"><![CDATA[<p>The flitter-flap of red webbed wings carry emerald critters around the campus, knocking into walls and trying to find a safe place to land. Sometimes these landing pads just so happen to be your hair and stylish clothes. These emerald critters are flying blind, crashing about and spooking onlookers who are rushing to class or enjoying a nice chat at lunchtime.</p>

<p>These little critters are known as June bugs because it’s their most active month of the year. Adult junebugs emerge from the soil nearing the end of spring, typically May and June, greeting the transition into Summer weather. June bugs spend most of their life underground and the warmer weather and longer days activate their muscles. Most of the time, junebugs are just trying to find a nice warm place to reproduce. They may unintentionally fly into your path but these green beetles mean no harm. Their diet includes almonds, strawberries, sugar cane, roses, potatoes, and corn, which can bother farmers who grow these crops. These bugs are exploring the world but are simply blind and aren’t trying to crash land into you.</p>

<p>If you ever feel frightened by these small little fliers, remember that they are exploring the world just like you. Remember two important things, Junebugs are blind and they are harmless.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="campus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The flitter-flap of red webbed wings carry emerald critters around the campus, knocking into walls and trying to find a safe place to land. Sometimes these landing pads just so happen to be your hair and stylish clothes. These emerald critters are flying blind, crashing about and spooking onlookers who are rushing to class or enjoying a nice chat at lunchtime.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Campus Cockroaches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/campus-cockroaches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Campus Cockroaches" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/campus-cockroaches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/campus-cockroaches/"><![CDATA[<p>In October, roaches infested some classrooms and areas on campus, leaving many students with creepy-crawly feelings.</p>

<p>The roaches were mostly around the 200s, the Quad, and the cafeteria. Principal of Academics Nicole Read said that the rain and then the pipe burst probably “forced” them out of underground plumbing.</p>

<p>Exterminators spray insecticide on campus once every few weeks. Last month, they sprayed several times in one week. “They did it over three small doses,” Ms. Read said. “We have to be careful not to overdo it in order to protect our students since insecticides can be powerful chemical agents.” The school also has to follow state environmental restrictions for pesticides.</p>

<p>Cockroaches are not aggressive. “While cockroaches can certainly be gross and scary, they will not hurt you,” said Ms. Read. However, an infestation of roaches can cause harm. According to the EPA, (Environmental Protection Agency), roaches can trigger asthma attacks or carry bacteria like [salmonella, staphylococcus and streptococcus.]{.mark}</p>

<p>Ms. Read encourages students to keep reporting the roaches to administration.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="campus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October, roaches infested some classrooms and areas on campus, leaving many students with creepy-crawly feelings.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/campus-cockroaches.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/campus-cockroaches.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Absolute Twist: DC’s Comic Series</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/an-absolute-twist-dc-s-most-unique-comic-series/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Absolute Twist: DC’s Comic Series" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/an-absolute-twist-dc%E2%80%99s-most-unique-comic-series</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/an-absolute-twist-dc-s-most-unique-comic-series/"><![CDATA[<p>In October 2024, DC introduced a new series called the Absolute Universe written by Scott Snyder. This universe takes the stories of the classic heroes we know and love, and flips them right on their back. Following the death of Darkseid in DC All In, the “Elseworld” or the “Alpha World” was formed from the despair and negative energy that he released. This directly opposes the main world, Earth 0, which contains hope and justice at its core. Darkseid’s soul cursed the Elseworld, giving the usual characters in DC different stories.</p>

<p>Absolute Batman, for one, isn’t rich like in the original universe. Instead, he’s a lower class man depicted with multiple different jobs, one of which being a construction worker. This reimagination highlights the intelligence of Bruce Wayne by showing his capabilities in different circumstances and not just when he’s wealthy. When he was a child, his dad was killed in a shooting at the Gotham zoo, leaving his mom as a single mother and taking away from the "nothing to lose” aspect of the original Batman.</p>

<p>Another example is Absolute Superman, who instead of being sent to Earth as a baby, was sent to Earth as a young boy. Kal-el’s connection to Krypton separates him from the human aspect of the original Superman, creating the biggest difference between the two: a lack of his alter-ego Clark Kent. Kal-el is guided by his suit which contains Kryptonian artificial intelligence, and actively seeks perpetrators of social injustice and oppression parallel to his parents’ past efforts to save Krypton from corruption. This Superman is in his teens, making the change from Krypton to Earth more recent and causing him to be much more angry and emotional than the original.</p>

<p>Superman enthusiast Noah Johnson, who is an Integrated Arts senior at CSArts, expresses how he’s yet to read Absolute Superman due to hesitance over the major changes. Although a fan of Superman and the Absolute series altogether, he shares a concern on the adaptations of the character and says, “I still prefer normal Superman because of what he symbolizes”. Nevertheless, Noah approves of the new storylines saying, “Whoever is coming up with this stuff deserves a raise.” Another senior at CSArts, Kayden Hicks, also shows an appreciation for the differences in the Absolute series. “I think it’s the most creative thing they’ve done in a couple years,” he says, “there’s been many spins on characters like Batman, but this one feels special.” Kayden highly recommends Absolute Batman, and says that despite his preference in the Marvel universe, it piqued his interest.</p>

<p>There are many more characters depicted in the Absolute series from heroes to villains. Other popular favorites include Absolute Wonder Woman, Absolute Flash, and Absolute Martian Manhunter. DC fan or not, this series is a gamechanger from the well-known narratives and could be a good read for any superhero fans.</p>]]></content><author><name>Miranda Cervantes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October 2024, DC introduced a new series called the Absolute Universe written by Scott Snyder. This universe takes the stories of the classic heroes we know and love, and flips them right on their back. Following the death of Darkseid in DC All In, the “Elseworld” or the “Alpha World” was formed from the despair and negative energy that he released. This directly opposes the main world, Earth 0, which contains hope and justice at its core. Darkseid’s soul cursed the Elseworld, giving the usual characters in DC different stories.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/dcs-absolute-universe.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/dcs-absolute-universe.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>