<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-25T12:46:09-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Senior VA Art Showcase</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-senior-showcase/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Senior VA Art Showcase" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-senior-showcase</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-senior-showcase/"><![CDATA[<p>On May 6th, the cafeteria at CSArts was transformed into an art gallery, as the seniors of the Visual Arts Conservatory held their final showcase, exhibiting their best works that they have created throughout this year and their time at CSArts. From ceramics to acrylic paint, to even mixed media, the seniors were able to discuss their work with others and their artistic journey, and what the future has in store for them as this school year comes to a close.</p>

<p>When it came to actually selecting the work they wanted to display, the seniors debated on the pieces they were most proud of.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I knew that I wanted to showcase work from different years that I’ve been at CSArts,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Rosie Williams (VA ‘23)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I was able to pull things from a few different places and I’m really happy with how it came out! I found a piece in my garage from my sophomore year that I completely forgot about and I am really glad that I was able to put that in there.”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The process of selecting works for the exhibition for me was mainly just looking through all of my sketchbooks and art pieces and deciding which of them would go with the vibe I wanted. It also included a lot of ignoring insecurities and putting pieces up regardless because you are trying to get over those struggles among your own art,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Aria King (VA ‘23)</p>

<p>When asked about her favorite piece on display, Rosie said,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My proudest piece is the portrait series I did of my bestie Aria. We were asked to practice portraits from different angles in our anatomy drawing class, and we chose to draw each other! I spent a lot of time on these drawings and I’m really proud of them. plus they actually look like her!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For Aria, her favorite work revolved around the medium she chose to create it from.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think my favorite piece that I put up was one of the portraits I did of Patti Smith just because I got better at using gouache through it and I just liked the way it turned out,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>she said.</p>

<p>Since this exhibition is the last show these seniors will experience in their high school career, there is an abundance of emotions felt for this event.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This exhibition means the closing of a chapter for me. I was at the same school for eight years before coming here, so four years went by like nothing. I’ve been able to learn so much about myself and about the world in the short time that I’ve been here, and I’m so lucky to have shared this journey with such amazing people. This is the first exhibition that I’ve truly been proud of, both in the art that’s up there and in what it symbolizes for me, and it’s really an embodiment of the work we’ve done together,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Rosie.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think that what the exhibition meant to me was a celebration of the art that every senior has made and the fact that we have grown up, learned, and made mistakes, but we all have our own ways of expressing ourselves. It’s a celebration of similarities and differences among our collective creative energies.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Aria.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>After the exhibition ended, I just felt really bittersweet, things are ending and some of the people I have come to know over the last four years I will never see again. It’s very much a feeling of joy that it took place, but also feeling how temporary it all is. It’s a very sad and happy state to be in.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One thing is for certain, that no matter where these seniors go in the future, their hard work and dedication deserves to be appreciated and celebrated. Some of their artwork is still on display in the entrance, so be sure to stop by!</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Brunet</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 6th, the cafeteria at CSArts was transformed into an art gallery, as the seniors of the Visual Arts Conservatory held their final showcase, exhibiting their best works that they have created throughout this year and their time at CSArts. From ceramics to acrylic paint, to even mixed media, the seniors were able to discuss their work with others and their artistic journey, and what the future has in store for them as this school year comes to a close.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/VA-senior-showcase.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/VA-senior-showcase.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">School Spirit Shenanigans</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/school-spirit-shenanigans/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School Spirit Shenanigans" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/school-spirit-shenanigans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/school-spirit-shenanigans/"><![CDATA[<p>From our haunting Halloweens to our crazy contests, there’s no denying that at CSArts, festivities are beyond fantastic. As we approach the end of the school year, there’s no better time than the present to reflect on the spirited shenanigans that CSArts gets up to when spirit days roll around.</p>

<p>Halloween this year, as always, transformed our beloved campus into a perfectly spooky-themed hauntfest! With a wide assortment of spooky and hilarious costumes, it’s safe to say that CSArts goes above and beyond for Halloween.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/sss1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Source: Sidney Tsai</p>

<p>Highlighting the many diverse and culturally rich backgrounds from which many of us hail, the Taste of CSArts festival treated everyone to a wide variety of aromas and flavors, each unique and delicious in their own way!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/sss2.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Source: Sidney Tsai</p>

<p>Last but not least, Homecoming: a day to remember, preceded by a week of cross-class fun and pep!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/sss3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Source: CSArts-SGV Facebook</p>

<p>Each special event celebrated our heart for the arts, our strength in diversity, and the immense talent of our student body.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sidney Tsai</name></author><category term="events" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From our haunting Halloweens to our crazy contests, there’s no denying that at CSArts, festivities are beyond fantastic. As we approach the end of the school year, there’s no better time than the present to reflect on the spirited shenanigans that CSArts gets up to when spirit days roll around.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/school-spirit-shenanigans.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/school-spirit-shenanigans.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Thank You Class Presidents!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/thank-you-class-presidents/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank You Class Presidents!" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/thank-you-class-presidents</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/thank-you-class-presidents/"><![CDATA[<p>As the school year comes to an end, it’s important to recognize some people who helped us make this year so fun. Our co-class presidents took it upon themselves to not only take on the responsibility of being a voice for us students, but giving us a memorable school year. From cocoa and cram sessions, to senior sunrise, the class presidents put in the work! Here are some of their personal highlights of the year:</p>

<h3 id="a-message-from-one-of-your-class-of-2023-co-presidents">A message from one of your Class of 2023 co-presidents:</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>A highlight from this year was definitely our Senior Sunrise! We had so much fun coming together as a class, especially with the knowledge that we would gather once more for Senior Sunset, months later. The best part of being class presidents is getting to put ideas into action. We usually start with, “Wouldn’t it be cool if…?” and then we get to see those ideas come to fruition! For Halloween, we wanted to do something of our own for the school, so we had seniors drive their cars onto the field and host games out of the trunks. Executing ideas is exhilarating because it’s like seeing your Pinterest board brought to life! Class of 2023, you are amazing. You are strong and persistent in the face of opposition, and now that the work is done, we can’t wait for the best Grad Week ever. To the underclassmen/almost-seniors, our advice is to appreciate your fellow students’ work. One day, you’ll be leaving, and you’ll wish you saw the All School Musical  or watched the IM Jazz Ensemble, or spent more time observing the Visual Art showcases. Not everyone is surrounded by so much art and talent in high school, so take advantage of the opportunities you have now to watch that person you sit next to in math belt their face off, because one day they might be on Broadway (and those tickets will be much more expensive)”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Bella Chang and Tati Bovia (IA ‘23)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="a-message-from-one-of-your-class-of-2024-co-presidents">A message from one of your Class of 2024 co-presidents:</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Some of my favorite parts about being class president this year have been planning events, getting to add to the CSArts culture and work on school involvement, and really just being the voice of the junior class. One of my most memorable experiences this year has definitely been Junior Campout which my co-president and I planned and advertised for months. It was so rewarding seeing all of our hard work pay off at the event! My current co-president and I will be running for senior class president and hope that everything we have done this year has prepared us for next year. To the class of 2024, good luck with working on college applications within the next 6 months, and keep pushing through! We got this!”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Hannah Pung (BCD ‘24)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="a-message-from-one-of-your-class-of-2025-co-presidents">A message from one of your Class of 2025 co-presidents:</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>My favorite part about being this year’s class president is honestly wearing the maid dress after getting elected. As well as just being able to represent your class is really nice. My advice to any future presidents is that it’s important to be yourself and to do it all for your class and not yourself, have fun too! And I’d just like to say that the Class of 2025 is honestly the best class!”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Giovanni Huang (P&amp;D ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="a-message-from-your-class-of-2026-co-presidents">A message from your Class of 2026 co-presidents:</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was a bit difficult to learn how to manage to fit in time for planning and discussion into a jam-packed schedule. Our favorite moment from the year was the first pep rally of the year. We loved seeing everyone so determined and working together on the games. Most importantly, cheering for our fellow classmates was really nice to be a part of. As for advice to future presidents, iron out your schedule for the year, sit down and review your calendar with your partner, and plan! Myself and Zakai have loved building relationships with the class; learning about each and every one of you has been amazing. We are going to finish the year strong with Clash of Classes and run head first into sophomore year!!!”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Francis Fontana (MT ‘26) and Zakai Haynes (MT ‘26)</li>
</ul>

<p>The CSArtisan sends out a special thank you to all of our class presidents for their hard work and dedication! As for the next school year, there are many different presidential campaigns running this month with amazing candidates running to earn the spot as class presidents. So, make sure to cast your vote for the next co-class presidents as soon as you can!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jocelin Lila-Cruz</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the school year comes to an end, it’s important to recognize some people who helped us make this year so fun. Our co-class presidents took it upon themselves to not only take on the responsibility of being a voice for us students, but giving us a memorable school year. From cocoa and cram sessions, to senior sunrise, the class presidents put in the work! Here are some of their personal highlights of the year:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/10.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/10.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">So Long, Sugarpine!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/so-long-sugarpine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So Long, Sugarpine!" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/so-long-sugarpine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/so-long-sugarpine/"><![CDATA[<p>Every year, the CSArts conservatory closes the season with a showcase highlighting their artistic abilities, whether it be performances or galleries. Among the flurry of end-of-the-year recitals and art exhibitions, the Creative Writing Conservatory quietly says goodbye through their respective niche: in the pages of a book.</p>

<p>Sugar Pine Literary Magazine is CSArts’s official literary magazine, operated and edited by Creative Writing Conservatory students. Sugar Pine is a collaborative effort that allows students in each conservatory to express themselves without the confines of artistic factions. Every year, students are encouraged to submit their creative works, ranging from paintings, short stories, and poetry, to photography of any subject, spanning from dancers to set designs.</p>

<p>My experience with Sugar Pine began in ninth grade. I went in not knowing much about the class I had signed up for, but excited at the promise that I would get to assist in creating a published piece of work. My naivety was a blessing because I experienced Sugar Pine without expectations, receiving an honest look into what made our magazine so special. Typically dominated by seniors, Sugar Pine is almost always intimidating for younger students. For me, being around more experienced peers was intimidating; however, once I saw how welcoming and helpful they were, I quickly became infatuated with the dedication of a team as spectacular as the Sugar Pine staff. The staff operates with the utmost respect and care for each other, collaborating and discussing frequently to create a beautiful result.</p>

<p>I am now a senior, and I have had the honor of being a prose team editor, facilitating group discussions and working with fellow editors to organize each submission into a beautiful magazine. As I prepare to graduate in a few weeks, my heart is filled with memories from my four years at CSArts, and I am forever grateful that the Sugar Pine family fills the bulk of that space. Sugar Pine has been the highlight of my high school experience, and I hope it can recreate that same sense of fulfillment for future creative writing students and aspiring editors.</p>

<p>As thrilling and dynamic as room 210’s editorial space is, none of our beloved magazines could have been possible without the excellent guidance of Sugar Pine’s faculty advisor, Mrs. Estella Ramirez. An endless source of support and positivity for every student involved, Mrs. Ramirez’s dedication toward her students—and Sugar Pine as a whole—made the experience gratifying. This year was Mrs. Ramirez’s last as the advisor for Sugar Pine and there’s no denying she and every student working on the magazine put in the effort to make Volume 6 the best, most beautiful issue yet. On behalf of all Sugar Pine staff, past and present, we extend our gratitude to Mrs. Ramirez for her kindness, encouragement, and compassion throughout our journeys in the conservatory. You have left a lasting impact on every student in the Creative Writing Conservatory in such an impactful, memorable way, and we are all filled with gratitude for the years we’ve spent under your wings.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sevana Zadoian</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every year, the CSArts conservatory closes the season with a showcase highlighting their artistic abilities, whether it be performances or galleries. Among the flurry of end-of-the-year recitals and art exhibitions, the Creative Writing Conservatory quietly says goodbye through their respective niche: in the pages of a book.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Memories with Mr. Blaylock</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/mr-blaylock/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Memories with Mr. Blaylock" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/mr-blaylock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/mr-blaylock/"><![CDATA[<p>Mr. Blaylock embodies all that is good about our school. His positive energy, boundless enthusiasm, deep commitment to excellence, endless creativity, and heart-felt dedication to his students all reflect the best possible qualities of a director of a program at an arts school.</p>

<p>Commitment to the development of students’ artistic talents is in Mr. Blaylock’s DNA. His father, James Blaylock, started the creative writing program at OCSOA. Both programs are modeled after graduate-level Masters of Fine Arts programs, and their depth and breadth are incredibly impressive. There are few programs like it in the entire country.</p>

<p>The creative writing curriculum developed by Mr. Blaylock has exposed students to a wide variety of writing styles over the course of the program. He brought in a wide array of writers for our master classes. He developed a relationship with Citrus College so that we could have access to college-level conservatory classes. He helped us produce an amazing literary magazine, Sugarpine, every year. Mr. Blaylock developed creative writing classes that served needs in the community– the Creative Nonfiction class connected students with their elders at a local senior center, and the Theatre for Young Audiences course introduced students to elementary school students. Open-mic nights gave students the opportunity to share their work with others, not just at school, but at Vroman’s Bookstore in Pasadena.</p>

<p>Mr. Blaylock has been loved by not only the creative writing conservatory students– he has fans from every other conservatory on campus. This is no accident.  Mr. Blaylock has always been very intentional about reaching across conservatory lines, as is evidenced in the mini-musicals program and the Peter Pan class.</p>

<p>Students have been eager to share their fondest memories of Mr. Blaylock. One of Levvy Butler’s (CW ‘25) fondest memories with him took place after school,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I came in to talk to him about something he was working on and he explained it to me, and I didn’t feel like I was being talked down to at all. He mentioned a part that he was struggling to figure out, and it was really cool to see that he was a normal person who was looking for solutions to things in his writing, the same as me.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Julia Pilch (CW ‘24) loved hearing about Mr. Blaylock’s childhood stories. One of her favorite ones was when he was talking about Mr. Fish, a character he made up.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>He and his friends had passes to Disneyland and one summer they would go around saying “vote for Mr. Fish!” and then all of the workers would be confused. But eventually, all of the workers recognized him and would do a fishlike motion when he walked by.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sevana Zadoian’s (CW ‘23) favorite memory was the senior showcase she and her classmates put on,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>He worked really hard to give us the best possible experience and send off in our last year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Samantha Thomas’s (CW ‘24) favorite memory of Mr. Blaylock was one of his classes–</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Whenever I’m in a Blaylock class, there always comes a point where his lectures and our discussions take turns into more introspective territories, and this was especially true in our Peter Pan class last semester. I feel like Mr. Blaylock has such a connection and command of childhood and youth which were the central themes of the class. You can always tell how much he loves talking about how childhood and youth reflect so much of ourselves. I feel like we as teenagers often want to keep fragments of childhood with us, but also want to appear mature. And Blaylock really has always provided such a space to be mature and have beautiful conversations about life while also keeping this glow of youth about everything. I feel like Blaylock understands us.  Never have I had a teacher that truly understands and emphasizes the process of growing up. You can tell how much he loved teaching that class and how much he wanted us to get out of it. From him letting us play dress up and create stories from photographs, it was the blend of fun, passion, and heart that made Neverland one of the most fun classes I’ve ever taken.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mr. Blaylock’s friendly presence as conservatory director is cherished by everyone, students and faculty alike. We all are thankful for the memories we have made with him and are so excited to see what’s in store for him in the future, whether here at CSArts or somewhere else entirely. Thanks for everything, Mr. Blaylock.</p>]]></content><author><name>Griffin Stenzel</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mr. Blaylock embodies all that is good about our school. His positive energy, boundless enthusiasm, deep commitment to excellence, endless creativity, and heart-felt dedication to his students all reflect the best possible qualities of a director of a program at an arts school.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AP or Dual Enrollment? Which is better?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AP or Dual Enrollment? Which is better?" /><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/AP-dual-enrollment/"><![CDATA[<p>Every spring, students at CSArts debate on whether they’ll take AP courses or Citrus College classes. For some, this debate goes on throughout the summer, and some hope for the best in the fall about their decision. But even after having put in so much thought, is one actually better than the other?</p>

<p>On one hand, AP courses tend to have a higher demand of students interested rather than Citrus classes. This is due to the prestigious look of it on transcripts, as it shows that students were able to challenge themselves throughout their high school careers.</p>

<p>Although even with such advantages, AP courses also have their downfalls; they demand a strong work ethic and resilience. Throughout the year, students are expected to prepare themselves for the final AP exam through countless homework assignments and lengthy tests. This can be hard for CSArts students to manage considering the extra work of conservatory many have to manage, as well as rehearsals and shows to prepare for.</p>

<p>In addition, college credit for these courses is also not always guaranteed. According to the CSArts handbook, students will only receive credit after passing a two to three-hour-long exam. This is a huge deciding factor for most students, considering that if you fail the exam, then you may feel that it was all a huge waste of time and money, since the exams usually cost a certain fee in order to take the test.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Citrus College courses differ between subjects depending on if it is popular during a certain year. The difficulty of these classes ranges depending on the subject.</p>

<p>Overall, Citrus College courses  can be considered to be the “easier” option because of the automatic college credit granted if students pass the class, no matter what. These courses are also free of charge, and are a lot less anxiety-inducing when it comes to exams and credit.</p>

<p>Dual enrollment courses, like AP classes, also offer a GPA boost for students. However, some students seem to dislike the structure of Citrus College classes, considering it isn’t your typical high school class, and while it can be good practice for college, it can be a hard adjustment for some people. Grade formatting isn’t the same as in regular classes, and student and teacher relationships can be hard to establish depending on the class. There are also many student complaints about the Canvas platform used in Citrus classes, due to the confusing structure of grade reports and assignments. Therefore, all aspects of AP courses and Citrus College courses should be taken under consideration before making a decision on which to take.</p>

<p>As students prepare for the upcoming school year, it is also important to hear what their counselors have to say about AP and dual enrollment courses. Counselors will be able to help students take in both pros and cons of the two choices and support them in coming to the best decision.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For students already enrolled in an AP course, it makes sense for them to take the test at the end because you already work so hard the whole year. So, might as well take the exam and see if you can get college credit for it. Although if you are debating between taking an AP course in the fall or a CCC college course, it all depends on the student. Both can give you college credit but dual enrollment is automatic just by passing the class. For the AP courses, you have to pass the exam. So personally, I am biased, and I would lean towards the dual enrollment classes,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Ms. Shiroma, one of the counselors here at CSArts.</p>

<p>Teachers who teach these college level courses are also a great source for more in depth information regarding the course, considering they are highly aware of student habits and common experience among the school population.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The fact that the college credit all comes down to one exam might be stressful for some students. On the other hand, having to focus on preparing for an exam might provide some students with a clearer vision of what they need to do in the class. Of course, both AP and CCC classes are going to have college level work expected… In terms of deciding, it is important to think about whether you want to focus on taking an exam or not. The AP exam is a multi-hour exam, and it will require extra preparation time outside of class. The CCC class doesn’t have that type of all or nothing exam but it does have several writing assignments that are challenging. The courses are just different and one might work better for different students,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Mr. Pegan, who teaches the community college course for US history.</p>

<p>School staff and students have very distinct perspectives on whether or not which course is better, and opinions vary based on your plans for the future and your current circumstances. Students who experience the courses firsthand have a more valuable take on how both courses can affect their academic or social life. Here is what some students had to say about their experiences in both courses:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The dual enrollment classes can sometimes have an exaggerated workload which can interfere with your personal life but in the end, I’d say it is less harsh than AP courses”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Alina Ayala (VA ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Citrus classes tend to be less manageable and more professional, leading it to be more difficult. Although sometimes it can be the better route to go down because AP tests are expensive and it isn’t as important when you’re an underclassman”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Kayla Rigo (IM ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>AP classes are decent as long as you keep up with the work. They also have very helpful benefits if you take advantage of them”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Joann Cruz (VA ‘24)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Emotionally AP classes are overwhelming to a degree, depending on the student. They have their advantages academically but it takes a lot of commitment. Depending on the subject I would take an AP class again”</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Maddalena Cano  (VA ‘25)</li>
</ul>

<p>In the end, there is no “perfect” option for every individual. The demands of the classes differ and the factors that come into the decision-making such as testing, course work, and even what one wants in their high school experience. There are pros and cons to both sides, but the best choice is to go with what suits you the best.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jocelin Lila-Cruz</name></author><category term="essays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every spring, students at CSArts debate on whether they’ll take AP courses or Citrus College classes. For some, this debate goes on throughout the summer, and some hope for the best in the fall about their decision. But even after having put in so much thought, is one actually better than the other?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/8.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Interview with AI</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/an-interview-with-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Interview with AI" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/an-interview-with-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/an-interview-with-ai/"><![CDATA[<p>ChatGPT has taken the world by storm. With over 100 million users worldwide within a week of its launch, nearing numbers that rival sites like Google and Youtube, it can feel like nearly everyone is on the edge of their seats asking - What’s next? To answer these concerns, we’ve asked for an exclusive interview with ChatGPT itself. Here it is:</p>

<p><strong>ChatGPT:</strong> Hello, CSArtisan! I’m happy to assist with your interview. Please feel free to ask me any questions you have.</p>

<p><strong>CSArtisan:</strong> With the immense rise in both educators and students using AI in school environments, a number of concerns have been raised about using AI to cheat. How would you respond to these types of concerns?</p>

<p><strong>ChatGPT:</strong> Concerns about using AI to cheat are understandable, but clear guidelines and policies can be put in place to prevent misuse of AI tools. Educators can make it clear to students that using AI to cheat is not acceptable, and students can be encouraged to use AI responsibly. AI can also be used to prevent cheating, such as through plagiarism detection software and AI-powered proctoring tools. Ultimately, it is up to everyone involved in the education system to ensure that AI is used in a responsible and ethical manner.</p>

<p><strong>CSArtisan:</strong> As both journalists and arts students at the CSArtisan, we understand the importance of human creativity. How do you respond to the idea of AI taking over both creative and practical jobs?</p>

<p><strong>ChatGPT:</strong> AI is unlikely to completely replace human creativity and practical skills, and is better used as a complement. AI can improve efficiency and productivity, but many tasks require human skills such as empathy, critical thinking, and problem-solving. A balance between AI and human workers can achieve greater results.</p>

<p><strong>CSArtisan:</strong> Thank you for your responses. Last question: What do you think about the idea of AI replacing search engines like Google and Bing? Do you think it’ll lead to a slippery slope where AI replaces all technology?</p>

<p><strong>ChatGPT:</strong> While AI could potentially replace search engines, it is unlikely to lead to a total replacement of all technology by AI. However, the increasing use of AI raises important questions about its impact on society, including concerns about harmful or discriminatory use and its impact on employment. It is important to consider the benefits and risks of AI, and ensure its responsible and ethical development and use through regulation and ongoing discussions.</p>

<p><strong>CSArtisan:</strong> Thank you so much for your time. Could you please say goodbye to our readers in a fun way?</p>

<p><strong>ChatGPT:</strong> Of course, it was my pleasure to chat with you all! Keep up the great work at CSArtisan, and don’t forget to sprinkle a little bit of creativity into everything you do. Stay curious, stay imaginative, and stay inspired! Goodbye for now!</p>

<h6 id="this-interview-has-been-edited-slightly-for-clarity-and-length">This interview has been edited slightly for clarity and length.</h6>]]></content><author><name>Sidney Tsai</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT has taken the world by storm. With over 100 million users worldwide within a week of its launch, nearing numbers that rival sites like Google and Youtube, it can feel like nearly everyone is on the edge of their seats asking - What’s next? To answer these concerns, we’ve asked for an exclusive interview with ChatGPT itself. Here it is:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/an-interview-with-ai.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/an-interview-with-ai.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dubs and Snubs of the 95th Oscars</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/oscars-95/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dubs and Snubs of the 95th Oscars" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/oscars-95</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/oscars-95/"><![CDATA[<p>At the 95th Academy Awards, Everything Everything All at Once lived up to its name. This genre-bending film took home seven Oscars, including Best Picture, Best Director, and several acting awards. Other successful movies were The Whale, which garnered two awards, one of which was for Brendon Fraser’s acting comeback, and All Quiet on the Western Front, which won many technical awards.</p>

<p>CSArts students reflected on the record-breaking night and who they wished had won. Rhys Shaw (ACT ‘23) was overjoyed with Everything Everywhere All at Once’s win.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>1,000% Everything Everywhere All at Once deserved to win. I think it’s a very unconventional movie. And it tells a story in a way that we’ve never seen before, that hasn’t been told that has been needing to be told. It’s been a great platform for much-needed Asian representation in mainstream media. It revived the career of Ke Huy Quan, who deserved it more than anybody else. It allowed Jamie Lee Curtis to go beyond the Halloween franchise and extend into what can be seen as more prestigious acting. And it cemented Michelle Yeoh as not only an Asian actress but also an important piece of American cinema,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>he said.</p>

<p>Samantha Thomas (CW ‘24) loved seeing Sarah Polley win for her adapted screenplay of Women Talking, but wished it got more Oscar love.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It has incredibly powerful performances that got zero attention from Rooney Mara, Jessie Buckley, Claire Foy — and I think that it’s a movie tackling such a difficult topic that typically in Hollywood is so exacerbated and exploitative. Also, the music was beautiful. The score heightens the experience of the movie and truly went out of its way to highlight the dread that these women feel, and I’m sad that it did not get nominated for Best Original Score,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>she said.</p>

<p>There was a sense of CSArts students being more passionate about movies this year, compared to last year. That was reflected in the ratings as well. Ratings jumped from last year’s Oscars by 12% compared to last year’s dismal ratings. Nearly 20 million people tuned in from everywhere, all at once, to celebrate cinema on the big screen.</p>]]></content><author><name>Griffin Stenzel</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the 95th Academy Awards, Everything Everything All at Once lived up to its name. This genre-bending film took home seven Oscars, including Best Picture, Best Director, and several acting awards. Other successful movies were The Whale, which garnered two awards, one of which was for Brendon Fraser’s acting comeback, and All Quiet on the Western Front, which won many technical awards.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/oscars-95.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/oscars-95.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Shamrock Saint: History of Saint Patrick’s Day</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/the-shamrock-saint/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Shamrock Saint: History of Saint Patrick’s Day" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/the-shamrock-saint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/the-shamrock-saint/"><![CDATA[<p>On March 17th, CSArts students wore their best green clothes to celebrate Saint Patrick’s Day. St. Patrick’s Day is celebrated annually on March 17, which is the death anniversary of Saint Patrick. But who is Saint Patrick, and why do we celebrate him?</p>

<p>Saint Patrick is the patron saint of Ireland and its national apostle. He was born in Roman Britain, and was then kidnapped and brought to Ireland as a slave at 16. He would later escape, but would later return to Ireland. He is often credited with bringing Christianity to its people. By the time of his death on March 17, 461, he had established monasteries, churches, and schools.</p>

<p>There are a variety of myths and legends regarding Saint Patrick. One of the most notable is how he was the one to drive the snakes out of Ireland, or how he used the native shamrock of Ireland to explain the Holy Trinity.</p>

<p>The traditions of Saint Patrick’s Day have evolved over the centuries. The city of Chicago dyes its river green, and other cities hold parades, where thousands of people, Irish and non-Irish alike, gather together to celebrate the holiday. Corned beef and cabbage are associated with the holiday, and even beer is sometimes dyed green as well.</p>

<p>Whether you believe in Irish luck or not, the holiday of Saint Patrick’s Day is a fun way to celebrate the history, mythology, and culture of the Irish people.</p>]]></content><author><name>Sophia Brunet</name></author><category term="essays" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On March 17th, CSArts students wore their best green clothes to celebrate Saint Patrick’s Day. St. Patrick’s Day is celebrated annually on March 17, which is the death anniversary of Saint Patrick. But who is Saint Patrick, and why do we celebrate him?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/the-shamrock-saint.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/the-shamrock-saint.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">VA 10th Grade Showcase</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-tenth-grade-showcase/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VA 10th Grade Showcase" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-tenth-grade-showcase</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/VA-tenth-grade-showcase/"><![CDATA[<p>Every year, the Visual Arts Conservatory hosts an art showcase for all grade levels. March 8th was the opening night for the 10th Grade Showcase where sophomores showcased their pieces from last semester in the front lobby for everyone to enjoy! The show consisted of various types of artworks from a multitude of classes. The show included master copy paintings that sophomores completed in the 2D Design class. Students were able to display their knowledge and create their own rendition of other master painters. The show also contained a few pieces from other classes like photography and ceramics. Overall, the showcase was a great opportunity to celebrate their work in a space with their family and friends. Here is what a few Visual Arts students had to say about their experience with the show:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This was my first time being a part of a CSArts visual arts showcase! It was so much fun and exciting to have my artwork be appreciated by everyone. It was a great showcase and I am excited for next year!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Alina Ayala (VA ‘25)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was very inspiring to see my fellow peers use their skills to create something beautiful and new.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Monze Aquino (IA ‘25)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My experience with the showcase was a bit nerve wracking because other people’s paintings and photographs were really good. So, I felt a bit down because I thought mine wasn’t good enough but then I realized that we are all different in our levels of artist and that mine was good because I worked hard. I could tell that everyone also worked hard and I think that is what counts as an artist and that is what is going to make other’s experience the showcase”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Nayeli Gutierrez (VA ‘25).</p>

<p>As always, the Visual Arts conservatory did a spectacular job, but this specific showcase was even more special. For the first time ever, visual arts students from the Exhibition and Design class worked behind the scenes to help the show come to life. From marketing, curating, decorating, and organizing, the visual arts students worked alongside each other to make the show possible. We asked a couple students who worked on the show about their experience.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was definitely a great experience since I’ve never created/designed a showcase before. It was challenging but my group was great and we had little trouble deciding the details. My favorite part of the showcase is definitely the center area where the ceramic pieces are shown! I also really loved the sign for the 10th grade showcase on the main wall!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says the team’s curator, Alisa Kang (VA ‘24).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Working on the showcase was really fun! It was a great experience to collaborate with a team and create that setup. My favorite part of the showcase was probably the centerpiece with the curtains. It was cool to put it up and really show off and frame those pieces,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says the team’s Director of Marketing, Dyllan Edge (VA ‘25)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Even though it took a lot of work and brainstorming, it was a lot of fun working on the showcase! We had to work from scratch, figuring out the theme we wanted, purchasing the items we needed, and contacting the teachers to collect artworks as well. We also had a deadline to meet, so it was even more pressuring. Although all the sweats and tears went into each individual tacky used to put up the paintings, the exhibition turned out wonderful! I learned how to work better as a team and problem-solve on the way, so the experience was worth it as well! My favorite part of the showcase was the main wall! My teammate created a beautiful font and I worked on laying out the paintings. I thought it turned out to be a very effortlessly perfect type of effect and I liked that a lot!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says the team’s client relations, Han Lam (VA ‘24)</p>]]></content><author><name>Jocelin Lila-Cruz &amp; Ivy Kim</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every year, the Visual Arts Conservatory hosts an art showcase for all grade levels. March 8th was the opening night for the 10th Grade Showcase where sophomores showcased their pieces from last semester in the front lobby for everyone to enjoy! The show consisted of various types of artworks from a multitude of classes. The show included master copy paintings that sophomores completed in the 2D Design class. Students were able to display their knowledge and create their own rendition of other master painters. The show also contained a few pieces from other classes like photography and ceramics. Overall, the showcase was a great opportunity to celebrate their work in a space with their family and friends. Here is what a few Visual Arts students had to say about their experience with the show:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/va-tenth-grade-showcase.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/va-tenth-grade-showcase.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>