<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-21T17:37:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Get the latest on CSArts Performances, Events, Updates, &amp; More, or play the Weekly Mini Crossword!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">MT Shows Serious Skill in “Starcatcher”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/peter-and-the-starcatcher/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MT Shows Serious Skill in “Starcatcher”" /><published>2024-12-13T04:30:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T04:30:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/peter-and-the-starcatcher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/peter-and-the-starcatcher/"><![CDATA[<p>The sea roars and two boats collide. A father, Lord Aster, and his daughter named Molly, get separated in the process. Pirates take over and the story continues on highlighting the main character of the story, Peter Pan before he was given his iconic name.</p>

<p>The Musical Theater Conservatory performed an amazing production of Peter and the Starcatcher, a prequel to Peter Pan. It was an upbeat and comedic show showcasing characters like Black Stache and his sidekick Smee. Pirates try to steal the treasure of Lord Aster, but Peter, a young orphan boy, helps Molly get the treasure back. A love blooms between the two and Peter goes through many other obstacles such as meeting mermaids and getting his full name Peter Pan. Action and humor mixed in together to create a wonderful and laughable show that everyone enjoyed on opening night.</p>

<p>“This show is Peter Pan’s backstory. The highlight of this show is the swimming scene.” - said an anonymous Production and Design student.</p>

<p>“My favorite part of the show is definitely the mermaid scene. It was so much fun to do. This play is a prequel to Peter Pan and it’s kind of about Peter, his upbringing as an orphan and how he ends up getting his name and finding his family.” said Ev Cullen, who played Lord Aster.</p>

<p>Look for CSArts next major production of Once Upon A Mattress, the all-school musical, January 16th-18th.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aryhanna Pham</name></author><category term="productions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sea roars and two boats collide. A father, Lord Aster, and his daughter named Molly, get separated in the process. Pirates take over and the story continues on highlighting the main character of the story, Peter Pan before he was given his iconic name.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/peter-and-the-starcatcher.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/peter-and-the-starcatcher.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Conservatory Transfers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/conservatory-transfers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conservatory Transfers" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/conservatory-transfers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/conservatory-transfers/"><![CDATA[<p>Transferring conservatories at CSArts is a major step that could open new doors for growth and creativity, but making the transition seamlessly, requires thoughtful planning and a clear understanding of the process. CSArts principal Nicole. Read shared her advice in a recent interview, offering insights to help students and families navigate this important decision:</p>

<h3 id="tip-1-start-early-and-be-punctual">Tip #1: Start Early and Be Punctual</h3>

<p>Mrs. Read emphasized the importance of starting the transfer process early– and not procrastinating. “I would do it ahead of time, don’t wait till the last minute– oftentimes students forget, or they’re a few days late with their submission,” she said. “Conservatory directors really hold this firm line because they believe that your punctuality and submitting a transfer application shows you’re really serious about it and that you’re not just escaping a situation in another conservatory.”</p>

<h3 id="tip-2-understand-the-timing">Tip #2: Understand the Timing</h3>

<p>A key point Mrs. Read clarified was the timeline for transfers. “A common misunderstanding that families and students have about conservatory transfers is that they think it’s for the next semester, but it’s for the next fall,” she said. “Directors plan budgets based on the number of incoming students for the next academic year, so mid-year transfers aren’t possible.”</p>

<h3 id="tip-3-leverage-teacher-and-mentor-support">Tip #3: Leverage Teacher and Mentor Support</h3>

<p>Mrs. Read encouraged students to involve their mentors and advisors in the process. “Certainly all the directors and teachers are willing to discuss with kids whether they think it’s a good fit or not,” she said. Seeking feedback from those who know your strengths and goals can provide clarity and confidence.</p>

<p>So, start early, respect the timeline, and leverage support of teachers and advisors.  As Mrs. Read put it, “If you’re thinking about transferring, just go for it! It can’t hurt– find out if you can transfer. Even if you decide not to, at least you’ll know your options.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transferring conservatories at CSArts is a major step that could open new doors for growth and creativity, but making the transition seamlessly, requires thoughtful planning and a clear understanding of the process. CSArts principal Nicole. Read shared her advice in a recent interview, offering insights to help students and families navigate this important decision:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/conservatory-transfers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/conservatory-transfers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chromakopia: Good or Great?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chromakopia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chromakopia: Good or Great?" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chromakopia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chromakopia/"><![CDATA[<p>With all the hype around Chromakopia, Tyler, The Creator’s newest album, I’ve been excited to check it out. The album was released on Oct 28, 2024 to its eager fansbase. But, does the album deliver?</p>

<p>I would say yes! Song after song was different: “Balloon”, “Sticky” and “Rah Tah Tah” have energetic scream-worthy beats along with slower, more emotional songs like “Hey Jane”, “I Hope You Find Your Way Home,” and “Judge Judy.”</p>

<p>Song after song has been added to my playlist, but “Balloon”, “Sticky” and “Rah Tah Tah” have been my favorites from the beginning. I love the playful and comedic lyrics of the first two, and the dramatic melodies in the background of all three catch my attention. In my opinion, other songs, especially “Judge Judy” have been a lot less impressive and exciting.</p>

<p>The poll included CSArts’ favorite and least favorite Chromakopia song, and rating of the album. So far, “Sticky” appears to be the most liked song, and “Judge Judy” is the least favorite.</p>

<p>“The change in St. Chroma from the trailer to the official song actually made it worse,” said student Plaid Brake. Student Jaxon Jackson said, “Judge Judy is not all that. If I were to rank it in comparison to every Tyler song I’ve ever heard, it would be near the bottom.”</p>

<p>The album got an 8 out of 10 overall.</p>

<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfcXu9wF8h9OptyBH_OLmHfial1Ldr-PNeR6F7pmglMzVK7dQ/viewform?pli=1">Do you agree with your peers at CSArts?</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Ari Dawson</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With all the hype around Chromakopia, Tyler, The Creator’s newest album, I’ve been excited to check it out. The album was released on Oct 28, 2024 to its eager fansbase. But, does the album deliver?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/chromakopia.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/chromakopia.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Ode to Alien Stage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alien-stage-ADD-LINKS/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Ode to Alien Stage" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alien-stage-ADD-LINKS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alien-stage-ADD-LINKS/"><![CDATA[<p>Alien Stage (sometimes styled ALIEN STAGE) is a South Korean music project and animated YouTube series told through consecutive music videos featuring original characters and songs. Led by VIVINOS, a South Korean artist and animator, in collaboration with QMENG and STUDIO LICO, Alien Stage follows the story of humans born into a futuristic society in which aliens have taken over the world, giving rise to the advent of “human pets” forced to compete in the titular game show. It’s often described by fans as “a cross between The Hunger Games and The Masked Singer,” in which pairs of contestants compete against each other through duets. The winner advances to the next round, and the loser is publicly executed in front of a live audience at the end of the song.</p>

<p>While such a violent premise may sound dubious, the real magic of Alien Stage is expressed through the dynamics between the seven main characters, all told without a single line of dialogue (bar a brief monologue in the song “My Clematis”). As the show progresses, character storylines overlap and increase in complexity, often with gut-wrenching results, such as the sacrifice of the character Ivan in Round 6, following a kiss between one of the show’s two queer couples.</p>

<p>I got into Alien Stage from recommendations by my friends, expecting it to be a casual watch before I moved on with my life. Instead, I was immersed in a world that I’m finding difficult to escape; it’s been over two months since I watched each round in succession and I’m still just as engaged with the fandom and the lore of the story as I was in the first week of discovery. The writing really shines through the beautiful animation and original songs performed by a coalition of skilled artists. I would give Alien Stage five out of five stars. You can watch Alien Stage on YouTube and view a variety of bonus content from the authors’ social media accounts and on VIVINOS’s Patreon.</p>]]></content><author><name>Quinn Mcnary</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alien Stage (sometimes styled ALIEN STAGE) is a South Korean music project and animated YouTube series told through consecutive music videos featuring original characters and songs. Led by VIVINOS, a South Korean artist and animator, in collaboration with QMENG and STUDIO LICO, Alien Stage follows the story of humans born into a futuristic society in which aliens have taken over the world, giving rise to the advent of “human pets” forced to compete in the titular game show. It’s often described by fans as “a cross between The Hunger Games and The Masked Singer,” in which pairs of contestants compete against each other through duets. The winner advances to the next round, and the loser is publicly executed in front of a live audience at the end of the song.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/alien-stage.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/alien-stage.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Scholarship Opportunities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/scholarship-opportunities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scholarship Opportunities" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/scholarship-opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/scholarship-opportunities/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s officially the season where Junior and Seniors are  scrambling to win scholarships. There are all kinds of scholarships out there so what you submit to one place might be different for another. For example, one might ask for an essay, another could ask for an application, resume, letter of recommendation, transcripts or even a portfolio/video submission. It all depends on what you are applying for.</p>

<p>The number of websites you can use in order to apply are endless, however, counselor Emily Christy recommends you use trusted websites like “Fastweb,” “BigFuture Scholarships,” and “Scholarships.com.” While on your search for scholarships, Mrs. Christy emphasizes the gravity of being safe while applying for scholarships and to watch out for potential scams. A telltale sign of a scam are websites that require you to pay a fee to apply. During the process of application, Mrs. Christy suggests carefully following the instructions. “To learn how to apply for a scholarship, go to the scholarship’s website or application portal, follow the instructions carefully and make sure to submit by the deadline,” Christy explains.</p>

<p>Picking a scholarship that matches your profile is equally as important. “It’s helpful to choose a scholarship that aligns with your strengths, interests or background. For example, if you love the arts, apply for some art-based scholarships. If you love math or science, apply for some STEM related scholarships,” Christy said.</p>

<p>In addition to interests and academics, consider ones that focus on personal development, hobbies, culture, and community involvement. By using your passions and achievements your chances of winning the scholarship is higher.</p>

<p>All in all, focus on finding opportunities which align with you for a better chance at success and be vigilant to avoid scams. Scholarships are a valuable resource which can only benefit you in the long run for your journey into college.</p>]]></content><author><name>Victoria Maradiaga</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s officially the season where Junior and Seniors are scrambling to win scholarships. There are all kinds of scholarships out there so what you submit to one place might be different for another. For example, one might ask for an essay, another could ask for an application, resume, letter of recommendation, transcripts or even a portfolio/video submission. It all depends on what you are applying for.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keeping the Holiday Spirit Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/keeping-the-holiday-spirit-alive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keeping the Holiday Spirit Alive" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/keeping-the-holiday-spirit-alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/keeping-the-holiday-spirit-alive/"><![CDATA[<p>As CSArts students begin their winter festivities, they try to keep the holiday spirit alive as teenagers, with decorations, festivities, and traditions new and old.</p>

<p>The students at CSArts and highschool students in general are in a period of expedited growth as people. A common discussion among my peers is the nostalgia of our childhoods; this time of year, especially, we look back at the magic of the holidays as children. “The holidays feel less special and less exciting,” Vana Kojikian, a CSArts sophomore said, “I still look forward to it but it doesn’t always feel the same as it did when we were younger.”</p>

<p>Students and teens as a whole scramble to keep the holiday spirit and magic alive. One way to accomplish this is creating the right atmosphere. A poll of CSArts students shows that over 50% decorate for the holidays the day after Thanksgiving. Another 16% of students decorate even earlier than that. Joy Thomas said, “I like to start decorating a week before Thanksgiving to have everything ready.” She explains that decorating earlier extends the season and allows you to make the most of this time of year.</p>

<p>Childhood holiday traditions are still important to many teens, and help keep the spirit alive. “I watch movies with my family, cook dinners, and bake cookies,” CSArts student Sofia Wallach said, “I’ve done these traditions since childhood.” She said that, “Receiving gifts and waiting for Santa to come, are not the priority.” Wallach explains that now that she is older, instead of feeling holiday magic through literal magic, she focuses more on the spirit throughout the month, with all of her traditions.</p>

<p>As we grow up, new traditions are formed to go along with the old ones. Wallach has a younger brother, and talks about her new traditions and trying to keep the magical element alive for him. She said, “I would help wrap his presents and try to keep him believing in Santa.” Students also spend more time with their friends around the holidays. Many participate in “Secret Santa’s,” or other winter activities like ice skating, gingerbread house making, and baking with friends. These new traditions can be just as important as the old ones.</p>

<p>The holidays feel different now that students are growing up, but the holiday season is still a magical time thanks to decorations, traditions, friends, and family.</p>]]></content><author><name>Nico Deany</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As CSArts students begin their winter festivities, they try to keep the holiday spirit alive as teenagers, with decorations, festivities, and traditions new and old.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Winter Blues: More Than Just A Feeling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/winter-blues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Blues: More Than Just A Feeling" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/winter-blues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/winter-blues/"><![CDATA[<p>As winter approaches and days get shorter, many students experience Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD), or the “winter blues.” This mood disorder skyrockets in December and causes symptoms like fatigue, irritability, lack of motivation, and depression. High school students are especially vulnerable, with the darker days intensifying these obstacles.</p>

<p>SAD is caused by factors like biological clock changes, brain chemical imbalances, Vitamin D deficiency, and melatonin overproduction. Cleveland Clinic explains, “Brain chemicals called neurotransmitters send communications between nerves. These chemicals include serotonin, which contributes to feelings of happiness.” Treatments for SAD are exercise, light therapy, cognitive behavioral therapy, and antidepressants.</p>

<p>SAD deeply affects high school students, especially those at CSArts, as shorter days and less sunlight trigger depression-like symptoms, says John Hopkins Medicine. These change mood, energy, and focus, making it harder to stay engaged in school and social life. For teens, effective coping strategies—such as getting outdoor sunlight, staying active, and seeking support from trusted adults will make a real difference.</p>

<p>By understanding SAD’s indicators, you can take steps to management before affecting your mental health. Get outside for sunlight, stay active, and don’t hesitate to talk to trusted adults if you’re struggling. Remember, taking care of your mental health is just as important as your physical health—especially during challenging times like these. SAD is more than just a feeling, it should be prioritized and discussed. You’re not alone, and help is available.</p>

<p>If you are experiencing a mental health or substance abuse crisis, dial 988 for help.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Natalie R. Merino</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As winter approaches and days get shorter, many students experience Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD), or the “winter blues.” This mood disorder skyrockets in December and causes symptoms like fatigue, irritability, lack of motivation, and depression. High school students are especially vulnerable, with the darker days intensifying these obstacles.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-blues.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-blues.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Remembering People Who Experienced Homelessness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homelessness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remembering People Who Experienced Homelessness" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homelessness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homelessness/"><![CDATA[<p>Although December 21st is Winter Solstice this year, it is also National Homeless Persons’ Memorial Day (or very unofficially National Persons Experiencing Homelessness Memorial Day), which serves to remember people who have passed away without a home. This is especially relevant here. According to the Los Angeles Homeless Services Authority, in 2023, 75,518 people experienced homelessness each night in LA County.</p>

<p>National Homeless Persons’ Memorial Day raises awareness on the higher risk of death. At the same time, it implies a call to action: people should not be dying without homes, and especially not solely because of not having a home.</p>

<p>To honor those who have been lost, people hold events to share their life stories and hold candlelight marches or moments of silence.</p>

<p>On the first full day of Winter, December 21st, the day of remembrance is an invitation to remember those who died without a home, and think about what the state and the country can do to help. Even if it’s just something small like preparing and donating a bag of necessities, or giving food to a food bank, each of us can make a difference.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although December 21st is Winter Solstice this year, it is also National Homeless Persons’ Memorial Day (or very unofficially National Persons Experiencing Homelessness Memorial Day), which serves to remember people who have passed away without a home. This is especially relevant here. According to the Los Angeles Homeless Services Authority, in 2023, 75,518 people experienced homelessness each night in LA County.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/homelessness.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/homelessness.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Productive Over Winter Break</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/winter-break-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Productive Over Winter Break" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/winter-break-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/winter-break-productivity/"><![CDATA[<p>During winter break, it can be easy to slide away from a schedule. Especially when you know that the first semester of school is over. However, if you do nothing all break, then it can become challenging and stressful to get back to keeping up with your work every day.</p>

<p>The best way to stay productive across winter break is to plan ahead. “At the beginning of the break make a list of things you want to accomplish during the break so you can have a little bit of structure in your time of relaxation,” said CSArts counselor Riena McMillen. As for what it is you can do during this time, she recommends volunteer hours and extracurricular activities. These are things that are hard to do when you have conservatory classes.</p>

<p>It’s also important to avoid falling into unhealthy habits. Things like screen time and sleeping in late, should be avoided so that it’s easier for you to start school again once break is over.</p>]]></content><author><name>Salvador Villagomez</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During winter break, it can be easy to slide away from a schedule. Especially when you know that the first semester of school is over. However, if you do nothing all break, then it can become challenging and stressful to get back to keeping up with your work every day. The best way to stay productive across winter break is to plan ahead. “At the beginning of the break make a list of things you want to accomplish during the break so you can have a little bit of structure in your time of relaxation,” said CSArts counselor Riena McMillen. As for what it is you can do during this time, she recommends volunteer hours and extracurricular activities. These are things that are hard to do when you have conservatory classes.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-break-productivity.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-break-productivity.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts’ Favorite Winter Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/winter-movies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts’ Favorite Winter Movies" /><published>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/winter-movies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/winter-movies/"><![CDATA[<p>‘Tis the season for festive films! Whether we’re lighting up candles for Advent or Hanukkah, listening to Santa songs, hanging up stockings, or simply kicking back with a cup of hot cocoa and blankets to relax, there are hundreds of movies to choose from, but which of the classics beat them all?
The CSArtisan polled students regarding their favorite holiday film. Students were given options or could write in their favorite. And here are the results! (Drum roll please):
The 1st place for favorite movie was tied with A Charlie Brown Christmas and Elf, at 25%. The second favorite? Die Hard with 12.5%. Rounding out the top 3 were 4 movies tied at 3rd place: A Christmas Carol, It’s a Wonderful Life, How the Grinch Stole Christmas and Nightmare Before Christmas at 8%.
The results bring interesting conclusions of how the timeless Christmas classics were less popular than silly, lighthearted movies (or Die Hard, which doesn’t have the warm feels usually, but still lies in the genre, just as an outlier.)</p>

<p>Some students chose to write in their favorites which include: Home Alone, Scrooged, Klaus, and Eight Crazy Nights.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ashel Brown</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Tis the season for festive films! Whether we’re lighting up candles for Advent or Hanukkah, listening to Santa songs, hanging up stockings, or simply kicking back with a cup of hot cocoa and blankets to relax, there are hundreds of movies to choose from, but which of the classics beat them all? The CSArtisan polled students regarding their favorite holiday film. Students were given options or could write in their favorite. And here are the results! (Drum roll please): The 1st place for favorite movie was tied with A Charlie Brown Christmas and Elf, at 25%. The second favorite? Die Hard with 12.5%. Rounding out the top 3 were 4 movies tied at 3rd place: A Christmas Carol, It’s a Wonderful Life, How the Grinch Stole Christmas and Nightmare Before Christmas at 8%. The results bring interesting conclusions of how the timeless Christmas classics were less popular than silly, lighthearted movies (or Die Hard, which doesn’t have the warm feels usually, but still lies in the genre, just as an outlier.)]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-movies.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/winter-movies.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>