<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-30T19:31:01-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>The official website of the CSArts student newspaper. Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Persistant Pipe Problems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Persistant Pipe Problems" /><published>2024-05-31T05:10:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:10:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/persistant-pipe-problems/"><![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday, April 23, pipes burst in the 200s and flooded the area. Students puddle-jumped their way to classes, as CSArts-SGV administrators made the all-too-familiar calls to maintenance to fix an area of pipes that have a history of bursting.</p>

<p>Upper-class students joke that the pipes in the 200s buildings have a calendar to burst every year, creating a mess in the same spot and raising questions about the school’s infrastructure. No students or faculty were hurt, no classes disrupted, and the water was shut off quickly by campus administrators and authorities. Students still had their concerns. “I think that it is important to learn in a clean environment,“ Maiya Bhat, a 9th grader said.</p>

<p>Assistant Principal, Mr. Metoyer says he does not expect any other problems with the main pipe and that during the break, there are multiple projects to strengthen the campus’ infrastructure.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Each Summer CSArts-SGV utilizes a pre-determined budget to maintain the infrastructure, make upgrades, and prepare for the future school year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer is actively planning with the school’s plumbing and facility teams on the areas that require the most focus and funding. One of the areas of focus?  The bathrooms. He says that this summer, money wil go “to enhance the restroom experience for all CSArts-SGV staff and students next year.”</p>

<p>The dry season is the perfect time for work on infrastructure, with students and the rain gone. During the winter, however, due to our school’s location near the foothills, we are at Mother Nature’s mercy, as climate change fuels stronger storms, heavy rainfall, and gusty winds.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park &amp; Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday, April 23, pipes burst in the 200s and flooded the area. Students puddle-jumped their way to classes, as CSArts-SGV administrators made the all-too-familiar calls to maintenance to fix an area of pipes that have a history of bursting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/persistant-pipe-problems.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/persistant-pipe-problems.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing, Testing: How State Tests Impact CSArts and Students</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/testing-testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing, Testing: How State Tests Impact CSArts and Students" /><published>2024-05-31T05:09:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:09:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/testing-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/testing-testing/"><![CDATA[<p>Every Spring, 9-11th grade students endure a week of state testing. The week is long and the rules are strict: no computers, no phones in the classroom, even after students finish the computerized tests. So, what are these tests?  Why are they so important? The CSArtisan has done the research for you!</p>

<p>The focus of state testing is on the Junior Class. 11th graders take the California mandated CAASPP test, which collects important data including academic performance and determines how the school ranks compared to other state schools in California. 9-10th graders take “interim testing” which the California Department of Education defines as a formative assessment. That data can help teachers pinpoint exactly where students need more help.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s a great way for students to practice, but the scores don’t count towards anything.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Says Ms. Read, the Assistant Principal at CSArts.</p>

<p>While the Interim testing can be thought of as formative, the CAASPP test is summative and has real effects on schools and students. The state requires a student participation rate of at least 95% and if that percentage is not met, it puts the school in legal jeopardy and in danger of receiving corrective action from the state.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>One incentive the school uses to keep our participation rate over 95% is valedictorian status.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Ms. Read.</p>

<p>While state and Interim testing can be a bore, it’s important for students to understand the effects that they can have on CSArts and their school experience.</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Spring, 9-11th grade students endure a week of state testing. The week is long and the rules are strict: no computers, no phones in the classroom, even after students finish the computerized tests. So, what are these tests? Why are they so important? The CSArtisan has done the research for you!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/testing-testing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/testing-testing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reel Big Deal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reel-big-deal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reel Big Deal" /><published>2024-05-31T05:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:08:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reel-big-deal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reel-big-deal/"><![CDATA[<p>You might have heard about the new Film/TV Industry program being introduced for the 2024-2025 school year. When I spoke with Dr. Cook, he clarified that it is less of a standalone conservatory and more of an integrated program, offering classes of which all conservatories can participate. For example, Creative Writing conservatory students might take a TV writing or broadcast news class, while Instrumental Music students could enroll in a composition-in-film class. Additionally, there will be elective classes available during the academic day, allowing students from any conservatory to explore film industry-related subjects.</p>

<p>This exciting development is made possible by a grant that CSArts-SGV recently won and is part of an “industry readiness” program. The grant has not only funded the new Film/TV Industry program but has also enabled the introduction of a new E-Sports computer science class and the remodeling of Mr. Read’s classroom. Keep an eye out for these new classes in 2025!</p>]]></content><author><name>Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have heard about the new Film/TV Industry program being introduced for the 2024-2025 school year. When I spoke with Dr. Cook, he clarified that it is less of a standalone conservatory and more of an integrated program, offering classes of which all conservatories can participate. For example, Creative Writing conservatory students might take a TV writing or broadcast news class, while Instrumental Music students could enroll in a composition-in-film class. Additionally, there will be elective classes available during the academic day, allowing students from any conservatory to explore film industry-related subjects.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/reel-big-deal.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/reel-big-deal.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TEDxCSArts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tedxcsarts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TEDxCSArts" /><published>2024-05-31T05:07:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:07:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tedxcsarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tedxcsarts/"><![CDATA[<p>TED Talks are coming to CSArts-SGV in 2025! So, if you’re a passionate speaker wanting to improve your craft while exploring bold ideas and sparking meaningful conversations, this is for you! If you have a vision for positive change and innovation in your community or beyond, this is right up your alley! And, if you’re eager to develop your communication, leadership, and critical thinking skills in a supportive environment, TEDxCSArts is headed your way in 2025!</p>

<p>Next Spring, CSArts-SGV will launch TEDxCSArts giving students the opportunity to create, get coached and critiqued, and deliver their own TED Talks in collaboration with the big guy in red known as “TED.” (TED isn’t a real person-but stands for “technology,entertainment, and, design)</p>

<p>Plans are still being ironed out. If you are interested and want more details, you can contact Creative Writing Conservatory Director, Timothy Gomez at <a href="mailto:timothy.gomez@sgv.csarts.net">timothy.gomez@sgv.csarts.net</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TED Talks are coming to CSArts-SGV in 2025! So, if you’re a passionate speaker wanting to improve your craft while exploring bold ideas and sparking meaningful conversations, this is for you! If you have a vision for positive change and innovation in your community or beyond, this is right up your alley! And, if you’re eager to develop your communication, leadership, and critical thinking skills in a supportive environment, TEDxCSArts is headed your way in 2025!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Volunteer Opportunities in Duarte</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/duarte-volunteering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volunteer Opportunities in Duarte" /><published>2024-05-31T05:06:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:06:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/duarte-volunteering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/duarte-volunteering/"><![CDATA[<p>With all the free time during summer break, it would be a great idea to get a summer job or volunteer! Duarte has volunteer opportunities for high schoolers during their break. There are many available options with local youth programs for people under the age of 18. You can check out the Duarte’s Park and Recreation Department to get involved in community cleanups and other fun summer projects. Not to mention, it is a great thing to put on your resumes and job applications!</p>

<p>Click <a href="https://www.accessduarte.com/government/departments/administrative-services/human-resources/volunteer-opportunities">here</a> to find all the info and applications.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With all the free time during summer break, it would be a great idea to get a summer job or volunteer! Duarte has volunteer opportunities for high schoolers during their break. There are many available options with local youth programs for people under the age of 18. You can check out the Duarte’s Park and Recreation Department to get involved in community cleanups and other fun summer projects. Not to mention, it is a great thing to put on your resumes and job applications!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/duarte-volunteering.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/duarte-volunteering.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cleaning Empathy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cleaning-empathy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cleaning Empathy" /><published>2024-05-31T05:05:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:05:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cleaning-empathy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cleaning-empathy/"><![CDATA[<p>With the end of our school year nearing, most students are stressed about finals or graduation. While being nervous, they tend to overlook the beauty of the CSArts campus. Months ago, boxes for unwanted food and trash appeared around campus, but there is a problem: students are not using them.</p>

<p>Some students have been brave enough to pick up their trash and the trash of others. Still, this leaves more work for the custodial staff.</p>

<p>CSArts’ custodial staff JJ and Alex do more than their fair share of hours, helping to manage the campus, setting up school-wide events, and more! And security is always ready to pitch in and help clean up; however, unnecessary littering gives them more work.</p>

<p>With summer approaching, students are encouraged to make their school shine brighter than before by keeping the campus clean, donating unwanted food, and thinking about how your actions affect others.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the end of our school year nearing, most students are stressed about finals or graduation. While being nervous, they tend to overlook the beauty of the CSArts campus. Months ago, boxes for unwanted food and trash appeared around campus, but there is a problem: students are not using them.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cleaning-empathy.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cleaning-empathy.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodbye!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/goodbye-mj-cho/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodbye!" /><published>2024-05-31T05:01:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T05:01:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/goodbye-mj-cho</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/goodbye-mj-cho/"><![CDATA[<p>Although I’ve told everyone (including college applications) that I first joined the school newspaper in my junior year, I am ready to admit that it was a lie for my last article at the CSArtisan. </p>

<p>“But Minji! It can’t be a lie! I’ve been your biggest fan for the past four years, and I’ve tracked every single one of your articles; all of them have been written between 11th and 12th grade,” you might say.</p>

<p>True, most of my work has been limited to those two years. But the first time I joined the CSArtisan was in 9th grade, hosted in the awkward silences of Mr. Turf’s Zoom Room. My camera was off, of course. But behind the blank Zoom box was an anxious 14-year-old who thought this was her one shot at fitting in at high school. This club would be my ticket to making friends and finding a sense of community; there is no way I can screw this up. </p>

<p>But, like always, life happens. Although I can’t remember exactly why I didn’t attend any more meetings or accomplish the things I promised to commit to, I do have the emails I sent to the Chief Editor with excuses. Here’s one attached:</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/posts/content-goodbye-email.png" alt="Minji Cho to Alyssa Chang Ho (9/29/2020) Hey, I just wanted to let you know that for the first week of the month, I'm going to come to the newspaper club meetings and on the third week of the month, I'm heading over to the social activism club. Sorry about that." /></p>

<p>Note: I never went to the social activism club.</p>

<p>The more meetings I missed, the more shame that gripped my soul. How could I not pounce on the opportunity to participate in this club? Wasn’t one of my goals to BECOME Chief Editor? And why didn’t I finish my emails with a proper</p>

<p>end message? The embarrassment was too much, and I swore never to join the newspaper club again to save myself from being recognized and ridiculed. I could already imagine the horror:</p>

<p>“Look! That’s the girl that never wrote an article even though she promised to!”</p>

<p>I made sure that my CSArtisan experience would end there. </p>

<p>And thankfully, it didn’t. With a bit of force from Sidney Tsai to choose Newspaper as one of my classes for Creative Writing and relief that it wasn’t being hosted in Mr. Turf’s Zoom Room (little did I know he was married to Mr. Blair…), I was able to reestablish myself. </p>

<p>Sure, my embarrassment might have been an overreaction, and nobody remembers my lack of involvement in 9th grade. But my attitude of shying away from things that I initially messed up on has been something I’ve had to recognize throughout high school. CSArtisan has been a catalyst for identifying that problem, and I’m so grateful for those who supported me through those rough times. </p>

<p>Thank you, Mr. Blair, for being the guiding light of the club and graciously understanding all those times I slept in class or sobbed my eyes out. Thank you to Abbey, who listened to my charged rants and remained an optimist throughout our struggles to use Figma. And thank you to everyone who reads the CSArtisan and doesn’t immediately flip to see the games. Initially, I did regret not being able to spend more time at the CSArtisan after totally ghosting the club in 9th grade. But now, I see that mistake as the event that started my growth, and I’m so happy to have grown a bit before being able to start again. </p>

<p>Cheers,
<strong>Minji</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>MJ Cho</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although I’ve told everyone (including college applications) that I first joined the school newspaper in my junior year, I am ready to admit that it was a lie for my last article at the CSArtisan. ]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/6.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Productive Over Break</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/staying-productive-over-break/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Productive Over Break" /><published>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/staying-productive-over-break</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/staying-productive-over-break/"><![CDATA[<p>By this time of year, a lot of us are ready for school to end. Now that we’ve made it to summer though, what do we want to do with our time? While it’s important to rest, it’s a good idea to use your time productively.</p>

<p>Summer is a great opportunity for learning. If you’re aiming to catch up or get ahead, the Options for Youth (OFY) and Opportunities for Learning (OFL) organizations offer a free July program with a range of classes like History, Spanish, and Electives (talk to your counselor if you’re interested.) Or, you can complete summer workbooks, reviewing what you learned. It’s also a good idea to study for College Board tests, research for college, scholarships, and careers, or get some volunteer or work experience (see <a href="/duarte-volunteering">“Volunteer Opportunities in Duarte”</a> for more).</p>

<p>On the non-academic side of learning, you could take advantage of the break to explore your hobbies and interests. For example, you could resolve to cook more or practice a form of art you’d learn in another conservatory.</p>

<p>Whether you’re trying to catch up, avoid summer slide, take a step or two ahead, or just make the most of your summer, it pays to be productive.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="essays" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By this time of year, a lot of us are ready for school to end. Now that we’ve made it to summer though, what do we want to do with our time? While it’s important to rest, it’s a good idea to use your time productively.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/staying-productive-over-break.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/staying-productive-over-break.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Transfer Triumphs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/transfer-triumphs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transfer Triumphs" /><published>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transfer-triumphs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/transfer-triumphs/"><![CDATA[<p>With the school year coming to an end, many students are already starting to prepare for the next school year, especially students who are transferring conservatories. Transferring conservatories can cause mixed emotions: being sad to leave your previous conservatory and friends behind, but being excited for new opportunities and a new chapter! The summer is a time to cherish those memories while preparing and hyping yourself up for the upcoming change.</p>

<p>The break can also be a great time to practice and prepare skills for your new conservatory for a smoother transition in August. Another great way to prepare for your transfer this summer is reach out to students in the new conservatory about classes, instructors, and advice.</p>

<p>Change is stressful, if you are changing conservatory, try not to worry about your upcoming transfer throughout the summer. You had the courage to make a decision to make your high school experience better! You took a risk, and it’s paid off! Enjoy your break, be proud of taking a chance, and look forward to new experiences and new relationships.</p>]]></content><author><name>Bridgette Bergman</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the school year coming to an end, many students are already starting to prepare for the next school year, especially students who are transferring conservatories. Transferring conservatories can cause mixed emotions: being sad to leave your previous conservatory and friends behind, but being excited for new opportunities and a new chapter! The summer is a time to cherish those memories while preparing and hyping yourself up for the upcoming change.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Yearbook Yields More Awards!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/yearbook-yields-more-awards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yearbook Yields More Awards!" /><published>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/yearbook-yields-more-awards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/yearbook-yields-more-awards/"><![CDATA[<p>In the digital age, students have fewer and fewer tangible reminders of their time in High School. Yearbooks are one of the few physical memories students across the United States, including CSArts-SGV students, will have as a keepsake. So much time, effort, and attention to detail goes into the monumental task of accurately capturing a year at CSArts and this year, the yearbook team is releasing another award winning edition.</p>

<p>The yearbook team, advised by Mrs. Martinez, spends 9 months designing each year’s edition. The CSArtisan would like to congratulate Editor in Chief, Senior Cheska Dizon, Copy Editor, Junior Linhly Harwell, and the entire team on winning the Portfolio Anthology award! The yearbook team received the award once again this year, ranking in the top 1% of all books produced by high school and college students.</p>

<p>Capturing CSArts-SGV students as they shine brightly throughout the entire year takes many hours.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There’s a lot of planning and late nights that go into ensuring that everything from our writing to our design to our photography is cohesive and unique and represents our school well.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Dizon.</p>

<p>CSArts-SGV has a spirit and reputation on the national stage, and this shows in the combination of creativity and heart to produce this important collection of memories.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We tend to take a different approach on how we do our yearbooks, and so I think that makes our yearbooks stand out from the other 600 books across the nation,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Harwell.</p>

<p>Congratulations on another award and amazing publication!</p>]]></content><author><name>Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the digital age, students have fewer and fewer tangible reminders of their time in High School. Yearbooks are one of the few physical memories students across the United States, including CSArts-SGV students, will have as a keepsake. So much time, effort, and attention to detail goes into the monumental task of accurately capturing a year at CSArts and this year, the yearbook team is releasing another award winning edition.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>