<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-16T09:17:27-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Podcast Alert!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Podcast Alert!" /><published>2023-10-20T07:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T07:01:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/podcast-alert/"><![CDATA[<p>Loving the CSArtisan newspaper but getting sluggish eyes? No worries! The CSArtisan has a brand new podcast: “CSArtisan Talks!”  It’s our goal to give students a “literal” voice and serve the student body with the most accurate information through our podcast! You can find “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0HJcSdDT6CnREdafnh1Ilo">CSArtisan Talks</a>” on Spotify. Look for new episodes with each issue.</p>

<p>CSArtisan Talks gives students a chance to listen to the latest students news at CSArts San Gabriel Valley! Don’t have time to sit down and read the latest news? We’ve got you covered!  In the car, on the train, or while you’re out for a jog!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As the creator of the podcast, I wanted to take different external and internal factors into consideration. I was inspired by Mr. Blair, creative writing teacher and club manager of the CSArtisan, who taught about making all stories and reports applicable to everyone! And CSArts has the core valley of  excellence and equity for all, while fostering a nurturing environment of creativity, respect, and collaboration. I hope to exemplify this  idea of being inclusive and creating an audio version with a podcast is the perfect way to meet these goals.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Karina Yue, Producer and Host of “CSArtisan Talks”</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When I heard about the podcast, I loved it, such a great way for everyone to listen!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Vana Kojikian, fellow writer of the CSArtisan.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Honestly, listening instead of reading the newspaper is so much more enticing. I’ll definitely go check it out, and everyone else should too!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Alyeen Park</p>

<p>You can find “CSArtisan Talks” <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0HJcSdDT6CnREdafnh1Ilo">on Spotify</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loving the CSArtisan newspaper but getting sluggish eyes? No worries! The CSArtisan has a brand new podcast: “CSArtisan Talks!” It’s our goal to give students a “literal” voice and serve the student body with the most accurate information through our podcast! You can find “CSArtisan Talks” on Spotify. Look for new episodes with each issue.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/csartisan-talks.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/csartisan-talks.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Hispanic Heritage Month</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Hispanic Heritage Month" /><published>2023-10-20T07:00:35-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T07:00:35-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/hispanic-heritage-month-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Each September, Latino and Hispanic people throughout The United States observe their countries’ Independence Day on September 15th! The celebrations of culture and history don’t stop there!  Hispanic Heritage Month originally started as a week in August, 1968 by President Johnson. In August, 1988 the week was extended to a month (from September 15th to October 15th) by President Reagan. The declaration was created to celebrate Hispanic/Latino independence days and culture with parades, traditional foods, and parties.</p>

<p>The celebration recognizes the 64 million Americans of Hispanic/Latino descent, and their  important historical contributions. From political activism, to art, to entreprenuership, Hispanics and Latinos from the U.S have shaped the country into what it is today. Throughout the month, corporations like Starbucks, Target, and Barnes and Noble have participated in Hispanic Heritage month by promoting and incorporating the work of Latino and Hispanic people into their products. Barnes and Noble dedicated a wall specifically for books written by Hispanic authors, while companies like Starbucks and Target released merchandise specifically created by Hispanic artists.</p>

<p>At CSArts, Spanish teachers design special lessons during the month in order to  teach students about the many different cultures and traditions surrounding people of Hispanic and Latin origin. AP Spanish teacher Andrea Nelson, says the designated month  gives students a break from exams, and gives them insight into the culture and the important role the Hispanic and Latino community plays in the U.S.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Recognition and celebration are a good starting point for our year round focus on Latino culture. Two aspects are most important for AP Spanish, Spanish 4 Honors and Spanish 3 Honors: we celebrate by using the language as a means of communication and develop cultural appreciation for Latino influences around the world.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The learning experience isn’t just focused on books. Students passing by Spanish classrooms in the 400’s will hear music and the sounds of students competing as they play Spanish games in order to deepen their understanding and appreciation of the language and culture. The celebration doesn’t end there!</p>

<p>Just weeks after the end of Hispanic Heritage Month, El Dia de los Muertos will begin, honoring and celebrating the lives of those who have passed away. There are many traditions, holidays, and events etched into Hispanic and Latino culture that are worth celebrating and recognizing, as they have such a large impact on the U.S too. To learn more and connect with Hispanic and Latin culture, feel free to pass by a Spanish classroom, visit a LUCHA meeting, or even just watch some classic telenovelas!</p>]]></content><author><name>Juliet Martinez &amp; Sophia Gutierrez</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Each September, Latino and Hispanic people throughout The United States observe their countries’ Independence Day on September 15th! The celebrations of culture and history don’t stop there! Hispanic Heritage Month originally started as a week in August, 1968 by President Johnson. In August, 1988 the week was extended to a month (from September 15th to October 15th) by President Reagan. The declaration was created to celebrate Hispanic/Latino independence days and culture with parades, traditional foods, and parties.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/hispanic-heritage-month-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/hispanic-heritage-month-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bell-in Cocomelon</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/cocomelon-bell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bell-in Cocomelon" /><published>2023-10-20T07:00:30-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T07:00:30-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/cocomelon-bell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/cocomelon-bell/"><![CDATA[<p>By now, most of us here at CSArts have heard the new school bell, and we are all asking the same question: “What the hell?” Previous students at CSArts had been hearing the same bell for years, and without warning, change arrived. Week after week, the campus heard a variety of tunes, leaving many students wondering what tune would be assaulting their ears next.</p>

<p>Some students like the change, but their opinion doesn’t matter. The majority hate it, like Braedon Younger (CW ‘24). He expressed:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The bell is gonna make me rip out my ears.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Agreeing with Younger’s opinion, students add on that it sounds like the intune of a popular kid’s YouTube channel, Cocomelon. </p>

<p>The CSArtisan asked the assistant principal, Mrs. Read, to clarify the bell situation.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The PA system works better with a wireless system so that the little chime that [used to] happen at the end of the blocks doesn’t reach… the 400s…[the tune is] too short so we have to elongate it.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Due to this, Admin experimented with different audios, that came as default tunes with the wireless system such as ones that sounded like a chorus of trumpets, a bass-booted C# note, and a literal fire alarm.</p>

<p>In the end, Mrs. Read chose the current bell because of its simplicity and long enough tune. It was not intentionally made to sound like Cocomelon, it was just an arpeggio that came with the default sound pack.</p>

<p>If you hate it that much, Mrs. Read did mention that there might be a contest near the end of the year to determine the new bell:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want to just spread the word that that’ll be a possibility in the spring, people can start composing whatever they want [for the bell].” </p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>MJ Cho &amp; Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By now, most of us here at CSArts have heard the new school bell, and we are all asking the same question: “What the hell?” Previous students at CSArts had been hearing the same bell for years, and without warning, change arrived. Week after week, the campus heard a variety of tunes, leaving many students wondering what tune would be assaulting their ears next.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/cocomelon-bell.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/cocomelon-bell.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Art Marketeers</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/art-marketeers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Art Marketeers" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/art-marketeers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/art-marketeers/"><![CDATA[<p>School events are beginning to pick up again this year and the Visual Arts Conservatory is hosting yet another Art Marketeers sale! With this exciting, artist alley- style event, a handful of our Visual Arts students will get a hand at practicing skills in customer service, networking, and product design. With business cards and creative table set ups, this event will be a wonderful mixture of both professionalism and self-expression.</p>

<p>Art comes in many forms and the market will be a prime example of how different mediums of art can become something practical, decorative, or even both at once. From cute crocheted hats to colorful hand sewn dolls, there’s something for everyone.</p>

<p>The event helps support both the Visual Arts Conservatory and the students themselves so some of the members have provided an exciting look into what kinds of products will be at the market this year.  Plans are for the event in December and March.  We’ll keep you up to date!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am deeply thankful to Ms. Betters and Ms. Ma for organizing this event. It’s such an exciting opportunity! All of the peers I’ve spoken to have been working hard on their products. I’m very excited to see how it all turns out,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Arianna Ramras (VA ‘26)</p>

<p><em>Handmade products courtesy of: Angelina Lam, Arianna Ramras, Joyce Shaw, Sara Tran</em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/artmarketeers1.jpg" alt="Handmade products" /></p>

<p>Many handmade products will be featured but digital art can also take the form of a physical object through prints, stickers, keychains, and more.</p>

<p><em>Digitally drawn products courtesy of: Diane Park, Carlie Wong, Tyree Dilihay</em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/misc/artmarketeers2.jpg" alt="Digital art products" /></p>

<p>There will be lunch sales in December and March and a final sale during the schools Battle of the Bands in which art pieces like these will be available!</p>]]></content><author><name>Akira Mueller</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[School events are beginning to pick up again this year and the Visual Arts Conservatory is hosting yet another Art Marketeers sale! With this exciting, artist alley- style event, a handful of our Visual Arts students will get a hand at practicing skills in customer service, networking, and product design. With business cards and creative table set ups, this event will be a wonderful mixture of both professionalism and self-expression.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Breaking News: Help Armenia!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/help-armenia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking News: Help Armenia!" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/help-armenia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/help-armenia/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-views-expressed-in-this-article-are-solely-those-of-the-student-journalist-and-do-not-necessarily-reflect-the-views-of-the-csartisan-or-csarts-sgv">The views expressed in this article are solely those of the student journalist and do not necessarily reflect the views of The CSArtisan or CSArts-SGV.</h3>

<p>Have you heard about the blockade in Artsakh? You probably haven’t, which is why we need to raise awareness and educate the people around us. It is crucial for the community to recognize the tragic impacts of this blockade on the Armenian people of Artsakh.
Azerbaijan is responsible for the blockade in Artsakh. This oppression of Armenia and Artsakh has existed for too many decades. Turkey and Azerbaijan have teamed together to ethnically cleanse all of Armenia and Artsakh from Armenians.</p>

<p>This blockade ran for 9 months and cut Armenians off from the rest of the world and from getting any resources from outside, such as food, medical supplies, and more. Azerbejian even blocked the Lachin Corridor, which is also known as the lifeline of people living in Artsakh. It is the only way people living in Artsakh could get resources. This caused starvation and medical complications, and many innocent people died because of this. <strong>The constant refusal of Azerbaijan to lift the blockade violates basic human rights.</strong> They are continuing this oppression of Armenians from the Armenian Genocide in 1915, where 1.2 million Armenians were killed at the Ottoman Empire’s hand. Which is a genocide that Turkey has refused to admit they were responsible for, and spent thousands of dollars to cover it up by paying journalists and news channels to report the Armenian Genocide never happened.</p>

<p>Last month, Azerbaijan bombed Artsakh using drones and missile strikes, bombing civilian areas like schools and churches, while their soldiers destroyed cultural sites and artifacts. Azerbaijan soldiers have even gone as far as posting videos of them shooting innocent civilians and destroying graves while laughing. Armenians are being killed by Azerbaijan and Turkey for the reason of them being Armenians. This ethnic cleansing of the people in the Armenian land of Artsakh by Azerbaijan(which is backed by Turkey) needs to end. Turkey and Azerbaijan have targeted Armenians solely based on ethnic hatred. And now, for the first time in 5,000 years, no Armenians remain in Artsakh. It is time to recognize these events and end them so there can be peace in the region.</p>

<p>How does this relate to us today? Los Angeles has the largest Armenian population in the U.S. Armenian students at CSArts in the Armenian Student Union (ASU) have been doing everything in the hopes of saving their ancestral land and preventing another genocide.</p>

<h3 id="how-can-you-help">How can you help?</h3>

<p>The club is available for anyone to join; it’s for anyone who is interested in helping and advocating for this issue. ASU has been sending emails to government officials in hopes of flooding their inboxes until they have no choice but to help. Any student here that is interested in joining will be an amazing help in making a difference. Simply by reading this article, more people have been educated so this event in history is remembered.</p>

<p>ANCA is an organization working to get the U.S. to help its Armenian community and sanction the Azerbaijan government for its crimes. On <a href="https://anca.org/">its website</a>, you can access emails you can send to show your support.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The views expressed in this article are solely those of the student journalist and do not necessarily reflect the views of The CSArtisan or CSArts-SGV.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/help-armenia.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/help-armenia.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Senior Center is Looking for Art</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/senior-center/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Senior Center is Looking for Art" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/senior-center</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/senior-center/"><![CDATA[<p>Calling all Visual Arts students! Students are organizing a visual arts showcase at the Duarte Senior Center on December 8th and want you to join in. Actual “Physical” art is needed, like: paintings, drawings, sculptures, and graphic designs. Just drop off your art to Ms. Ma including any information you would like to have displayed with your work. If you would like to have your artwork showcased, just fill out the <a href="https://qrco.de/beSDyN">Google Form</a>!</p>

<h3 id="holiday-in-the-park---performers-needed">HOLIDAY IN THE PARK - PERFORMERS NEEDED</h3>

<p>The Duarte Senior Center is also  putting on a “Holiday in the Park” on December 10th starting at 4pm at Beardslee Park.  They  need performers interested in sharing various talents during the festivities. For more information contact Rylee Birtja at rylee.birtja@sgv.csarts.net.</p>]]></content><author><name>Mason Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Calling all Visual Arts students! Students are organizing a visual arts showcase at the Duarte Senior Center on December 8th and want you to join in. Actual “Physical” art is needed, like: paintings, drawings, sculptures, and graphic designs. Just drop off your art to Ms. Ma including any information you would like to have displayed with your work. If you would like to have your artwork showcased, just fill out the Google Form!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Telltale Bell</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/telltale-bell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Telltale Bell" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/telltale-bell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/telltale-bell/"><![CDATA[<p>It is impossible to say how the idea first entered my brain; but once conceived, it haunted me day and night. ‘Twas a lonely and slow evening when that idea first formulated, a thought that I wish never entered my twisted mind; to replace our old bell with a new ring. Object there was none. Passion there was none. I loved the old bell.</p>

<p>You fancy me mad. I know the old bell is no more and I am the one responsible for its demise. But yet, hour by hour, day by day, I still hear it. Its haunting melody lingers in my head: <em>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</em>.</p>

<p>I don’t know what urged me to stay after hours that night. The 5 o’clock bell rang, the new one, the wretched one, and yet I chose to stay. I tried to occupy myself by doing administrative work. But, before I knew it, my eyes began to bear the weight of my work, the pull of slumber creeping up my spine. And then, just like that, I heard it.</p>

<p><em>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</em>. This wasn’t in my head. It was as if I heard it bellowing from the PA speakers. I didn’t think much of it for it was late and I was exhausted. It was only an earworm; a catchy, but long-dead tune. I went back to my work.</p>

<p>It only became worrisome once I heard the bell again. The same eerie jingle. <strong>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</strong>. I pinched myself to ensure that I was awake and to my dismay, I felt the sharp pain of my own nip linger; proving my consciousness.</p>

<p><em>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</em>. It couldn’t be! Have I gone mad? I paced the floor of my office to and fro with heavy, pensive, strides. <em>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</em>. It only grew louder - louder - louder! Oh god, what do I do? What can I do?</p>

<p>“Villains!” I shriek. “I repent! I’ll revive the old bell! I’ll revive it!” I raved. 
My head hit the desk and I awoke. A sliver of pale sunlight crept through the blinds of my office. I checked the time on my watch; it read 8:29. Could it be? Was it all a dream? The clock struck 8:30. <em>Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. Hello, CSArts. We are CSArts</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Maleyna Alcisto</name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is impossible to say how the idea first entered my brain; but once conceived, it haunted me day and night. ‘Twas a lonely and slow evening when that idea first formulated, a thought that I wish never entered my twisted mind; to replace our old bell with a new ring. Object there was none. Passion there was none. I loved the old bell.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CSArts, A Magnet for Creativity</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/magnet-for-creativity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSArts, A Magnet for Creativity" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/magnet-for-creativity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/magnet-for-creativity/"><![CDATA[<p>CSArts was built on a foundation of creativity where art meets scholastics. From academics to conservatory, CSArts uses a different approach to learning. Students throughout Los Angeles and Orange Counties brave long commutes because of the many opportunities CSArts offers. The CSArts conservatory doesn’t just attract students, it attracts instructors interested in sharing their knowledge and talents</p>

<p>Before coming to CSArts to work as a creative writing instructor, Pasha McKenley worked at two other schools. She taught young children plays and monologues. Her students performed onstage, and those performances ignited a passion in other students throughout the school! From plays to monologues, students took advantage of this new opportunity to share their voices through acting and performing. Students even got the change to perform their own works in slam poetry.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Usually, I was the person bringing creativity to the schools,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>McKenly said.</p>

<p>This not only increased passion in students for the arts, it also helped improve communication among students and their peers, and improved the culture of the school.</p>

<p>Hearing about CSArts, McKenley thought the opportunity to work in a school that focused on the arts would be a good fit. After her first visit, she knew she was meant to teach at CSArts.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There was some guy playing the violin and there were girls tap dancing over there… I was like, where am I? Like on this island of bliss?”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While most schools offer artistic opportunites, not all encourage students to follow creative paths. Creative Writing Conservatory Director Timothy Gomez taught at many different schools, each with different ways of incorporating creativity. Gomez said that one middle school where he taught had a decent theater and visual arts program, but that it was limited.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They ended up de-prioritizing their creative skills and finding more traditional pathways, while only exploring their art as a hobby. Or some of our most talented artists ending up leaving our school and going elsewhere to a school that could prioritize their creativity and had the resources for it.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>CSArts prioritized creativity for students and teachers, which led Gomez here last Summer.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I see a real social comfort here that I didn’t see at my other schools. Students feel fully safe to be themselves and explore who they are, and I think this is a product of allowing them to explore their creative lives more fully. I wanted to engage more with my creative life. At CSArts, I get to have the freedom to explore the exact kind of material that I’d like to with my students. And I get to value their creative work in the exact ways that I think matters.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>CSArts continues to attract students and teachers alike because it offers a blank canvas and the tools for success in both academics and conservatory. This balance of art and scholastics continues to produce students who are prepared for their next chapter after graduation.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSArts was built on a foundation of creativity where art meets scholastics. From academics to conservatory, CSArts uses a different approach to learning. Students throughout Los Angeles and Orange Counties brave long commutes because of the many opportunities CSArts offers. The CSArts conservatory doesn’t just attract students, it attracts instructors interested in sharing their knowledge and talents]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/magnet-for-creativity.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/magnet-for-creativity.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Security at School</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/security-at-school/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Security at School" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/security-at-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/security-at-school/"><![CDATA[<p>School security dominates national headlines. Concerns about rising rates of violence across the country have led to the implementation of new policies to keep students, teachers and staff safe. This includes practicing emergency drills, educating students on what to look for, and implementing technology to enhance safety around campuses. But what does school safety look like at CSArts?</p>

<p>School-wide drills prepare students and staff on what to do and where to go in emergency situations. Staff is also trained in overdose prevention, including the safe administration of Narcan.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As administrators we’re trained in various ways, CPR and First Aid, and we have a nurse. If things are happening, we’ve been trained on how to respond,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>assistant Principal, Nicole Read, said.</p>

<p>CSArts continues its dedication to campus safety by contracting security staff. The presence of security guards, according to Read, increases the safety and security of the campus, as they can directly identify and manage any kind of internal/external security threats.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Say Cheese, students! You are on camera!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Security cameras are peppered around campus and school administrators say these additions are instrumental in maintaining security. The video cameras provide visuals and double -check student or staff observations of potential security breaches.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We typically have only used them after the fact. So if something is reported and we have to do an investigation, we pull out footage…we can go back and get the information,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Read said.</p>

<p>Recently, the school implemented a new form of surveillance that uses live-streaming. The hub for these cameras is in Mr. Metoyer’s office, in the form of a big screen above Mr. Metoyer’s door. The cameras, video and live streamed, in tandem with the other security measures are instrumental in addressing real-time security concerns on campus.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Mr Metoyer saw some people behind the 400s…that didn’t look like students, and it turned out to be parents on some kind of a tour, but it was like- what’s going on? So he radioed security and they checked in,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Read said. While in that instance there were no problems, students and staff should know that the combination of training, staff security, bathroom sensors and the newest technology is keeping The CSArts campus safe.</p>

<p>Students are taking notice of the new additions.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I feel that the emergency stations on campus are a great idea. Drugs are becoming a big problem in school,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said one freshman student. The promotion and access to resources on assessing an overdose-related situation is essential, and will ensure that if there is an overdose on campus, there are people with training and Narcan to save a life.</p>

<p>While students and school administrators are trained and equipped, school security also relies on students. Students are here for the longest amount of time, and can more easily detect when something might be happening. That’s why CSArts depends on the student body to use the resources available.</p>

<p>If you see something, say something! CSArts also has a text-to-tip number that you can use 24 hours a day at 626-531-1271.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon, Samson Khachatryan, &amp; Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[School security dominates national headlines. Concerns about rising rates of violence across the country have led to the implementation of new policies to keep students, teachers and staff safe. This includes practicing emergency drills, educating students on what to look for, and implementing technology to enhance safety around campuses. But what does school safety look like at CSArts?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/security-at-school.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/security-at-school.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Return of the Painted Pumpkins</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/painted-pumpkins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Return of the Painted Pumpkins" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/painted-pumpkins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/painted-pumpkins/"><![CDATA[<p>The approach to Halloween means CSArts Visual Arts students are painting their way into the spooky season. Each year students take simple craft pumpkins home and bring back incredible pieces of art, all part of CSArt’s annual Painted Pumpkin Auction. 
This year, students came up with a wide variety of innovative designs. Some were sculpted, stacked, hollowed out; some were big, some small, some even sideways. Many featured faces, windows, dioramas, eyeballs, characters from various media and more. Students used paint, clay, glue, and paper to transform the gourds into “gourd”-geously wicked art pieces.
Participants shared some reasons why they liked painting the pumpkins and attending the event:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Freedom of creativity, because you can do pretty much anything.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Elise Hsu (VA ‘26)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The food. It’s pretty diverse and there’s also gluten free food; it’s hard to get good gluten free food.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Yaretzi García Lopez (VA ‘25)</p>

<p>“Halloween is one of my favorite holidays so it’s really fun to celebrate it with my classmates.” -Bonita Hefty (VA ‘28)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Meeting different people, and I feel like the games were fun to play with other people that you might have not met normally. And it was really fun to see all of the pumpkins.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>says Luca Ramos (VA ‘27)</p>

<p>The patch of Halloween-themed pumpkins were displayed in the school lobby, where people could place their bets on their favorite design. On the night of the Spooky Painted Pumpkin Bash, students, families and staff joined together in the school cafeteria for a night of costumes, refreshments, and games. Some attendees of the shared which pumpkin they felt was the scariest:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Probably the one titled Yummy. It just scared me, it made me feel itchy,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said one.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I think the scariest for me [was] the lady’s head with the flowing hair coming out. That was really creepy. And the maggot one was a close second,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>another one added.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There was one where it was carved out and it had people in it. Not a lot of them were really carved out like that one was, so I thought that was different, that was like ‘ooh, that’s scary’.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said Khai Dimaculangan (VOC ‘26)</p>

<p>At the end of the event, following a thunderous drumroll from the audience, the winning painted pumpkins were announced. The awards given out featured a number of different categories:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Cutest: “Mickey Spooky Treats” by Jayden Vosberg (VA ‘28)</li>
  <li>Scariest: “Pumpkin Puppy” by Chanel Garcia (VA ‘27)</li>
  <li>Funniest: “Little C. Pumpkin” by Faye Cardella (VA ‘25)</li>
  <li>Most Creative: “Butterflies” by Lilyana Mortellaro (VA ‘26)</li>
  <li>Most Realistic: “Yummy” by Jiashan Lyu (VA ‘28)</li>
</ul>

<p>Congratulations to the winners and all other participants for their hard work, creativity, and artistic embodiment of the Halloween spirit!</p>]]></content><author><name>Danica Chen</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The approach to Halloween means CSArts Visual Arts students are painting their way into the spooky season. Each year students take simple craft pumpkins home and bring back incredible pieces of art, all part of CSArt’s annual Painted Pumpkin Auction. This year, students came up with a wide variety of innovative designs. Some were sculpted, stacked, hollowed out; some were big, some small, some even sideways. Many featured faces, windows, dioramas, eyeballs, characters from various media and more. Students used paint, clay, glue, and paper to transform the gourds into “gourd”-geously wicked art pieces. Participants shared some reasons why they liked painting the pumpkins and attending the event:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/painted-pumpkins.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/images/posts/painted-pumpkins.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>