<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-21T09:13:59-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CSArtisan</title><subtitle>Explore CSArts related news stories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Update on the Bathroom Vape Sensors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update on the Bathroom Vape Sensors" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:30-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:30-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bathroom-sensors/"><![CDATA[<p>With the recent changes in vape sensors in the bathrooms, the CSArtisan interviewed Mr. Metoyer to clear up rumors circulating around the campus, detecting what’s true and what’s false.</p>

<h3 id="what-factors-led-to-the-decision-to-invest-in-the-detectors">What factors led to the decision to invest in the detectors?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Student, parent, and teacher feedback over the past couple of years. And while we were doing focus groups and research for our most recent WASC accreditation. So this work started before I got here a couple of years ago. And that work led our team to believe one of the best ways to address what I heard was a pervasive amount of smoking.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-process-do-students-go-through-when-these-detectors-are-used-for-investigation">What process do students go through when these detectors are used for investigation?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Our practice and it’s an evolving practice… But our practice right now is: if the vape detectors go off at a certain level, that indicates that there might be some vaping going on. Our staff is immediately informed, and security brings that student to the office for a quick search. We try to do them as quickly as possible. And then students get to go back to class. However, we live in an imperfect world, and I’m an imperfect person who also has scheduled meetings. So if there’s a meeting, if I’m in a meeting, and someone gets brought in, sadly, we will ask that person to wait because it’s not realistic to send that person back if they’re suspected of having done this thing.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="if-a-vape-device-is-found-how-is-the-situation-typically-handled">If a vape device is found, how is the situation typically handled?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>There’s an ED code against students having tobacco products, marijuana products, drug paraphernalia, and those types of things on campus. They’re held accountable, according to the ED Code. Typically, that’s suspension. I can’t think of when it hasn’t been a suspension in my tenure… We believe in restorative practices here. So a student who is suspended does earn demerits, but has an opportunity to make those demerits go away through the use of a Restorative Action Plan, which is 100%, the student’s responsibility to opt in and participate in.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-are-some-examples-of-some-things-that-might-be-in-the-restorative-action-plan">What are some examples of some things that might be in the Restorative Action Plan?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>People have written songs, content therapy, done things around the house for their parents, and volunteered to work extra time at the front desk. One person did beach cleanup. Others have done PowerPoint presentations. One person did an analysis on parking practices. So it would be impactful for them as it relates to why a student received that type of suspension.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-data-has-been-gathered-before-and-after-implementing-the-vape-sensors">What data has been gathered before and after implementing the vape sensors?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Since full implementation in early January, from that week to the next week, the number of detections went down by 50%. By the next week, it went down 50%. And the next week, it probably went down 70%. So either we’ve gotten better at gaming the system, or we’re choosing to make better choices, I’m hoping we’re choosing to make better choices. But I’m realistic, and understand that people have been smoking in bathrooms and high schools since before I was born… It’s my hope that it’s gotten a little better. At the end of the year, I’ll probably do like some many focus groups and try to talk to some students and see what they’ve seen from January to June, and see where we’re at.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-is-the-most-commonly-confiscated-item">What is the most commonly confiscated item?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Lighters and nicotine vapes. A lighter alone is a suspension; it’s one of those things in the ED code listed under like cigarette products.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="how-does-the-vape-system-discern-between-substances">How does the vape system discern between substances?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>We get a report from the base detector system. It has different types of particles where it will say, this might be more likely this. And that differentiates between colognes, Nicotine, and marijuana. But the system is also there to detect noise and keep students safe…So in case there’s a bunch of people screaming, which is typical high school behavior, there’s noise peaks.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="why-have-some-students-have-had-their-phones-taken">Why have some students have had their phones taken?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because it’s an investigation about what happened within the bathroom at that time. We found that sometimes these investigation leads to other people who aren’t in the hallway at that time…When students have their phones, misinformation gets posted on the internet. People get told to go hide your drugs, and it negatively impacts our ability to get some real information. It’s not a confiscation. We hold it. We don’t go into it. We don’t do anything. The minute that we’re done with that investigation, bone comes back.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="what-are-the-resources-or-support-available-for-students-dealing-with-substance-related-challenges-on-campus">What are the resources or support available for students dealing with substance-related challenges on campus?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>All of our counselors have access to information and direct support for students who are struggling with drug use… there’s also a Wellness Center. We have a thing called Care Solace, which is a free referral service for anyone in our organization, not just students, but teachers and any of our people that need some direct support”</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Minji Cho &amp; Abigail Risdon</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the recent changes in vape sensors in the bathrooms, the CSArtisan interviewed Mr. Metoyer to clear up rumors circulating around the campus, detecting what’s true and what’s false.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bathroom-sensors.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/bathroom-sensors.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blame It on the Rain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blame It on the Rain" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:25-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:25-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blame-it-on-the-rain/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Picture this:</em> CSArts students in rain jackets crowd the pathways to classes, umbrellas crashing together, it’s rainy season in Southern California. The problem is some parts of Southern California received their annual rainfall in just two days, with parts of the San Gabriel Valley getting 10 inches for the first storm, and another 3 inches last week. Students who love the rain are all happy and delighted, but other students are used to the California sun, and hate the wet weather on our <em>“outdoor campus.”</em></p>

<p>The tarps around campus are meant to provide shade to students and can’t handle rain at this intensity, which leads to students getting splashed and soggy. Throughout the rainy season, the campus has witnessed flooding in many different parts of the school due to the heavier than normal rain. Plus, leaves, wood chips, and other objects clogging up the drains.</p>

<p>One of the major challenges is outdoor nutrition and lunch lines. CSArts administrators have addressed these issues, discussing moving the lines to a covered area. Also, there are shade covers near these lines that are not being used due to the fact that the shade covers cannot handle the amount of rain with these record breaking storms.</p>

<p>The buildings in the 400s have leaks in the roofs. With all the umbrellas, it causes traffic jams in the narrow path when students are heading to classes.</p>

<p>CSArts admin are working on solutions for problems on campus, but the problem extends outside of campus, with Duarte’s infrastructure  being challenged by mudslides from the foothills. With the way the sewage and water works in Duarte, everything comes from the high mountains and hills to the low streets, creating more collection and more standing water. CSArts does their best to address possible problems before it rains.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The leakage in the gym was affected by Duarte Unified putting new air exchangers on the roof and those connections aren’t fully sealed as well as they could be. So there were leaks in the gym,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>assistant principal Mr. Metoyer said. He is also aware of the water puddling up in the 100s, 200s, and the Quad. The problem is that cash, unlike rain, doesn’t fall from the sky.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We have a limited capital budget and that’s the budget that we use every summer to fix things,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Metoyer said.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It will be hard to spend a decent amount of that budget when it rains, which is only a few days a year.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Admin is being focusing on what they can control and fix, with these goals:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Replacing the tarps with one individual durable tarp that slightly bends at both ends so there are no open spaces</li>
  <li>Mats that soak up water efficiently to be put near the front doors of each classroom</li>
  <li>2 buckets for each classroom to put umbrellas</li>
</ul>

<p>You can always reach out to admin with any concerns or ideas on how to better deal with the rainy weather.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon &amp; Ares Ho</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Picture this: CSArts students in rain jackets crowd the pathways to classes, umbrellas crashing together, it’s rainy season in Southern California. The problem is some parts of Southern California received their annual rainfall in just two days, with parts of the San Gabriel Valley getting 10 inches for the first storm, and another 3 inches last week. Students who love the rain are all happy and delighted, but other students are used to the California sun, and hate the wet weather on our “outdoor campus.”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/blame-it-on-the-rain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/blame-it-on-the-rain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wrestling with the Words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wrestling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wrestling with the Words" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:20-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:20-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wrestling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wrestling/"><![CDATA[<p>This semester, creative writing teacher Daniel Strasberger introduced a new and unique course to the conservatory’s class repertoire: Storytelling in Pro Wrestling. </p>

<p>A long time fan of the sport, Mr. Strasberger jumped on the opportunity to teach this class when it first arose, but he wasn’t so sure it would get a good response from the students.
 </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>It is very niche; it is very weird. So I was definitely worried if there wouldn’t be as much engagement.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But with professional wrestling’s rich storytelling, combined with Mr. Strasberger’s passion, the class was bound to attract some. With a class size of 20 students, it’s safe to say it did.</p>

<p>Pro wrestling, while originating from legitimately competition-based sport, has long since been scripted– focusing more on showy moves, characters, and plotlines that garner massive audience reactions. According to Mr. Strasberger, this writing is “the purest form of storytelling.” He makes the joke often, arguing that “it’s good and bad. That’s the pureness of it.”</p>

<p>Students’ reasons for taking the class varied widely. When Santiago Awori signed up for it, they were already working on a wrestler character, and joined so that they could learn “how to write her in her own story.” Now that they’re in the class, they’re finding the variety of matches and promos shown in the class valuable. On the other hand, Zoe Lopez is excited to start writing characters and stories, having grown up around wrestling.</p>

<p>The class is proving to be promising, and students are already finding value and fun in it. Mr. Strasberger claims there are more exciting things to come, too, with a field trip to meet with real professional wrestlers in the works.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dominic Anaya Gulaya &amp; Ada Schmidt</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This semester, creative writing teacher Daniel Strasberger introduced a new and unique course to the conservatory’s class repertoire: Storytelling in Pro Wrestling. ]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Course Selection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/course-selection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Course Selection" /><published>2024-02-23T04:00:15-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T04:00:15-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/course-selection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/course-selection/"><![CDATA[<p>Honors, AP, and Citrus College classes are available at CSArts. If you haven’t taken advantage of these courses because you are unsure of the workload, we talked with students about the courses.</p>

<h3 id="honors">Honors:</h3>

<p>Honors classes are to help students prepare for college-level work. There are many options on campus, including: Honors Biology, Honors Chemistry, Honors English, and other language classes. “Honors Chem is a lot of work and challenging at times, especially if Chemistry is not a subject you are interested in. But once you understand the topic it gets easier.” If you take an honors course, you can expect more rigorous assignments and an increase in homework compared to CP classes.</p>

<h3 id="advanced-placement-courses-ap">Advanced Placement Courses (AP):</h3>

<p>AP courses offer even more advantages but students should expect an 5 additional hours of homework per week. Although AP courses add on extra work, students have the option of taking the AP exam at the end of the year to get college credit, plus they look very good on transcripts! Some examples of AP classes that students have said have nightly homework: AP U.S. History, AP World History, AP Physics, AP Statistics.</p>

<h3 id="citrus-college-courses">Citrus College Courses:</h3>

<p>Students can start their college career at CSArts!  While performing well on the AP test can get you possible college credit, Citrus College classes are college classes, with college credit. The classes are challenging, but they also help students shave off time until graduation and save money.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The Citrus College courses really helped me understand what it’s like to be in a college class and equip me with experience for after I graduate,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>said MJ Cho (CW’24)</p>

<p>Additionally, if you take an honors or AP class, your GPA goes automatically up one point. This means if you earn a C, the C will show up on the transcript, but that 2.0 GPA, changes to a 3.0!</p>

<p>Everything you need to know about all the courses is in the CSArts curriculum handbook. Hopefully, this gives you an idea of what you may be interested in to select your courses for the next year!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vana Kojikian</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Honors, AP, and Citrus College classes are available at CSArts. If you haven’t taken advantage of these courses because you are unsure of the workload, we talked with students about the courses.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comic: Water Fountain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comic: Water Fountain" /><published>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spencers-show-1/"><![CDATA[<p>Read “Spencer’s Show Pt 1: Water Fountain”</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/comics/comic-water-fountain.jpg" alt="Spencer's Show Pt 1: Water Fountain" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Sofia Ruiz</name></author><category term="comics" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read “Spencer’s Show Pt 1: Water Fountain”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-fountain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/comic-water-fountain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reel Potential: Latest Update on the Newest Program</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reel-potential/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reel Potential: Latest Update on the Newest Program" /><published>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reel-potential</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reel-potential/"><![CDATA[<p>With many students hearing whispers around campus about a possible new Film/Television conservatory, there are lots of questions to be answered. So, the big question is, will there be a new Film/TV conservatory? Not exactly.</p>

<p>Dr. Cook, Assistant Principal at CSARTs-SGV says that Film, Television, and Media Technology won’t have its own conservatory.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We were thinking of doing a Film, Television and Media Technologies Conservatory but the more we started talking to the [other conservatory] directors, so many of the conservatories wanted to be a part of it.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>With this in mind, the school decided to make a Film, Television and Media technologies program, meaning there will be multiple classes spread through already existing conservatories. This way, students in Production &amp; Design, Creative Writing, Acting, etc. will be able to take Film, Television and Media Art classes related to their own conservatories.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We thought that it would actually be able to serve more students if we offered it as a program.” Dr. Cook said.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Another question that came to many students’ minds was how the school will be funding the new program. Especially considering the cut on this year’s conservatory schedule due to under-funding issues. Dr. Cook explained that the school received an SWP (Strong Workforce Program) Grant from the state of California, which is designed to offer training to students who are looking to enter the workforce after high school. He added that this is the same grant that is being used to boost the school’s E-Sports and Computer Science programs.</p>

<p>The upcoming program represents an initiative aimed at providing students with a diverse skill set to meet the needs of today’s job market. Across various disciplines, the curriculum will offer a range of classes designed to equip students with practical skills in film, television, and media technologies. These classes will cover topics such as camera production, acting for the camera, digital video content creation, film making, script writing, film scoring, etc. Scheduled to begin in the fall of 2025, the program will provide students with an opportunity to explore their interests and develop their abilities within a supportive educational environment.</p>

<p>Although students will have to wait to take any Film, Television, and Media technology classes through our school until Fall 2025, UCLA’s Film and Television Summer Institute allows students to take classes in Digital Filmmaking, Writing for TV, Cinematography, Traditional Animation, and Media Parks. The program also allows students to experience the UCLA campus while earning college credit and networking with other emerging artist from around the globe. Students who are interested in the UCLA summer institute can find more information on Student Square or by speaking directly with their school counselor.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayleen Park &amp; Evyn Clayton</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With many students hearing whispers around campus about a possible new Film/Television conservatory, there are lots of questions to be answered. So, the big question is, will there be a new Film/TV conservatory? Not exactly.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/reel-potential.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/reel-potential.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re Just Our Type</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blood-drive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You’re Just Our Type" /><published>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blood-drive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blood-drive/"><![CDATA[<p>There is a major shortage of blood in the U.S. according to The American Red Cross, and CSArts students and faculty rolled up their sleeves to give the gift of life to two different blood drives.</p>

<p>Students also had the opportunity to help with registration, event scheduling, public outreach, and clean-up and earned volunteer hours for their hard work.</p>

<p>Over 70 donors rolled up their sleeves and donated 73 pints of blood. This amount could save as many as 220 lives!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Partnering with the Red Cross to host a blood drive at CSArts has been extremely important to me as I am able to directly connect students to the opportunity of helping those in need. I strive to create a positive environment so students and community members continue to help in any way possible,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>sophomore Makenna Bear said.</p>

<p>CSArts-SGV also collaborated with Duarte High School’s Interact Club to host a blood drive with City of Hope in order to further their impact.</p>

<p>Approximately 65 donors made up of staff and students donated in this separate event and students understand by donating, they can make a difference and save lives.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Hosting a blood drive is essential to the community right now. Everything we can do to help patients and families, especially within our local community is crucial. I hope this inspires others to also lend a hand and make a difference in the world,“</p>
</blockquote>

<p>sophomore Natalie Lanza, president of the Rotary Club, said.</p>

<p>If you would like to donate, you must be at least 16 years of age, weigh a minimum of 110 pounds, and be free of serious medical conditions. If you’re interested in donating, you can make an appointment to give blood or platelets by contacting the Red Cross at 1 800 RED CROSS (1-800-733-2767) or City of Hope at <a href="https://www.idonateblood4hope.org">idonateblood4hope.org</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Karina Yue</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is a major shortage of blood in the U.S. according to The American Red Cross, and CSArts students and faculty rolled up their sleeves to give the gift of life to two different blood drives.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/youre-just-our-type.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/youre-just-our-type.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Winter Formal: Mermaid Tails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/winter-formal-mermaid-tails/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winter Formal: Mermaid Tails" /><published>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/winter-formal-mermaid-tails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/winter-formal-mermaid-tails/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="dive-into-the-magic-unleash-your-inner-mermaid">Dive Into the Magic: Unleash Your Inner Mermaid</h4>

<p>The grand room of the Centre in Lakewood greeted students for Winter Formal with sparkling decorations, music pumping, the soft glow of lights as students grew their sea legs for the “Meet Me at the Mermaid Lagoon” party! No one wore fins to the dance on February 3rd; however, the room was a sea of elegant gowns and dapper suits, and there even was a group of Pirates!</p>

<p>Students danced, stood in long lines to get pictures in the photo booth. The silliest pictures and cutest moments have been captured. Not just in their hearts, but with photos documenting their formal for the Winter “Sea-son.”</p>

<p>The students of CSArts nominated their peers that they thought should be crowned for the Winter Formal Court. Congratulations to Sofia Thompson and Kiana Alverez! And thank you to CSArts Leadership for an amazing night!</p>]]></content><author><name>Pippin Langdon</name></author><category term="events" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dive Into the Magic: Unleash Your Inner Mermaid]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/none/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Wildlife at CSArts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wildlife-at-csarts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Wildlife at CSArts" /><published>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wildlife-at-csarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wildlife-at-csarts/"><![CDATA[<p>The many insects and animals on our campus can help us to be mindful during the long school day, yet we often undervalue (and step on) them. While it’s true that countless things are more entertaining than watching, for example, several earthworms fleeing the rain, these animals have actually helped me to relax, and have become an anxiety coping method.</p>

<p>The activity of observing insects or small creatures is calming because it is repetitive and slow, similarly to yoga. Over time, it can become a trance where nothing exists except for the animal. Naturally, if the mind is engrossed in watching the animal, it cannot worry, and will be at rest. When the trance ends, and if the mind is given time to rejuvenate with sleep, food, and water, it will be able to function well.</p>

<p>Even if you live in the city and aren’t familiar with the outdoors, it’s fairly easy to find creatures on campus. Mr. Crumley, who teaches Biology and Honors Biology says our campus’ location brings a diversity of wildlife.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Since it is closer to the foothills, there’s definitely a lot more biodiversity.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Crumley says that several species live nearby include: cougars, bobcats, finches, bears, and coyotes. And you can’t leave out the insect population.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You can pretty much find anything in the San Gabriel Valley area, your typical insects like praying mantises. The monarch butterflies come here during the season, so you might see some monarchs flying by here and there.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He adds,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you go out to the field, actually, during the springtime, you’ll see a bunch of dragonflies out there.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Large animals, as well as small ones, visit CSArts occasionally.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve heard we’ve had possums,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mr. Crumley says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A skunk or two found their home in the dance studios in the past.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Next time you start to walk by a small animal, whether it’s a butterfly or a frog, stay a minute. There are lessons in how each animal lives–in the loyalty of the ants to their queen, in the way squirrels steal bird seed, and in the way worms cross sidewalks, unable to realize they’re almost getting stepped on. They’re just waiting to be found.</p>]]></content><author><name>Noelle Lee</name></author><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The many insects and animals on our campus can help us to be mindful during the long school day, yet we often undervalue (and step on) them. While it’s true that countless things are more entertaining than watching, for example, several earthworms fleeing the rain, these animals have actually helped me to relax, and have become an anxiety coping method.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/wildlife-at-csarts.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/wildlife-at-csarts.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of the 400’s</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/future-of-the-400s/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of the 400’s" /><published>2023-12-15T04:00:20-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T04:00:20-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/future-of-the-400s</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/future-of-the-400s/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re a student at CSArts, chances are you’ve had a class in Diagon Alley, better known as the 400’s. Rumors of termites, deterioration, and admin losing the 400’s have spread around the school. But what’s true and what’s false?</p>

<p>Dr. Endelman, Principal at CSArts, says he had no knowledge of termites or deterioration in the 400’s when asked about the problems.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>There’s certain things that get sent to me, and then there’s a lot that just never get sent to me,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>he said. He said teachers’ complaints sometimes bypass him and are sent to a team responsible for repairs, so not all information goes straight to him.</p>

<p>Regarding the future of the 400s and whether or not we would be losing them to Duarte, Dr. Endelman says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s partially true,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>referring to Duarte wanting the 400s back.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>They [the portables] have served as a temporary hub, and that was organized by Duarte. We entered a lease agreement with Duarte but we pay the leasing company, not Duarte.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He was able to give the cost to lease the portables which was over $1 million annually.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That lease is getting ready to expire,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman says.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So the big question for all of us is what are we going to do about it?”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After the completion of Duarte’s new sports complex, they are interested in getting the space back for a parking lot. But admin also has big plans for the land that the 400s sit on.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The long term solution is to get rid of the 400s and close off that backside of the school, letting the school end at the studio portables/PAC and let Duarte High have their parking lot back,”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Endelman explained.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My dream is to have permanent buildings.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman says the most probable location would be Northview park or replacing some of the portable dance studios with permanent buildings.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>We’re already having high-level conversations with the school district and the city about what those plans could look like… It’ll take time and money to get these things accomplished, but I am very excited for the future growth of the school.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dr. Endelman said there currently is no definitive timeline for the plans.</p>]]></content><author><name>Quinn Mc-Nary &amp; Karina Hil</name></author><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re a student at CSArts, chances are you’ve had a class in Diagon Alley, better known as the 400’s. Rumors of termites, deterioration, and admin losing the 400’s have spread around the school. But what’s true and what’s false?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/future-of-the-400s.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/future-of-the-400s.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>